<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scott Tactical </title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/national-park/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Scott Tactical</author>
    <rights>(C) 2015</rights>
    <updated>2015-10-17 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>Yosemite National Park, CA - October 9, 2015</title>
          <link>http://localhost:1313/yosemite-national-park-panorama-trail-glacier-point-vernal-nevada-fall/</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://localhost:1313/yosemite-national-park-panorama-trail-glacier-point-vernal-nevada-fall/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;hiking-yosemite-ca:1217abd15b682e31e138a95d5c798515&#34;&gt;Hiking Yosemite, CA&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;rimrise-and-shine:1217abd15b682e31e138a95d5c798515&#34;&gt;Rimrise and Shine&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mornings in Yosemite Valley are breathtaking. The weather was perfect IMO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had some unfortunate luck with the camping and as you can see we could not get duplicate nights on our spot. See our note on getting your site well in advance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our wonderful neighbors were kind enough to help us out. They got us from the upper pines campsites out around the valley and back to the trailhead of the 4 mile trail. It is a pleasure to meet with good folks. Living in the San Fernando Valley, Los Angeles causes one to disparage the lack of humanity in the throngs of the masses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-mile-trail:1217abd15b682e31e138a95d5c798515&#34;&gt;4 mile trail&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a whole day hike that took metered out around 17 miles. Give or take a little. Starting around 9am and coming in around 5pm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;glacier-point:1217abd15b682e31e138a95d5c798515&#34;&gt;Glacier Point&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Felt sooo good to summit the Glacier Point. It is up hill non-stop the whole way there for those 4 miles. What was odd was all the people with makeup and fancy shoes. I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize you could DRIVE THERE! Freakin A. As long as there is no ski lift to the top of half dome. Please no.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the top there was a wedding going on. It was a beautiful place. I am hoping they charged for that. I am going to find the people up there. I didn&amp;rsquo;t take too many pictures so if anyone knows who they are please email me and I&amp;rsquo;ll send what I have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;half-dome:1217abd15b682e31e138a95d5c798515&#34;&gt;Half Dome&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though we didn&amp;rsquo;t get to summit Half Dome, there was a lot to see of it. Another Day I suppose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;panorama-trail:1217abd15b682e31e138a95d5c798515&#34;&gt;Panorama Trail&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This wound around, then wound back, then unwound, then zigged, and zagged, and my feet cracked, and my water leaked, and then a waterfall. It was a lot of sun getting here. Kinda hot. Even for Yosemite and California park weather. It was the direct sun and lack of wind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;illilouette-falls:1217abd15b682e31e138a95d5c798515&#34;&gt;Illilouette Falls&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The falls were kinda shallow. Not much going on there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;nevada-falls:1217abd15b682e31e138a95d5c798515&#34;&gt;Nevada Falls&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally. This was the top. Nothing but rugged rocky down hill. I stopped taking pictures. I was over it at this point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;vernal-fall-mist-trail:1217abd15b682e31e138a95d5c798515&#34;&gt;Vernal Fall, Mist Trail&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Water was light. There was a light fall, but no mist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was an epic hike for me. Yosemite lays it out like a buffet of beauty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.everytrail.com/guide/the-mist-trail-vernal-and-nevada-falls/map&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mist Trail, Vernal Vall, Nevada Falls, MAP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.everytrail.com/guide/glacier-point&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Glacier Point - MAP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.everytrail.com/guide/the-panorama-trail/map&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Panorama Trail - MAP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.yosemitehikes.com/glacier-point-road/panorama-trail/panorama-trail.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Panorama Trail Information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
