<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scott Tactical </title>
    <link>http://scotttactical.com/tags/design/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Scott Tactical</author>
    <rights>(C) 2016</rights>
    <updated>2016-12-09 08:52:58 -0800 PST</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>Why The Covered California Website Sucks</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/post/why-the-covered-california-website-sucks/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 08:52:58 PST</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/post/why-the-covered-california-website-sucks/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-it-needs-help-my-letter:6fc9dbe0e4c93911a33da0d91571ac2c&#34;&gt;Why It Needs Help - My Letter&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an open letter to the Covered California website designer, administrators, bureaucrats and contractors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;website-design-and-usability:6fc9dbe0e4c93911a33da0d91571ac2c&#34;&gt;Website Design and Usability&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have several things listed below. Things I find to be of poor design or just plain broken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-don-t-got-mail:6fc9dbe0e4c93911a33da0d91571ac2c&#34;&gt;You Don&amp;rsquo;t Got Mail!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Secure Mailbox (2)&amp;rdquo; even though nothing was in my mail box.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It randomly logged me out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;go-on-click-me-if-ya-can:6fc9dbe0e4c93911a33da0d91571ac2c&#34;&gt;GO&amp;rsquo;ON CLICK ME IF YA CAN&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am low on time for open enrollment and it gave me a &amp;ldquo;Pay Now&amp;rdquo; button in order to do it faster, but the button was broken. It would pop up and then if I tried to pay it would throw a JavaScript error in my console and close out. Now I can&amp;rsquo;t pay. It&amp;rsquo;s weird when people don&amp;rsquo;t want my money.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The page refreshing on every submission of information is mind numbing. Just cache it. Or make the template more clean. Or make it more responsive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;all-your-accounts-all-belong-to-us:6fc9dbe0e4c93911a33da0d91571ac2c&#34;&gt;All your accounts all belong to us!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;My Account section has almost nothing about what plans I selected. I am glad I was taking screenshots along the way. How do you guys even know what I selected. Isn&amp;rsquo;t there a table with a key that can simply show what my plans look like? How do I get back to that information? It shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be this hard. Do you even care about me getting to my coverage?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You sent me zero email notifications based on what I was signing up for. And I specifically put that email was my preferred contact method. Instead you handed it off to someone else and washed your hands. They will be mailing me things. I don&amp;rsquo;t go to my mailbox every day. It&amp;rsquo;s a drive. I&amp;rsquo;m not some home loafer who waits by his mailbox.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;penrose-navigation:6fc9dbe0e4c93911a33da0d91571ac2c&#34;&gt;Penrose Navigation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The layout of the pages is all wrong. It&amp;rsquo;s got too much nonsense on it. Right hand home page &amp;ldquo;extra&amp;rdquo; navigation is hard to see and nonintuitive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You have an informational video on the bottom left barely under the fold. Why? Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t there be an info section or a knowledge base. Just use another website for an example.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-are-up-100-of-the-time-50-of-the-day:6fc9dbe0e4c93911a33da0d91571ac2c&#34;&gt;We are up 100% of the time 50% of the day!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Work on reliability. The site will be down or throwing errors half the time I got through.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It took me 5 tries to actually get through this whole process.  It was painful. No commercial company would survive this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-not-home:6fc9dbe0e4c93911a33da0d91571ac2c&#34;&gt;We Not Home&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why do you make me fill in 8!!! lines of information to start a live chat. Seriously. If I am logged in just open the chat window and start talking. Is this a game? Don&amp;rsquo;t make me mask my phone number with special characters&amp;hellip; Especially if you know it&amp;rsquo;s going to just be integers.  (###) ###-####  no! I don&amp;rsquo;t like that format. I use dots because i&amp;rsquo;m not older than 50 and know how to use a 10key. What if I was doing this on a mobile device. Have you even watched Office Space? Do you want someone to red stapler your website?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why is &amp;ldquo;report a change&amp;rdquo; hovering in some dead zone where a lady and a baby are. Is that lady and baby supposed to make me think men don&amp;rsquo;t apply or that I should be taking out more coverage because there are family health issues at stake here. Report a change should show up when you log in. Just get people to log in and then present the info in order.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ordering of your navigation is not industry best practices.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;loco-help:6fc9dbe0e4c93911a33da0d91571ac2c&#34;&gt;Loco Help&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;BTW I tried the &amp;ldquo;Find Local Help&amp;rdquo; button and all the people I called on that suggested list said they don&amp;rsquo;t help with Medical or Covered CA. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what your intention is there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Español ▼&amp;rdquo; dropdown should actually be a drop down. I went to click on espanol and it just changed the language instead of actually giving me the drop down. You are doing double duty on that field and it&amp;rsquo;s misleading.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;mobiles-need-not-apply:6fc9dbe0e4c93911a33da0d91571ac2c&#34;&gt;Mobiles Need Not Apply&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This website is NOT mobile friendly.  Big sin buddies. Are none of your constituents under 30?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is pretty much all I picked up today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion:6fc9dbe0e4c93911a33da0d91571ac2c&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stop hiring crony consultants and design firms. Give respectable shops a chance to do it right. You might actually save some money and have some customer satisfaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just my .02&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;=st=&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
