<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Car Computer on Scott Tactical</title>
    <link>https://scotttactical.com/tags/car-computer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Car Computer on Scott Tactical</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2014–2019, Scott Tactical; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 18:16:54 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://scotttactical.com/tags/car-computer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing a USB Relay</title>
      <link>https://scotttactical.com/installing-usb-relay/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 18:16:54 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scotttactical.com/installing-usb-relay/</guid>
      <description>USB HID Relay   USB Relay on Ubuntu Linux This was fairly easy but not where I wanted to be. I found a library that did a ton of things for me.
Thank you to @darrylb123 for https://github.com/darrylb123/usbrelay
There was a python contribution but it broke the build. I spent a few hours trying to get it to build and gave up and just smashed the ugly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Car Computer Touchscreen Monitor</title>
      <link>https://scotttactical.com/car-computer-touchscreen-monitor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 21:15:12 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scotttactical.com/car-computer-touchscreen-monitor/</guid>
      <description>How do you control your new custom Linux powered car computer? With a touch screen monitor obviously. And maybe a bluetooth keyboard and mouse.
I would like this to feel like I am using a Steampunk hacker version of a Tesla.
  Tesla Streamliner Concept   Well maybe not all that.
Maybe more like this:
  Race Truck Dash   Touch Screens I started a similar project about 6 years ago on another vehicle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux USB Relay Controller</title>
      <link>https://scotttactical.com/linux-usb-relay-controller/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 01:10:53 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scotttactical.com/linux-usb-relay-controller/</guid>
      <description>Finding A Relay Controller One of my bigger worries is working with peripherals. I needed to find a camera and I felt like that was going to be easy enough. The relay controller will hit the actuators running the door locks.
What Is A Relay Switch Most things inside a car take a decent amount of power to actuate or power them. The car is limited to 12V DC and your other measurements are amps and watts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Car Computer Camera</title>
      <link>https://scotttactical.com/car-computer-camera/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 14:33:06 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scotttactical.com/car-computer-camera/</guid>
      <description>Camera Overview Finding a good camera shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be too difficult given how many cameras exist now. They are literally everywhere.
Camera Criteria I learned right away that the cameras were pretty much all standardized. They came in a few flavors but overall they were either too small, too wide, or too expensive. That helped me limit stuff down a lot.
 small not much distortion (fish eye is bad) resolution &amp;gt; 720p color USB preferable  Preferences  Embeddable Flush mounted White 1080p hardened housing  Hardware Choices First Find I found this one right off by searching for &amp;ldquo;USB Camera&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Car Computer Hardware</title>
      <link>https://scotttactical.com/car-computer-hardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 21:32:16 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scotttactical.com/car-computer-hardware/</guid>
      <description>Searching For The Right Car Computer Hardware My trip to Fry&amp;rsquo;s in LA this morning wasn&amp;rsquo;t as great as I hoped. But I did get some great ideas on how to accomplish things.
There were two major themes in the hardware that I looked at.
 Small isolated modular things Apple stuff  There wasn&amp;rsquo;t much for integration or components that were universal. Either they were for their own little world or they were for some subset of the Apple ecosystem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Car Computer Intro</title>
      <link>https://scotttactical.com/car-computer-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 21:32:16 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scotttactical.com/car-computer-intro/</guid>
      <description>Introduction To STAC Car Computer The purpose of the build out is to take a 100% analog vehicle and bring in modern creature comforts and a modern driveline. In addition to this I will be integrating a few technology tools that are developed at my current work.
Scenario In the morning I would like to walk out to my car, walk up to the door and have it unlock for me.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>