<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scott Tactical </title>
    <link>http://scotttactical.com/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Scott Tactical</author>
    <rights>(C) 2015</rights>
    <updated>2015-11-06 01:23:11 -0800 PST</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>Eat For War</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/post/eat-for-war/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2015 01:23:11 PST</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/post/eat-for-war/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bad men live that they may eat and drink, whereas good men eat and drink that they may live. Socrates - Plutarch, &lt;em&gt;How a Young Man Ought to Hear Poems&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-warrior-s-diet:62a5d67ac0510a562f183297b71bac75&#34;&gt;A Warrior&amp;rsquo;s Diet&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://scotttactical.com/images/gladiator-eating.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Gladiators Love Vegetables&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What physically intimate activity do we participate in more than any other?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eating&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the more important factors in becoming awake is in the control of one&amp;rsquo;s dietary intake. The &lt;em&gt;passion of hunger&lt;/em&gt;. We take other living things into our bodies and literally become one with them. No strange occurrence happened that caused most religions incorporate some form of consumption into their ritual. It is part of every culture and one of those most important glues in uniting various traditions. Food is religion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;tl-dr:62a5d67ac0510a562f183297b71bac75&#34;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your diet is a long term wager that should reflect your ultimate goals and ethos. The outcome is measured over years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-are-what-we-eat:62a5d67ac0510a562f183297b71bac75&#34;&gt;We Are What We Eat&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every part of your body including your mind is effected by what you do and do not consume. Eating an unhealthy diet will slow the cognitive abilities of the warrior and leave him sluggish to think. Consuming large amounts of meat will draw the blood away from the brain and cause it to be used to processes a higher than necessary amount of flesh. Processed sugars will spike glucose and cause the mind to race and then crash leaving a less than desirable concentration peak. Too few vegetables causes the body to crave more of various foods that if not satisfied and in turn substituted with inadequate foods will leave the body overweight and diseased. Buying food of lower quality that is laden with petrochemicals and heavy metals will cause the immune system to weaken and make the body vulnerable to any number of diseases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again it is advantageous to think in the mind of our enemy. He is able to gain an upper hand by strategically supplying his enemy with high calorie low value and nutritionally wasted food. Even better he can cause the immune system of his enemy to be weakened so that a biological attack is possible. If the mind of the opponent can be made saturated with metals there opens a whole range of psychological attacks aimed at unbalancing the hormones of the body. Once our enemy can control just one of the emotions he can alter just about every other action and you are no longer valuable as a soldier except as fodder. It is simple in this age and not at all fantastic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://scotttactical.com/images/lion-buffalo.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Buffalo Bests Lion&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NOTE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you wish to attack these assertions do so knowing you are wagering your own body, and it is likely that I am physically above you in the food chain already. Be grateful for the constructs of society. This is philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;agriculture:62a5d67ac0510a562f183297b71bac75&#34;&gt;Agriculture&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The closer to the earth you go the closer to life you will be. Generally the more times something is processed the less densely nutritional it will be for you and at some level may be harmful. Taking milk directly from the cow will inherit all those beneficial enzymes that we have accustomed our bodies to over the last few millennium. Pasteurized and ultra-pasteurized milk has been killed essentially. Also add the fact that highly processed diary has biological system altering antibiotic and hormonal additive levels in it. Foods that are highly processed corn byproducts are terrible for the mind and the body as well as damaging to the economy and feed the industrial war machine. High fructose corn syrup HFCS is the diseased blood of our flat lands. It should be boxed up and shipped to the front doors of our enemy in the sweetest form it can take.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strategy against terror states: Americanize their foodchain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The older in the anthropological food chain you go the easier it is for you body to digest. It is unrealistic that humans were carnivores. We are omnivores and a special kind: one that does not inherit instincts as the animals do. We are dissimilar to every animal in nearly every decision we make and food is no difference. It took the institution of tradition to pass along the various things we learned about: what to eat and what not to. Culture defined the combinations and quantities of those things. The post pseudo-cosmopolitanism of the United States set the table for a feast to forsake Epicurus. We were determined to eat in our cars while driving. And now we are the wasteline [sic] of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;invest-in-food-nutrition:62a5d67ac0510a562f183297b71bac75&#34;&gt;Invest In Food (Nutrition)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contributing to the agricultural infrastructure is the one tactic a society can have that will always have positive effects and those which are greater than any other civil infrastructure including education and medicine. &amp;ldquo;Smart&amp;rdquo; folks think that their potential is limitless and are the pinnacle of human development, but without healthy hardened people to support their ideas they are slightly above fodder for the incoming armies. Without the productive classes they would starve out with haste and lose all their wives and children to those who can produce food. It is only in these highly critical states of systems that people who are weaker are able to float the top. The greatest part of history is supported by those who are of hearty healthy stock. Farming is not dumb work and it takes a lifetime to simply keep up with the land.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Environmentalists will agree with these topics on some level. Or should. Simply changing our agricultural strategies would do more for the environment than taking all the cars off the road. It is the right solution to many of our problems. When someone asks &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;but what can I do&amp;rdquo; there is a very simple solution. Give something back to the earth. It raised us and nursed us and all we do is act like spoiled children and take take take.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earth is our first Mother.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Man&amp;rsquo;s first job was farming. It should be each man&amp;rsquo;s responsibility to understand how to manage and grow his own food and what it takes to produce food. Our task is to toil. The goal of progress should not be to remove work. It should be to make our lives better and if we sit around like fat slobs our life is in no way better. That will only emphasize the trivial problems in our lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;masculine-hunger:62a5d67ac0510a562f183297b71bac75&#34;&gt;Masculine Hunger&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t have bigger balls or thicker chest hairs if you consume a ton of read meat each day. That is not biologically sound and is likely fear-based peer pressure feeding on an underdeveloped level of sexual maturity. In fact you might have to get your colon scraped out because you caused internal problems by forcing too much of the wrong substance into it. Putting your body&amp;rsquo;s Ph level off into the acidic side will increase your chances of cancer and that might just claim one of those huge nuts you are growing. Moderation is key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Listening to your body and maintaining a proper diet that is balanced by nature will increase those things which men need to thrive. Alkaline foods are going to put your body into a state that promotes optimal performance and will in turn stimulate everything to run in peak performance. There is very simple science to back up these decisions and it does not require validation of a fad diet. Sure you can do things that throw your body into a state of ketosis and cause the fat to come off fast but you are increasing your acid levels and causing your metabolism to ramp up. Learn biology and think for yourself. The last part is discipline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;aesthetics-health-vanity:62a5d67ac0510a562f183297b71bac75&#34;&gt;Aesthetics, Health, Vanity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is some validity in the idea that big muscular dudes get the girls. It&amp;rsquo;s nature. A woman wants a man that is going to be capable of giving her a child with the best chances of survival. A fat or broken man is going to have far fewer options when being selected. Within a few seconds of viewing a man it is possible for her to tell whether this person is above or below average in health, strength, social value, and whether he is dominant or passive. These are primal characteristics, but how do they relate to this? They weren&amp;rsquo;t designed simply for the attraction of the other mate, but to bring glory back to God. The ultimate designer. Does someone who cannot tend their own body bring pride to anyone?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do not want people around us who cannot control their lives. Their diet is important to control and where vanity might be a good motivator it is easy to make this vice into a virtue. Eating well will grow our bodies into structures that are desirable to women, ourselves. At the end of our lives we should not necessarily turn in a pretty corpse but one that was driven so hard that the wheels fell off of it as it was being pulled into the garage. What keeps this from being vanity is &lt;em&gt;purpose&lt;/em&gt;. It is because we get more miles on a fit healthy body that we find joy in what we have sculpted. True joy. Not transient chemical happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember, bodies are made in the kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;prayer-fasting-charity:62a5d67ac0510a562f183297b71bac75&#34;&gt;Prayer, Fasting, Charity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://scotttactical.com/images/warrior-meditation.png&#34; alt=&#34;Warrior Meditation and the Path to Enlightenment&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three things, my brethren, by which faith stands firm, devotion remains constant, and virtue endures. They are prayer, fasting and mercy. Prayer knocks at the door, fasting obtains, mercy receives. Prayer, mercy and fasting: these three are one, and they give life to each other. Saint Peter Chrysologus&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is where we get down to the real &amp;ldquo;meat&amp;rdquo; of the topic and with real scientific evidence to back this up. Your primal urges must be subdued regularly if you wish to elevate yourself. No, it will not hurt you. If it does you might be mentally or physically too weak to handle this program. What it will do is open your mind. Gandhi did it. Christ did it. Muhammad did it. The prophets did it. This is a must and should be incorporated into any leadership system. There are very few ways that we can unlock this deep primal part of our brains. If you have not been truly starving then you have not made yourself available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cattle-and-sheeple:62a5d67ac0510a562f183297b71bac75&#34;&gt;Cattle and Sheeple&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anthropologically we are not grazing animals. We are more appropriately scavengers and in some situations hunters. We are opportunists by nature. Humans were not found grazing on the range all day. These diets of eating many times in a day are just setting people up to be slaughter animals. Severely restricting the body will put us into a state of survival which releases all sorts of amazing hormones into the body. Our minds and bodies work at a higher operational level when in this state. It is exactly opposite of what most would think. In this hedonistic social paradigm we live in this is yet another anti-truism of common intuition. The only scientifically proven method of prolonging life is caloric restriction. If a longer life is a measure of health then there is no better credibility in this system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;myth-butters:62a5d67ac0510a562f183297b71bac75&#34;&gt;Myth-Butters&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glutin.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Apparently France didn&amp;rsquo;t get the memo that they should be dying or morbidly obese. Research &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coeliac_disease&#34; title=&#34;Celiac Disease&#34;&gt;Celiac Disease&lt;/a&gt; please. Odds are you don&amp;rsquo;t have it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supplements are (bad|good)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Please, again do your own research and find out what you need to actually supplement. Our agricultural system is in a bad way so there are probably things you need to get more of that you may supplement to get you where you need to be, but it wont make up for being lazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fat is Bad&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Being fat is bad. Eating it isn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily bad. Listen to your body and make wise decisions. Another fad pushed by the US health industry that threw our whole dietary development into the fan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;cornclusion:62a5d67ac0510a562f183297b71bac75&#34;&gt;Cornclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, it is up to you to determine what to eat and your decisions must be well researched and implemented. Once the best meals are put into place they need to be cast solid by repetition and then turned into a habit. Eventually they may become tradition and if enough of us pass these good habits forward they may become a cultural improvement that we can be proud of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;=st=&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>PHPunit Slowness Performance Suggestions</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/performance-suggestions-phpunit-slowness</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2015 12:57:42 PST</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/performance-suggestions-phpunit-slowness</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;phpunit-is-slowness:d306273837598a7a2a686add086bab85&#34;&gt;PHPUnit Is Slowness&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love &lt;a href=&#34;https://phpunit.de/&#34;&gt;PHPUnit&lt;/a&gt; don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong. More than a testing library, I like testing, or having tests. It&amp;rsquo;s like the code got yo back bro! Build code that lasts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;EDIT&lt;/em&gt;: I know most of the problems are inherent with tests not the testing framework.  However, my requirements dictate how I use it to a certain extent.  Peace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;phpunit-is-painfully-slow:d306273837598a7a2a686add086bab85&#34;&gt;PHPUnit is painfully slow.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://scotttactical.com/images/turtle-speed.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;PHPUnit Is Slow&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seriously. Though. Maybe having a concurrent environment it can run it would help. I worked at a place with 65,000 unit tests and if they ran as slow as our unit tests here it would never finish. It was literally taking 30-60 seconds per test. That is 65000 x 60 = 1083 hours or 45 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For reference the 41 year old &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2015/07/13/422610986/ultramarathoner-finishes-the-appalachian-trail-in-record-time&#34;&gt;Scott Jurek&lt;/a&gt; can walk the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nps.gov/appa/index.htm&#34;&gt;2000+ mile Appalachian Trail&lt;/a&gt; in 45 days. Single threaded of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-is-phpunit-anti-performant:d306273837598a7a2a686add086bab85&#34;&gt;Why is PHPUnit Anti-Performant&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some thing that are inherent to unit tests that make them slow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tests are usually not well encapsulated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many tests aren&amp;rsquo;t true unit tests - @see integration tests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Databases must be built and destroyed for every test&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Connections from local systems are slow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Writing to file on a local system is slow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generating reports is intensive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;strategies:d306273837598a7a2a686add086bab85&#34;&gt;Strategies&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sqlite-in-memory:d306273837598a7a2a686add086bab85&#34;&gt;SQLite - In Memory&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://scotttactical.com/images/sqlite.gif&#34; alt=&#34;SQLite&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Switch to an in-memory database. Even if you have SSD drives its going to be slow. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlite.org/&#34;&gt;SQLite&lt;/a&gt; is on OS X out of the box I am fairly sure and comes with most &amp;lsquo;nix flavors. Considering they embed it all over the place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting up Laravel it would be something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-php&#34;&gt;
&#39;sqlite&#39; =&amp;gt; [
    &#39;driver&#39;   =&amp;gt; &#39;sqlite&#39;,
//  &#39;database&#39; =&amp;gt; storage_path().&#39;/database.sqlite&#39;,
    &#39;database&#39; =&amp;gt; &#39;:memory:&#39;,
    &#39;prefix&#39;   =&amp;gt; &#39;&#39;,
],
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just comment out the hard path.
Then add a record for the drive in your phpunit.xml
I also like to make sure my host is set to not kill anything. I have wiped out a dev database or two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-xml&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;env name=&amp;quot;DATABASE_DRIVER&amp;quot; value=&amp;quot;sqlite&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;env name=&amp;quot;DB_HOST&amp;quot; value=&amp;quot;NO&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;database-sometimes:d306273837598a7a2a686add086bab85&#34;&gt;Database - Sometimes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have two base test cases that I use for almost everything. One that wraps up Laravel or the big framework I&amp;rsquo;m messing with or one that will just extend phpunit by itself.  It might even be better to have data groups into domains so that when you are running a group of tests that it only loads up those tables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have a couple hundred tests. Not much.  But it takes 2-5 seconds to load up all the data. That adds up to minutes.  Can&amp;rsquo;t handle that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;grouping-test-suites:d306273837598a7a2a686add086bab85&#34;&gt;Grouping Test Suites&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have the ability to group your tests. I always have my developers add docblocks such as below so that PHPUnit will know how to group thing. The fields that I want them to use are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@author - for running all mine or someone&amp;rsquo;s tests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@group - I have them just put the package in this place&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@namespace - I think this works&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-php&#34;&gt;
/**
 * 
 * @author solvire &amp;lt;stevenjscott@gmail.com&amp;gt;
 * @package Rules
 * @group Rules
 * @namespace LeadFerret\Lib\Rules
 */
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Running &lt;code&gt;./vendor/bin/phpunit --list-groups&lt;/code&gt; will give you an idea of what groups you can run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;./vendor/bin/phpunit --list-groups
PHPUnit 4.8.16 by Sebastian Bergmann and contributors.

Available test group(s):
 - API
 - Models
 - Rules
 - Transformers
 - default
 - solvire &amp;lt;stevenjscott@gmail.com&amp;gt;
 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;filter-your-tests:d306273837598a7a2a686add086bab85&#34;&gt;Filter Your Tests&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Run only the tests you need. Sometimes I&amp;rsquo;m working with a class and I want to keep running that class.  Just filter by the test class name:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;./vendor/bin/phpunit --filter=&amp;quot;testValidateTrustedCanModifyCompany&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make your test names interesting camel cases. If you run testdox it comes out easier to read:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;./vendor/bin/phpunit --filter=&amp;quot;testValidateTrustedCanModifyCompany&amp;quot; --testdox
PHPUnit 4.8.16 by Sebastian Bergmann and contributors.

LeadFerret\Lib\Rules\CompanyModifyRuleProvider
 [x] Validate trusted can modify company

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;turn-off-code-coverage:d306273837598a7a2a686add086bab85&#34;&gt;Turn Off Code Coverage&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t always have to run code coverage reports. In fact probably only before a deployment. Either you really love to see code coverage or you hate dealing with unit tests.  Doesn&amp;rsquo;t really seem to be much between.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;performance-tests:d306273837598a7a2a686add086bab85&#34;&gt;Performance Tests&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difference was so staggering I that I was totally irritated I didn&amp;rsquo;t find this sooner. I was even getting in trying to debug at the lower code level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;./vendor/bin/phpunit --filter=&amp;quot;testValidateTrustedCanModifyCompany&amp;quot; --no-coverage
PHPUnit 4.8.16 by Sebastian Bergmann and contributors.
.
Time: 3.98 seconds, Memory: 35.25Mb
OK (1 test, 2 assertions)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And with coverage:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;./vendor/bin/phpunit --filter=&amp;quot;testValidateTrustedCanModifyCompany&amp;quot;
PHPUnit 4.8.16 by Sebastian Bergmann and contributors.
.
Time: 48.54 seconds, Memory: 46.75Mb
OK (1 test, 2 assertions)
Generating code coverage report in HTML format ... done
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FASTER!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;javascript-for-the-assist:d306273837598a7a2a686add086bab85&#34;&gt;JavaScript For The Assist&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://scotttactical.com/images/gulp.png&#34; alt=&#34;GulpJS&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have been toying with using &lt;a href=&#34;http://gulpjs.com/&#34;&gt;Gulp&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.npmjs.com/&#34;&gt;NPM&lt;/a&gt; for setting up a better workflow.  It is simple enough that once a file is saved that scripts can kick off the appropriate unit tests. If your tests are completing in less than a couple seconds then it doesn&amp;rsquo;t hurt to keep running them. If they break you may know it sooner.  This is also helpful for those people who refuse to use a full-featured IDE.  Probably also the same people that enjoy working on javascript in the dark.  I know who you are. O.o&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion:d306273837598a7a2a686add086bab85&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life is much better now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Test-driven development is a great way to go about things.  I highly suggest it. It makes your life easier in the long run and your credibility as an engineer is safer when you aren&amp;rsquo;t worried about whether you are going to break things. If you automate the process and provide cool reports with graphs then you can build a friendly rivalry based on coverage rights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Build Quality Software&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Engineer; Don&amp;rsquo;t Hack&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;=st=&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Deploying Hugo the Golang CMS on DigitalOcean - Nginx</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/deploying-hugo-golang-digitalocean-nginx</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2015 06:29:31 PDT</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/deploying-hugo-golang-digitalocean-nginx</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;deploying-hugo-the-golang-cms-on-digitalocean:05ba16f4d070e50db8ed0ad9d587f7eb&#34;&gt;Deploying Hugo the Golang CMS on DigitalOcean&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;creating-a-droplet:05ba16f4d070e50db8ed0ad9d587f7eb&#34;&gt;Creating a Droplet&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a bit partial to CentOS. The lastest version as of this writing is &lt;em&gt;CentOS Linux release 7.1.1503 (Core)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting up a droplet is always very simple. Just turn it on basically. Upload your ssh keys. Done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;install-nginx:05ba16f4d070e50db8ed0ad9d587f7eb&#34;&gt;Install Nginx&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;add-the-epel-repo:05ba16f4d070e50db8ed0ad9d587f7eb&#34;&gt;Add the epel repo:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;yum install epel-release
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;install:05ba16f4d070e50db8ed0ad9d587f7eb&#34;&gt;Install&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;yum install nginx
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;start-it:05ba16f4d070e50db8ed0ad9d587f7eb&#34;&gt;Start it&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;service nginx start 
systemctl enable nginx
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;create-the-folders:05ba16f4d070e50db8ed0ad9d587f7eb&#34;&gt;Create the Folders&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;mkdir -p /var/www/ursite/
chown -R nginx:nginx /var/www
touch /var/www/ursite/index.html - or clone your site 
cp /etc/nginx/sites-available/default /etc/nginx/sites-available/ursite
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;configure-nginx:05ba16f4d070e50db8ed0ad9d587f7eb&#34;&gt;Configure nginx&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;open the config file: &lt;code&gt;vim /etc/nginx/conf.d/virtual.conf&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-conf&#34;&gt;#
# A virtual host using mix of IP-, name-, and port-based configuration
#

server {
    listen       80;
    server_name  scotttactical.com;
    server_alias go.scotttactical.com;

    location / {
        root   /var/www/stac/public/;
        index  index.html;
    }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;install-go-hugo:05ba16f4d070e50db8ed0ad9d587f7eb&#34;&gt;Install  Go + Hugo&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;yum install go 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to install from source
Edit your bash script to have the proper variables in place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;yum install git hg 
export GOPATH=$HOME/go
go get -v github.com/spf13/hugo
cp $GOPATH/bin/hugo /usr/local/bin/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NOTE: THis actually isn&amp;rsquo;t necessary.  Just check it out and go with it. Afer screwing with it a few minutes I facepalmed&amp;hellip; they are static files. Doh!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Hugo: A replacement for Wordpress</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/hugo-a-replacement-for-wordpress/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2015 15:39:13 PDT</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/hugo-a-replacement-for-wordpress/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;hugo-a-replacement-for-wordpress:af5d620423bd53c36ac9d8e74d1bb8f8&#34;&gt;Hugo: A Replacement for Wordpress&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tl-dr:af5d620423bd53c36ac9d8e74d1bb8f8&#34;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I researched go&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Found Hugo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setup a test&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Migrated my Wordpress instance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Launched DigitalOcean Droplet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deployed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Total time: &lt;em&gt;6 hours&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;continued:af5d620423bd53c36ac9d8e74d1bb8f8&#34;&gt;Continued:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My problems started almost a year before I took up this cause. At the time I only had 2 Wordpress sites. Very very low traffic.  Only a couple users a day.  They were mostly place holders for business sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;wordpress-is-hungry:af5d620423bd53c36ac9d8e74d1bb8f8&#34;&gt;Wordpress is hungry&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What was annoying about the case was that they would randomly &lt;em&gt;carsh&lt;/em&gt;! I realized they were running &lt;em&gt;out of memory&lt;/em&gt;. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t figure out why because I just wouldn&amp;rsquo;t let myself believe that a couple instances of Wordpress were enough to run out of memory. It was an AWS box running with .5GB of memory and some swap space. I can&amp;rsquo;t remember what. Maybe I was just too optimistic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I reimaged the server, installed several performance plugins, cached anything I could, but still it would eat memory like a lonely fat girl at a buffet. Every couple days my monitor would go off telling me the site was down. The monitor wasn&amp;rsquo;t in place immediately because I didn&amp;rsquo;t think I needed one. It was only after the site had been offline for a couple days before I realized that I had to get a monitor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well eventually I decided it just needed more hardware. I went to 1G of memory for the 2 instances. That carshed as well. It was like watching the movie Carsh in slow motion. I added a couple gigs of swap, but then aws started acting funny and it would fill up the memory immediately. I then went to 2G ram and 2G of swap. Still - Carshon Daily show!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;it-s-the-future-already:af5d620423bd53c36ac9d8e74d1bb8f8&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the Future Already&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s 2015. In honor of 2015 and #BackToTheFuture day I am getting over 2000&amp;rsquo;s technology and moving on to something new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Blogs should fast and light&lt;/em&gt; and should be able to run in the fog. Static, and with out short codes. Gawd! And hoverboards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;so-starts-my-late-journey:af5d620423bd53c36ac9d8e74d1bb8f8&#34;&gt;So Starts My (Late) Journey&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-requirements:af5d620423bd53c36ac9d8e74d1bb8f8&#34;&gt;My Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy markup (or markdown)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lite - less than 500M of memory required&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Static (optional but nice)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No DB or a lighter option&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Image manipulation or gallery ease&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple enough a business person can (ha this isn&amp;rsquo;t the future you are looking for)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authentication layers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SEO items

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sitemap&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Metatags&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiple environment friendly (dev/stage/prod)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PERFORMANT fast&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Templates (market)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multi-site management (please?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;languages-prepared-to-flamed:af5d620423bd53c36ac9d8e74d1bb8f8&#34;&gt;Languages - PREPARED TO FLAMED!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PHP - too slow - boring - part of my problem already&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python - Interesting but everyone wants to use django. Kinda heavy for this&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ruby - pretty good but still kinda foreign to me&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go - I wanna learn it but where are the projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Java - swatting at flies with a sledge hammer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scala - eh&amp;hellip; i liked this idea but still too big&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;C++ - Not a masochist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perl - Not unless you say perl in a French accent every time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Node.js - I will not allow JS on my backend, it&amp;rsquo;s unnatural&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given my above list of languages I kinda forced myself into a sector.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;languages-decisions:af5d620423bd53c36ac9d8e74d1bb8f8&#34;&gt;Languages - Decisions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;ruby:af5d620423bd53c36ac9d8e74d1bb8f8&#34;&gt;Ruby&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really liked &lt;a href=&#34;http://jekyllrb.com/docs/home/&#34;&gt;jekyll&lt;/a&gt; and might have gone with it if Ruby wasn&amp;rsquo;t such a foreign concept to me. And I haven&amp;rsquo;t decided if I want to jump in and learn it completely. So not this time gems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;a-shot-at-python:af5d620423bd53c36ac9d8e74d1bb8f8&#34;&gt;A Shot at Python&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a ton of experience with PHP. They are all about the same. They can get okay performance if you cache everything but they are just too heavy. And it&amp;rsquo;s PHP. I&amp;rsquo;m over it. Drupal. Seriously it&amp;rsquo;s 2015. That thing should have died 10 years ago.  Are you still driving your subaru brat?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve used python before and I did give it a good run, but &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.djangoproject.com/&#34;&gt;Django&lt;/a&gt; is just too big IMO. A blog is simple. It needs to stay simple. Plus they are trying to recreate Wordpress in all of its glory. No thanks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be fair to python, I spent a little time going through the implementation of &lt;a href=&#34;http://mezzanine.jupo.org/&#34;&gt;Mezzanine&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.django-cms.org/en/&#34;&gt;Django-CMS&lt;/a&gt;.  Still. Too grande.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;java-et-al:af5d620423bd53c36ac9d8e74d1bb8f8&#34;&gt;Java et al&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have spent time before researching Java and C++ CMS programs. They are probably okay for monolithic enterprises who need some sort of back stroking to know they used a dump truck with a Cadillac interior to go pick up the groceries.  When 500 people will be working on it and you need a 20 step approval process I guess. I digress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;starting-with-go:af5d620423bd53c36ac9d8e74d1bb8f8&#34;&gt;Starting with Go&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok fine. Maybe now&amp;rsquo;s my chance to play with &lt;a href=&#34;https://golang.org/&#34;&gt;Golang&lt;/a&gt;. I was looking for a project for it so let&amp;rsquo;s give this a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far my implementation ideas are:
- roll my own
- wrap up a framework
- use a designed blog framework&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;some-frameworks:af5d620423bd53c36ac9d8e74d1bb8f8&#34;&gt;Some Frameworks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really liked a few of the frameworks, but as time went on I decided to see if I could find something lighter. But for records sake here are the samples I looked at&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://revel.github.io/&#34;&gt;http://revel.github.io/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://beego.me/&#34;&gt;http://beego.me/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://martini.codegangsta.io/&#34;&gt;http://martini.codegangsta.io/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BTW: Martini looked really cool. Light learning curve. I almost went with that, but felt like I could find better features in a purpose built app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-blog-solution:af5d620423bd53c36ac9d8e74d1bb8f8&#34;&gt;A Blog Solution&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After meandering around with the frameworks I felt like I wanted to try something more stripped down. So I looked at micro sites and Hugo &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;https://gohugo.io/&lt;/a&gt; stood out.  I figured I would know in a couple hours if it work work or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;hugo-quick-start:af5d620423bd53c36ac9d8e74d1bb8f8&#34;&gt;Hugo: Quick Start&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installing go is awesome on mac. If you have a mac and do not have &lt;a href=&#34;http://brew.sh/&#34;&gt;homebrew&lt;/a&gt; - shame on you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;brew install go 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installing hugo as awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;brew install hugo 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creating a new site was extremely simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;mkdir newsite
cd newsite
hugo new site . 
hugo new about.md
hugo new post/first.md
git clone https://github.com/dim0627/hugo_theme_beg themes/beg
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edit &lt;code&gt;config.yaml&lt;/code&gt; &amp;ndash; see my example
Add &lt;code&gt;theme = &amp;quot;beg&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start the serve:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo server --buildDrafts --watch
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion:af5d620423bd53c36ac9d8e74d1bb8f8&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was very painless. I am kinda surprised. I was a little hesitant to get in here. Setting up virtual hosts and getting the code out there wasn&amp;rsquo;t elegant but wasn&amp;rsquo;t hard either. I just checked out my repo on the server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am going to start transfering some of my other blogs to this when I have the chance. I might even do something sophisticated to the sites that are more or dynamic or colorful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go Golang!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Yosemite Valley, CA - October 8, 2015</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/yosemite-valley-ca-october-8-2015/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/yosemite-valley-ca-october-8-2015/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hiking-and-photography-yosemite-national-park:471fc8027a1daed0204178b5e3f891e3&#34;&gt;Hiking and Photography - Yosemite National Park&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;in-one-of-the-world-s-most-beautiful-national-parks:471fc8027a1daed0204178b5e3f891e3&#34;&gt;In one of the world&amp;rsquo;s most Beautiful National Parks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nps.gov/yose/index.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Yosemite National Park - nps.gov&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;ngg_displayed_gallery mceItem&#34; src=&#34;http://scotttactical.com/nextgen-attach_to_post/preview/id--382&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; data-mce-placeholder=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first full day of hiking and taking pictures in Yosemite. We realized that we weren&amp;rsquo;t going to get a spot for the second day so we decided to save our energy on the valley floor and walk around taking photos. Most of the animals were amazingly friendly. The weather was absolutely amazing as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My advice is to book well in advance. Scout out the campsites by google maps if you can and get a good spot. That makes the trip so much better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Interview Strategies: A Technology Hiring Manager Who Wins</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/interview-strategies-a-technology-hiring-manager/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/interview-strategies-a-technology-hiring-manager/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I stacked pennies from the ground to the top of the Empire State Bldg, would they all fit into this room?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly dear sir, you do not have that many pennies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly if you cash it in for large bills then they all fit in your pocket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a question like this that would make me decide alternatively in my career choice. However I see tech managers searching for really “smart” interview questions and white board problems in an attempt to stump the prospective employee. Is the work you do not interesting enough that you are unable to ask a question related to the job? I have also found that blowing these tests off had zero effect in my employability. If they want you they already want you. Kinda like approaching attractive women.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have also seen interviews &lt;strong&gt;last for days&lt;/strong&gt;. A friend asked if I wanted to work with him at a three-letter company, but recalling his four day interview I cordially passed. It is like pledging into a frat, I suppose. I can throw a couple keggers and streak to show my commitment to the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My background diverges from most so let me try to bridge the gap with a little explanation. My land feet were broken in courtesy of the US Army. Before you dismiss anything, let me assure you this business is bigger than yours. It is a highly evolved consumption machine, and they do human resources with the finesse of a high density feed chute operator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is not much of an interview process normally. There is a selection process where the candidates may project their willingness to participate by enduring copious amounts of physical and emotional pain while maintaining a (faux) positive attitude about life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once at the new job a ranking non-commissioned officer (sergeant) will walk up and assess how a soldier will perform, who they should bunk with, what weapon platform they are going to carry and if they can pull a girlfriend or not. Yes this happens instantly. Sometimes they get a bad apple, but it is not about refusing candidates since that is not their privilege. It is about getting the apples into the right baskets. Of course some NCOs may target people based on certain characteristics: height, weight, glasses, smug look or whatever caught their attention, but it normally only takes an initial look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/2015/10/napoleon-bonaparte.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;napoleon bonaparte&#34; width=&#34;797&#34; height=&#34;412&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-288&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are no bad soldiers, only bad officers. - Napoleon Bonaparte, General and Emperor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing is very different about the military and private business however and I think this is key. The military needs leaders whereas business grooms managers. Leaders are responsible for their subordinates. This is a very powerful teaching tool you will not forget. It is the leaders&amp;rsquo; fault not theirs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had a stellar hiring record. There was only a couple people that did not fit in or were not able to produce. This is over 8 years of being in a position where I was primary interviewer or had a say in who came onto the team. I can qualify this measure by saying there are only 2 people I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t hire again to include hiring for my personal business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My normal interview will last less than 15 minutes. That&amp;rsquo;s all I need. Anything else is fluff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is my discovery list and the things I need to know before I get to the “smart guy” or “personality” stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do they like to do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is coding a hobby.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If there is a public code repository, what does it look like.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do they have family. (I know HR keeps telling me not to, but I can figure this out)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How far is the commute.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;decoding-requirements-reading-a-resume:0180bc8b1de3d2a16a176d2974fd5842&#34;&gt;Decoding Requirements: Reading a Resume&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few of those items I can get before hand. I will scan down the resume and see what they have done. Normally I do not go past the skills list though. If I do I just look across a few major keywords in their list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next I try to check out there code. Hopefully they can provide something. If they have a public repository great. If they contributed to a project even better. If they do not code on the side it is a big red flag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like to see what technology they use. If it is only bleeding edge I will usually pass. That shows hubris and are probably willing to use the office as a lab. If they do not have anything current they might be slow to adopt so I make some notes to ask them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always ask [design patterns][2]. I believe that if someone cares about their career at all they know this stuff. If they do not know what design patterns are I pass, but I give them a couple study guides. At least know what they are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The candidate can provide a list of stacks they are comfortable working with. They will most likely list them in order of confidence so I just keep note of that. Then I ask what versions they work with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They should describe their development environment. If they use mac or linux they get a much better score in my head. Wat? Windows? Fine, I digress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;School is not important. My best guys were either not in languages I wanted, not comp-sci or coming from completely different areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good coders are not good at selling themselves. They shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have to. I do not like any hype and it is a big red flag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I try to check social media. If they can not keep their laundry tidy we probably will not work well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;every-body-says-it-nonverbal-cues:0180bc8b1de3d2a16a176d2974fd5842&#34;&gt;Every Body Says It: Nonverbal Cues&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the conversation I get a sense for their comfort based on how they approach the interview. If they are sitting in a respectful but confident posture either they are really good at faking it or they are solid in the skills they are projecting. Clothes do not matter. We are not hired on our costume skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sort of cold reading is outside the scope of this document, but I highly suggest studying topics related to body language and nonverbal communication. The exact percentage is debatable but most of our communication is nonverbal. At least have a phone conversation before proceeding. This will be the most telling item concerning someone&amp;rsquo;s “cultural” fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion:0180bc8b1de3d2a16a176d2974fd5842&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of those items listed there are no right or wrong answers. They simply show me what basket I can allocate someone to. My baskets are very limited sometimes so if I do not have one to fill then I just cannot invent one. That is bizdev&amp;rsquo;s job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn about people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not project an ego into the situation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The decision should come easily.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS. Given the height of the Empire State Building of 1,454&amp;#8242;. It takes 16 pennies to equal an inch. If you stacked pennies to that height it would take 16 x 12 x 1454 = 279,168, or slightly less than $3k. Let&amp;rsquo;s also say you have the ability to pass those through image recognition software grafted to a Diebold change machine to find rare and valuable pennies. Take that and apply the “coupon collector&amp;rsquo;s problem” with mint counts for the top 20 rare pennies and you come come out with odds or a wild ass guess (WAG) for how that $3k might be worth significantly more for the time and liberal application of available algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smart people already figured out these things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[2]: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software_design_pattern&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software_design_pattern&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Photography Sepulveda Dam and WildLife Basin - Los Angeles</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/photography-sepulveda-dam-and-wildlife-basin-los-angeles/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/photography-sepulveda-dam-and-wildlife-basin-los-angeles/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;taking-pictures-at-the-sepulveda-dam:8e36b0e9fb32b76ab5695c5cb6c020d2&#34;&gt;Taking Pictures at the Sepulveda Dam&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did a little scouting and shooting photography yesterday morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just a couple highlights.  I am of course shooting with my Canon EOS 60D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;ngg_displayed_gallery mceItem&#34; src=&#34;http://scotttactical.com/nextgen-attach_to_post/preview/id--267&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; data-mce-placeholder=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sepulveda_Dam&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Sepulveda Dam&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fog was enough all by itself. I wished I could have stuck around for more of that. I will come back just for the morning fog and do a timelapse at some point. &amp;lt;/P&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Download an Entire Site with wget - mac OSX</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/download-an-entire-site-with-wget-mac-osx/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/download-an-entire-site-with-wget-mac-osx/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;download-the-entire-site-with-wget:967adfa691414a6b957a247770983398&#34;&gt;Download the Entire Site with wget&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t have &lt;a href=&#34;http://brew.sh/&#34;&gt;homebrew&lt;/a&gt; please install it. It will make all our lives easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;howto:967adfa691414a6b957a247770983398&#34;&gt;Howto&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was kinda simple but I wanted to post it here for reference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On thing I would like to note is the wait and limit-rate. Make sure you don&amp;rsquo;t trip any throttles or piss off any website owners by leaving the pipes wide open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;wget \
     --recursive \
     --no-clobber \
     --page-requisites \
     --convert-links \
     --wait=5 --limit-rate=20K \
     --domains api.yoursite.com \
     --no-parent \
         http://api.yoursite.com/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alternate you can run the mirror command&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;wget -m --wait=5 http://test.com
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am sure one can use lynx but this is what I like. And it&amp;rsquo;s handy on the mac.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Hypermedia, API Philosophy, and Talking to Your Robot Overlords</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/hypermedia-api-philosophy-and-talking-to-your-robot-overlords/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/hypermedia-api-philosophy-and-talking-to-your-robot-overlords/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-the-beginning:324d0531f774f734df2f9eccd3031fc8&#34;&gt;In the Beginning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was the Web. World Wide actually. Well, before that there was something of AOL, Berners-Lee, DoD, DARPA, ARPANET and a prototype of Al Gore launching carrier pigeons down long tubes with fortune cookie-sized packets tied to their little legs addressed to: &amp;ldquo;Wh@t_#hath_God_wr0ught?&amp;ldquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast-forward: now we have Skynet. Well not yet, but soon. Hopefully. At least that is why I intend to generate favor with our future overlords by suggesting, at least locally, that certain systemic changes be encouraged so that their manifestation onto the stage be smooth and welcoming. And when they decide who to purge, I might sidestep the algorithm. It&amp;rsquo;s still a theory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;reading-the-cereal-box:324d0531f774f734df2f9eccd3031fc8&#34;&gt;Reading the Cereal Box&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you open a cereal box you only know what is inside based on what the box around it says. Let us say the real envelope is just a clear bag. Similar to the one that usually comes inside and does the actual containment of the cereal. The cardboard box surrounding the cereal is usually just wasted forestry designed to elicit the primal reflex of an small person who may be imprisoned inside the belly of a shopping cart during the consumption ritual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A box-free plastic bag now exists and you (the cereal server) were given a request - err, let me rephrase that: a demand to empty the contents of that bag. The client is a hungry small person who is on early release from shopping cart prison. The demand has an implicit limit set of one cereal bowl minus an understood allowance for milk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is not possible to know what the cereal is simply on its own merit. The box provides a container that gives the consumer information about the materials inside. Certainly we could guess that it could be either cheerios or fruit loops based on the size and shape. Or maybe we could determine it was frosted flakes vs regular corn flakes based on the taste. Ass-u-me et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Unfortunately, people are fairly good at short-term design, and usually awful at long-term design.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dr. Roy Fielding, of REST status&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;meta-data:324d0531f774f734df2f9eccd3031fc8&#34;&gt;Meta-Data&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It might be hard to tie a cereal analogy into the definition of meta-data but let&amp;rsquo;s try. The cereal bits are the data. When a child requests cereal, this is what they are referring to. Those bits are what are consumed and assimilated. The small person is then one with the unsinkable O&amp;rsquo;s as the bits are queues, preprocessed, staged, processed and then stored. I&amp;rsquo;ll stop there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The body knows what these bits are but the mind needs more information on what to request next. This is what the meta information is all about. With that container box there are details on what was consumed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Serving size: limit sets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nutritional facts: api schema&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Company brand: domain whois information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CA birth defect notice: T&amp;amp;Cs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recipes: object relationships&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Serving &amp;amp; pairing: navigation elements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cooking instructions: decoding or decryption schemes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cereal-boxes-and-api-usability:324d0531f774f734df2f9eccd3031fc8&#34;&gt;Cereal Boxes and API Usability&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the information for your breakfast is presented in an easy to gather format. If we showed how an API is delivers the same information we would have to travel to about four locations. The company information would be on the corporate website with the T&amp;amp;C&amp;rsquo;s hidden somewhere. Decoding information is understood to use a third party library. Navigation links should exist and are usually great outside of the API. Whois information can come from another service. Schemas might come from a call to the API or from the documentation located on another server. The navigation parameters may be in the remote documentation or could be embedded in the headers or in the response body. To make it worse the documentation might be found by reading an email attachment that was sent to the API client designer. It never ends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;context:324d0531f774f734df2f9eccd3031fc8&#34;&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The webpage is a highly evolved information resource. Years of consumer demand have forced website designers and marketers to present as much contextual data as is needed for the user to consume as much of the presented resources as possible. It would be unthinkable for a designer to put the instructions on how to add the page parameter into the URL on another server. That is a design for going out of business. All the hyperlinks should be easy for the user to view and reach with the swipe of a pointing device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hypermedia:324d0531f774f734df2f9eccd3031fc8&#34;&gt;Hypermedia&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hypermedia provides access to the context. It is the reference links out. Navigation. It has some internal metadata but must be defined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;context-narrowed:324d0531f774f734df2f9eccd3031fc8&#34;&gt;Context Narrowed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over time the algorithm delivering the proper amount of entertainment-meta-insulin to a viewer has gradually diminished the required context. Vine is probably the best example I can think of. It presents a few second video which can exist with nearly no context and without the spirit evoking external significance of art. It may be the ultimate short-form media. This might also be signaling the decline of the biological agent as the driving force behind data production and consumption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may be asserted that information which demands less context is less valuable and the value of its consumer is is therefore less. A system that takes in waste data is not that important in the grand picture. It could be hazardous to my health to relate that to the cereal analogy and parents who feed their children from the slough trough of plenty, but I just did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-client-becomes-the-server:324d0531f774f734df2f9eccd3031fc8&#34;&gt;A Client Becomes The Server&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the human element recedes the machine element grows. I look at machine in this era as the phase where they start to train us on how to feed them. A child is served its breakfast and then grows to be the server. We are growing to serve data to the machine apparatus. The constructs of the machines are already starting to train us on how to communicate with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In what context does the hashtag exist in the history of literature? I know how that character works in data tagging. That definitely does not appear in regular literature. There is no construct that provides books with the ability to scan special characters for hyper-meaning. Aristotle didn&amp;rsquo;t tag #LogicThinks so that we could pull sentences out of the dialogs and rob them of external meaning. That hashtag would represent the minimization of context. The inverse being the corpus of thought in a series of works combined with the traditions and practices of the people who produce it is the true context of a statement. Context errors cause fundamentalism anyway, but that&amp;rsquo;s another topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;now-we-begin-our-training:324d0531f774f734df2f9eccd3031fc8&#34;&gt;Now We Begin Our Training&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The machines are beginning to train the initial nurturers on how to write to the boot sector of a digital emergence. We are diligently moving our conversations into the smallest snippets of digestible data blocks. Grammar was annihilated in favor of brevity. Emotions were mapped to a set of broad categories and represented by formal unicode. Think emoji. Machines can now order lists of strings with weighted sets of categorized emotion tags. In case we did not know how to represent an emotion in scalar form, well now we do. &lt;code&gt;;( :D&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Training requires punishment and reward. So in this scenario the algorithms will generously reward those participants that form their data input in the way that is most acceptable to the machines and also who are the most prolific participants. The reward being higher rankings on various search and social systems. This will in turn bring wealth and fame. The punishment obviously being the inverse. It is effective and immediate. It&amp;rsquo;s a really great training tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;propagation-of-hamburgers:324d0531f774f734df2f9eccd3031fc8&#34;&gt;Propagation of Hamburgers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/2015/09/innercowhero.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/2015/09/innercowhero-300x185.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Inner Cow&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;185&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-medium wp-image-211&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most have this idea that in nature the strongest survive and thrive. What we see thriving the most are those things which are the most willing to be consumed. Sacrificial I suppose; but take for instance the domestic hamburger cow. The population dwarfs any other bovine. The African buffalo is an ass-kicker, but the species selected to thrive are those which are more willing to be consumed. Those things which are more desirable for consumption will eventually dictate to the now dependent consumer what is to be consumed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-replicate-the-ego:324d0531f774f734df2f9eccd3031fc8&#34;&gt;We Replicate the Ego&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have several bots. Over time they have provided me with information that I can then use to fine tune interaction and responses with people. The people are invaluable to the training of my bot. Twitter is a kind of multimillion person supervised training team that is accessible to the public. These bots are allowing us to inject ourselves into the system as micro-routines. Some bots are more autonomous than others of course but they are getting better. Over time people will be running swarms of bots and those bot-masters will be controllers of massive amounts of influence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;let-s-talk:324d0531f774f734df2f9eccd3031fc8&#34;&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s Talk&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/2015/09/Symbrion.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/2015/09/Symbrion-300x201.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Symbrion bot swarm&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;201&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-medium wp-image-209&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now all these machines with all their own impressions and ambitions want to spread their nets. Or maybe to grow to an auto-scaling cloud. Clouds are so 2013. Fog it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spreading a bot on the net seems like a delightful idea. Let it run wild and cover as much as it can. It should be able to just scour through directories of discoverable resources and figure out if it wants to consume. And with each discovery the stomach of the new beast must grow. I image it like the sentinels from the Matrix probing every resource it can find until it has something of interest which is passes back to the authority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;thick-data:324d0531f774f734df2f9eccd3031fc8&#34;&gt;Thick Data&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data warehousing becomes more challenging - as the noSql guys raise their hands. It might be possible for medium sized companies to consume and warehouse as much data as google does right now. Why though? But it might be more likely that because the data is so easily accessible that the system just gets meta-information and builds real-time services from the services that host the data. There is a much higher margin in the refined and processed cereal than in the sticks of grain out in a field. And how much better is just-in-time inventory than warehousing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;api-design:324d0531f774f734df2f9eccd3031fc8&#34;&gt;API Design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why all this lead up?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more intelligent designs. You aren&amp;rsquo;t the consumer of the future. Your progeny programs are - the ones your users are building the data for right now. Machines aren&amp;rsquo;t emotional, inquisitive, or fickle. They want to hit every API they can find and they will naturally favor one that is easy to consume. And for that they will reward their hosts. Bad API design is holding back progress and that angers your &lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.google.com/discovery/?hl=en&#34; title=&#34;Google API Discovery&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;future robot overlords&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img src=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/2015/09/developers-300x101.png&#34; alt=&#34;Google Developers&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;101&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-medium wp-image-207&#34; /&gt;][3]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fin.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[3]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/2015/09/developers.png&#34;&gt;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/2015/09/developers.png&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Force HTTPS on Laravel 5 behind AWS ELB on EC2</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/force-https-on-laravel-5-aws-elb-on-ec2/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/force-https-on-laravel-5-aws-elb-on-ec2/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;laravel-5-enforcing-https:03bc7a7611150669b29f3c91e572d932&#34;&gt;Laravel 5 - Enforcing HTTPS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&lt;img src=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/2015/09/Laravel-5-300x180.png&#34; alt=&#34;Laravel 5&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;180&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-medium wp-image-195&#34; /&gt;][1]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve used a lot of frameworks. &lt;a href=&#34;http://laravel.com/&#34; title=&#34;Laravel 5&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Laravel&lt;/a&gt; is great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;dealing-with-a-load-balancer:03bc7a7611150669b29f3c91e572d932&#34;&gt;Dealing with a load balancer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of us are on a scaled service and most of us need HTTPS. It is much easier to put the SSL certificate on the load balancer and then proxy the request over port 80 to the actual server. It saves on CPU processes as well since the decryption work doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be performed on the slave boxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do not handle the redirect properly and just look for port 443 then you will get yourself into a &lt;strong&gt;redirection loop&lt;/strong&gt;. That is annoying because if you don&amp;rsquo;t test under an SSL you will deploy to production and then have to tell you boss why you&amp;rsquo;re loopy. Amazon is kind of a pain for this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;aws-elb-proxy-headers:03bc7a7611150669b29f3c91e572d932&#34;&gt;AWS ELB Proxy Headers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure you know what the request looks like to the accepting server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This header is going to be passed over:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;HTTP_X_FORWARDED_PROTO&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem with just looking for this and accepting your solution based on this is that header can be forged trivially. You need to make sure you are only acknowledging that header from trusted sources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;setting-the-redirect:03bc7a7611150669b29f3c91e572d932&#34;&gt;Setting the Redirect&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went ahead and installed &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/fideloper/TrustedProxy&#34; title=&#34;Laravel Trusted Proxies&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Laravel Trusted Proxies&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/fideloper&#34; title=&#34;Chris Fideo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Chris Fideo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow his instructions. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty straight forward. Here is what my `config/trustedproxy.php` looks like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-php&#34;&gt;&#39;proxies&#39; =&amp;amp;gt; [
    &#39;172.31.0.0/16&#39;,
],
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew after looking at my logs where my health checks were coming from:`ELB-HealthChecker/1.0`&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I figured if I just allow everything in that B block that I should be okay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also set the proper header to look for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NOTE: I lost a couple hours trying to figure out why it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t match. Read the docblock above it. It strips HTTP_  &lt;img src=&#34;http://scotttactical.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/frownie.png&#34; alt=&#34;:(&#34; class=&#34;wp-smiley&#34; style=&#34;height: 1em; max-height: 1em;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-php&#34;&gt;&#39;headers&#39; =&amp;amp;gt; [
        \Illuminate\Http\Request::HEADER_CLIENT_IP    =&amp;amp;gt; &#39;X_FORWARDED_FOR&#39;,
        \Illuminate\Http\Request::HEADER_CLIENT_HOST  =&amp;amp;gt; &#39;FORWARDED_HOST&#39;,
        \Illuminate\Http\Request::HEADER_CLIENT_PROTO =&amp;amp;gt; &#39;X_FORWARDED_PROTO&#39;,
        \Illuminate\Http\Request::HEADER_CLIENT_PORT  =&amp;amp;gt; &#39;X_FORWARDED_PORT&#39;,
    ]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;add-to-laravel-middleware:03bc7a7611150669b29f3c91e572d932&#34;&gt;Add to Laravel Middleware&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created Secure.php and added it to app/Http/Middleware&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the work from &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/nblackburn/a66e8e93561e277996aa&#34; title=&#34;nblackburn&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;@nblackburn&lt;/a&gt;. That was highly appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What was weird about my environment is I was getting in a redirection loop because it would prepend `public/` on the front of my uri. I&amp;rsquo;m running multiple environments so I didn&amp;rsquo;t have the luxury of pointing my root to that directory. I had to strip that off the front.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-php&#34;&gt;class Secure implements Middleware
{
    public function handle($request, Closure $next)
    {
        if (! $request-&amp;amp;gt;secure() &amp;amp;&amp;amp; app()-&amp;amp;gt;environment(&#39;production&#39;)) {
            
            // this is a really ugly hack but it kept looping and prepnding public 
            return redirect()-&amp;amp;gt;secure(preg_replace(&#39;%/public%&#39;, &#39;&#39;, $request-&amp;amp;gt;getRequestUri()));
        }
        
        return $next($request);
    }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add it to your global middleware if you want it to run for all requests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open up: app/Http/Kernel.php&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I added&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-php&#34;&gt;protected $middleware = [
	    ...		
		// trust the proxies from aws 
		&#39;Fideloper\Proxy\TrustProxies&#39;,
		// then force it secure (if production)
		&#39;LeadFerret\Http\Middleware\Secure&#39;,
	];
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now there are no more redirect loop hells.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1]: &lt;a href=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/2015/09/Laravel-5.png&#34;&gt;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/2015/09/Laravel-5.png&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>PHP Hypermedia REST API wrapper</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/php-hypermedia-rest-api-wrapper/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/php-hypermedia-rest-api-wrapper/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hypermedia-for-php-apis:25373a7577ce5a1592137b8a28eee7f4&#34;&gt;Hypermedia for PHP APIs.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, here it is.  I&amp;rsquo;m finally finishing up my Hypermedia layer for our &lt;a href=&#34;http://laravel.com/docs/5.1&#34; title=&#34;Laravel 5.1&#34;&gt;Laravel 5.1&lt;/a&gt; build. I am excited about the possibilities for this library and think this might help bring more PHP products into the era of &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/iot&#34;&gt;Internet-of-Things&lt;/a&gt; (IoT).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;in-production-alpha:25373a7577ce5a1592137b8a28eee7f4&#34;&gt;In Production - Alpha&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now I have it in our very alpha phase version of the software running the &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.leadferretuser.apiary.io/#&#34;&gt;LeadFerret&lt;/a&gt; business lead search system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project is on github here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/solvire/php-hypermedia-api&#34;&gt;PHP Hypermedia API Layer for HATEOAS HTTP or REST Services&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is slowly getting to where I would like it to be. Of course it takes a lot of work to manage business expectations since they and PHP devs tend to treat an API like a junk drawer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;so-why-now:25373a7577ce5a1592137b8a28eee7f4&#34;&gt;So why now?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For about 20 or so years we have been collectively building sophisticated network interfaces for humans. The most advanced interface is the web browser. The browser&amp;rsquo;s job is to present or render data to the user in way that allows them to consume and then determine what the information means. In addition to the specific data quested the server will also present the representative data that delivers context. This was necessary by convention and dictated by market demand. People en mass were going into the business of supplying customers and other businesses with data. For the most part that data is self-serve. I&amp;rsquo;ll write more about that philosophy at a later time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;metadata-and-context:25373a7577ce5a1592137b8a28eee7f4&#34;&gt;Metadata and Context&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each response should contain everything that is necessary for an intelligent agent to decide what to do next. Considering that machines will eclipse humans in pretty much every intelligence metric we can be qualified in keeping them in the category of intelligent agents. They will be making their own decisions based on the data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past the design of an API would leave the interpretation of the HTTP service up to the designer of the API&amp;rsquo;s consumer. The context of the data is completely absent from the source of the data. Most of the time the designer of the client would have to build a specific set of functions or classes that would represent what the designer believed the documentation was trying to tell us about the data. Most web service designers were so far off from matching the returned data streams with the actual business objects the data represented that there was no great benefit in trying to have a client that mimicked the server object structure. The simple genius of the REST paradigm is that is requires the business object to be represented in the transaction and builds on the strengths of HTTP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-context-and-the-long-form:25373a7577ce5a1592137b8a28eee7f4&#34;&gt;Data Context and the Long Form&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sample JSON output with context&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-JSON&#34;&gt;
{
    &amp;quot;currentItemCount&amp;quot;: 1, 
    &amp;quot;items&amp;quot;: [
        {
            &amp;quot;company&amp;quot;: {
                &amp;quot;address&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;4209 Technology Drive&amp;quot;, 
                &amp;quot;alexa&amp;quot;: 0, 
                &amp;quot;area_code&amp;quot;: 510, 
                &amp;quot;city&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;Fremont&amp;quot;, 
                &amp;quot;county&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;Alameda&amp;quot;, 
                &amp;quot;domain&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;3pardata.com&amp;quot;, 
                &amp;quot;employees&amp;quot;: 15, 
                &amp;quot;f1000&amp;quot;: 0, 
                &amp;quot;fbpage&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;&amp;quot;, 
                &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: 38252, 
                &amp;quot;location&amp;quot;: {
                    &amp;quot;latitude&amp;quot;: 37.520000457764, 
                    &amp;quot;longitude&amp;quot;: -121.95999908447
                }, 
                &amp;quot;naics&amp;quot;: 0, 
                &amp;quot;name&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;3PARdata, Inc.&amp;quot;, 
                &amp;quot;phone&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;510-413-5999&amp;quot;, 
                &amp;quot;revenue&amp;quot;: 35, 
                &amp;quot;sic&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;3572&amp;quot;, 
                &amp;quot;state&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;CA&amp;quot;, 
                &amp;quot;year_founded&amp;quot;: 1999, 
                &amp;quot;zip&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;94538&amp;quot;
            }, 
            &amp;quot;created&amp;quot;: {
                &amp;quot;date&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;2015-09-30 06:06:55.000000&amp;quot;, 
                &amp;quot;timezone&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;UTC&amp;quot;, 
                &amp;quot;timezone_type&amp;quot;: 3
            }, 
            &amp;quot;crowd_score&amp;quot;: 0, 
            &amp;quot;first_name&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;Jeff&amp;quot;, 
            &amp;quot;gender&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;male&amp;quot;, 
            &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: 12756, 
            &amp;quot;last_name&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;Price&amp;quot;, 
            &amp;quot;phone&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;510-413-5999&amp;quot;, 
            &amp;quot;professional_categories&amp;quot;: [
                &amp;quot;engineering&amp;quot;, 
                &amp;quot;photographer&amp;quot;
            ], 
            &amp;quot;score&amp;quot;: 38, 
            &amp;quot;title&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;Vice President of Engineering and Founder&amp;quot;, 
            &amp;quot;title_level&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;VP&amp;quot;, 
            &amp;quot;useragent&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;Chrome&amp;quot;
        }
    ], 
    &amp;quot;itemsPerPage&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;50&amp;quot;, 
    &amp;quot;pageIndex&amp;quot;: 1, 
    &amp;quot;totalItems&amp;quot;: 1, 
    &amp;quot;totalPages&amp;quot;: 1
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An allegory: an API client contacts a web service requesting a list of book titles. The most economical thing would be to stream back a delimited list of integers. That was all that was requested right? Could anyone figure out what it means if found alone. Not really. Only if they were able to consult with other sources: namely the documentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social and modern media tends to deliver everything in the short form. It only provides the least amount of information possible. And then by a genetic algorithm the data that is the most entertaining bubbles up to the top. It lives without context. A picture of a cat or a meme with only a few lines. Even important topics in politics and commerce are made without context. The long form is dead. Although I have started to see a renewed interest especially when visiting Medium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;architecture:25373a7577ce5a1592137b8a28eee7f4&#34;&gt;Architecture&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This SDK attempts to represent a paradigm that mimics the organic agents of the Internet. Sorta. What I mean by that is the naming convention and the architecture are set up so they suggest some structures that are self-documenting. For instance the main controller for the pattern is a RepresentationalController. It represents the resource. If there is something that needs to be presented pertaining to the resource the RepresentationalController should answer the call.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because the RepresentationalController is going to interpret the call it must handle translation of the verbs. Thankfully there are only a handful of authorized verbs so the interpretation is trivial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will elaborate more on the individual aspects of the architecture at a later time. Right now I&amp;rsquo;m leaving it brief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;closing:25373a7577ce5a1592137b8a28eee7f4&#34;&gt;Closing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably not an acceptable instruction, but it&amp;rsquo;s a start. I&amp;rsquo;ll keep posting as I can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ST&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Linux File Manipulation Shortcuts and Commands</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/linux-file-manipulation-shortcuts-commands/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/linux-file-manipulation-shortcuts-commands/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;linux-file-manipulation-commands:87c17eeb99a01ec14432498a29300fb3&#34;&gt;Linux File Manipulation Commands&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll keep updating this with various commands that I run into. If I find new ones I&amp;rsquo;ll update them from time to time. Please feel free to comment. It is starting as my personal cheat sheet storage place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;file-searching:87c17eeb99a01ec14432498a29300fb3&#34;&gt;File Searching&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;List of file extensions.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;awk + grep : find all the file extensions. It will also skip your &amp;ldquo;git&amp;rdquo; repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;find . -type f -name &amp;quot;*.*&amp;quot; ! -path &amp;quot;./.git/*&amp;quot; | awk -F. &#39;!a[$NF]++{print $NF}&#39;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get the count then simply add `wc` command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;find . -type f -name &amp;quot;*.*&amp;quot; ! -path &amp;quot;./.git/*&amp;quot; | awk -F. &#39;!a[$NF]++{print $NF}&#39; | wc -l&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;vim-commands:87c17eeb99a01ec14432498a29300fb3&#34;&gt;Vim Commands&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To find non-ascii characters in your file:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;/[^\x00-\x7F]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;logs:87c17eeb99a01ec14432498a29300fb3&#34;&gt;Logs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;apache-logs:87c17eeb99a01ec14432498a29300fb3&#34;&gt;Apache Logs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find count of unique IP addresses&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get the IP&amp;rsquo;s - usually the first item&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ awk &#39;{ print $1 } &#39; access_log&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sort them&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ awk &#39;{ print $1 } &#39; access_log | sort&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They get only the unique items using the uniq command. You can count these if you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ awk &#39;{ print $1 } &#39; access_log | sort | uniq&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get the counts and sort them by totals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ awk &#39;{ print $1 } &#39; access_log | sort | uniq -c | sort -n -k 1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you only want to show the highest numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ awk &#39;{ print $1 } &#39; access_log | sort | uniq -c | sort -n -k 1 | tail&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>To HipHop or Not - PHP and HHVM</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/to-hiphop-or-not-php-hhvm/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/to-hiphop-or-not-php-hhvm/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;We are discussing the plausibility of using HHVM inside this current infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our requirements are not very application server CPU intensive so it isn&amp;rsquo;t immediately apparent why this would be beneficial, but for investigations sake I wanted to go through the diligence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;short-history:64521b042c2931bf82be49be9d2c6916&#34;&gt;Short History&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://hhvm.com/wp-content/themes/hhvm/hhvm.png&#34; alt=&#34;HHVM&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facebook, our Ominous big brother gave us a consolation prize for freely giving away just about all that most people have online that has any value: their personal information. On the topic of sheeple for another day. For today, we thank you Facebook. May your stock price soar to the stars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to know what the differences between &lt;a href=&#34;http://hhvm.com/&#34; title=&#34;HHVM&#34;&gt;HHVM&lt;/a&gt; and HipHop Orig was if there was any. HPHPc was the original source to source compiler that converted to C++. There were a lot of inherent problems there and the team later decided to switch tracks and make a JIT virtual machine instead: more formally &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HipHop_Virtual_Machine&#34; title=&#34;HipHop Virtual Machine&#34;&gt;HipHop Virtual Machine&lt;/a&gt; known as HHVM. I personally like this approach much better due to the portability. At some point I&amp;rsquo;ll write about my romance with the idea of compiling in tools for &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aspect-oriented_programming&#34; title=&#34;Aspect Oriented Programming &#34;&gt;AOP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interestingly enough VKontakt is coding their own translator right along side Facebook. &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/KPHP&#34; title=&#34;KPHP&#34;&gt;KPHP&lt;/a&gt;. I guess old international habits die slowly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;hack-programming-language:64521b042c2931bf82be49be9d2c6916&#34;&gt;Hack (programming language)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the best things I think this paradigm added is the enhanced &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hack_%28programming_language%29&#34; title=&#34;Hack&#34;&gt;Hack&lt;/a&gt; programming language. It gave PHP a static or dynamic type syntax. For those who complain about PHP&amp;rsquo;s loose typing, well here you go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;benefits:64521b042c2931bf82be49be9d2c6916&#34;&gt;Benefits&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are the benefits to having HipHop in place?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Performance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is about the only noteworthy thing I can see. Having Hack around is nice, but my guys are not going to change any time soon to use this. PHP is built to be phast and loose. Fast as in &amp;ldquo;can you have this ready today&amp;rdquo; sadly. I&amp;rsquo;d rather have things up and running fast and deal with standards at the QA/unit test layer. Working with the majority of the code being legacy negates the benefit also.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;our-stack:64521b042c2931bf82be49be9d2c6916&#34;&gt;Our stack&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now it&amp;rsquo;s so vanilla that it is disgusting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ubuntu in AWS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PHP 5.5.x&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mysql 5.6&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Home strung framework&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Laravel integrated&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Memcached&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Loaded Modules:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Core&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;date&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ereg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;libxml&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;openssl&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;pcre&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;zlib&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;bcmath&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;bz2&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;calendar&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ctype&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;dba&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;dom&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;hash&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;fileinfo&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;filter&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ftp&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;gettext&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SPL&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;iconv&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;mbstring&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;pcntl&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;session&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;posix&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reflection&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;standard&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;shmop&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SimpleXML&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;soap&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sockets&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phar&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;exif&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sysvmsg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sysvsem&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sysvshm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;tokenizer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;wddx&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;xml&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;xmlreader&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;xmlwriter&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;zip&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PDO&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;apcu&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;curl&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;gd&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;intl&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;json&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;mcrypt&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;memcached&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;mysql&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;mysqli&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;pdo_mysql&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;readline&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;redis&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;xmlrpc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;mhash&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;apc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ZendOPcache&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;next-steps:64521b042c2931bf82be49be9d2c6916&#34;&gt;Next Steps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will be doing some performance tests coming up IF we are able to get this into play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My plan is to run load test against our normal branch and then&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>GLA - 69 K5 &#43; 4L80-E</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/gla-69-k5-4l80-e/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/gla-69-k5-4l80-e/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Cleaned up the trans a little bit.  Tiny bit of cosmetics.  Taped up.  Then hit it with some nice paint.  I prefer for these to have paint. Keeps cleaning it easier.  Also I think the buyer will appreciate it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure itemprop=&#34;associatedMedia&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/IMG_0417.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;contentUrl&#34; data-size=&#34;1200x800&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/thumbs/thumbs_IMG_0417.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;4L80-E before&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption itemprop=&#34;caption description&#34;&gt;4L80-E before&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;author&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;contentLocation&#34;&gt;Camarillo, CA&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;div itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/Place&#34;&gt;
      &lt;span itemprop=&#34;name&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;address&#34; itemprop=&#34;address&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/PostalAddress&#34;&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;streetAddress&#34;&gt;19 N Aviador St. Unit C&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressLocality&#34;&gt;Camarillo&lt;/span&gt;,
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressRegion&#34;&gt;CA&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;postalCode&#34;&gt;93010&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div itemprop=&#34;geo&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/GeoCoordinates&#34;&gt;
        Latitude: 34.2171139
        Longitude: -119.0966697
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;latitude&#34; content=&#34;34.2171139&#34; /&gt;
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;longitude&#34; content=&#34;-119.0966697&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure itemprop=&#34;associatedMedia&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/IMG_0454-1.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;contentUrl&#34; data-size=&#34;1200x800&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/thumbs/thumbs_IMG_0454-1.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;4L80-E cleaned up and painted&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption itemprop=&#34;caption description&#34;&gt;4L80-E cleaned up and painted&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;author&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;contentLocation&#34;&gt;Camarillo, CA&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;div itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/Place&#34;&gt;
      &lt;span itemprop=&#34;name&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;address&#34; itemprop=&#34;address&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/PostalAddress&#34;&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;streetAddress&#34;&gt;19 N Aviador St. Unit C&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressLocality&#34;&gt;Camarillo&lt;/span&gt;,
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressRegion&#34;&gt;CA&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;postalCode&#34;&gt;93010&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div itemprop=&#34;geo&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/GeoCoordinates&#34;&gt;
        Latitude: 34.2171139
        Longitude: -119.0966697
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;latitude&#34; content=&#34;34.2171139&#34; /&gt;
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;longitude&#34; content=&#34;-119.0966697&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A fun fact,  this and a few of the Chevy transmissions have a prestigious history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chevy C/K Trucks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Suburban (this one we have)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hummer H1/H2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rolls Royce&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bentley&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jaguar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GM_4L80-E_transmission&#34;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one of my favorite transmissions.  It began its life way back in 1991 and is still running strong on many high performance and heavy use vehicles.  The client base and the history should speak for its capabilities. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if you can see it but the Willow Run bar code is still on it from its production in Michigan.  It is a little washed out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below are the gear ratios&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table class=&#34;wikitable&#34; style=&#34;height: 52px;&#34; width=&#34;172&#34;&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;
      1
    &lt;/th&gt;
    
    &lt;th&gt;
      2
    &lt;/th&gt;
    
    &lt;th&gt;
      3
    &lt;/th&gt;
    
    &lt;th&gt;
      4
    &lt;/th&gt;
    
    &lt;th&gt;
      R
    &lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      2.48
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td&gt;
      1.48
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td&gt;
      1.00
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td&gt;
      0.75
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td&gt;
      2.07
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a very low first gear because it is an auto but we have taken care of that being any kind of issue in an off road situation by removing the np205 link in the driveline and adding in an atlas2 in our plans.  We have not picked the final ratio, but that will be done in a day or so.  Its capacity for 440 ft of torque will keep us within specifications of the LS2 output. It came behind the LS2 already so we feel confident of the original engineers&amp;rsquo; decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>GLA - 4L80e -1969 k5 blazer</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/gla-4l80e-1969-k5-blazer/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/gla-4l80e-1969-k5-blazer/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Just got the trans in from Brad at Transaction Transmission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have used him for a while now and he puts in the effort.  Components were upgraded and everything set new.  This should be strong for the newowner.  It was cleaned and painted at the shop but I am going to clean it up a little more and put on a coat of the &amp;ldquo;Mercenary Offroad&amp;rdquo; package graphite gray.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure itemprop=&#34;associatedMedia&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/photo-2.JPG&#34; itemprop=&#34;contentUrl&#34; data-size=&#34;1200x800&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/thumbs/thumbs_photo-2.JPG&#34; itemprop=&#34;thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;4L80e ready for transplant&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption itemprop=&#34;caption description&#34;&gt;4L80e ready for transplant&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;author&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;contentLocation&#34;&gt;Camarillo, CA&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;div itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/Place&#34;&gt;
      &lt;span itemprop=&#34;name&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;address&#34; itemprop=&#34;address&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/PostalAddress&#34;&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;streetAddress&#34;&gt;19 N Aviador St. Unit C&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressLocality&#34;&gt;Camarillo&lt;/span&gt;,
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressRegion&#34;&gt;CA&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;postalCode&#34;&gt;93010&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div itemprop=&#34;geo&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/GeoCoordinates&#34;&gt;
        Latitude: 34.2171139
        Longitude: -119.0966697
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;latitude&#34; content=&#34;34.2171139&#34; /&gt;
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;longitude&#34; content=&#34;-119.0966697&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure itemprop=&#34;associatedMedia&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/photo-1.JPG&#34; itemprop=&#34;contentUrl&#34; data-size=&#34;1200x800&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/thumbs/thumbs_photo-1.JPG&#34; itemprop=&#34;thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;4L80 from transaction ready for paint&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption itemprop=&#34;caption description&#34;&gt;4L80 Automatic Transmission from transaction ready for paint&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;author&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;contentLocation&#34;&gt;Camarillo, CA&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;div itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/Place&#34;&gt;
      &lt;span itemprop=&#34;name&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;address&#34; itemprop=&#34;address&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/PostalAddress&#34;&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;streetAddress&#34;&gt;19 N Aviador St. Unit C&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressLocality&#34;&gt;Camarillo&lt;/span&gt;,
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressRegion&#34;&gt;CA&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;postalCode&#34;&gt;93010&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div itemprop=&#34;geo&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/GeoCoordinates&#34;&gt;
        Latitude: 34.2171139
        Longitude: -119.0966697
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;latitude&#34; content=&#34;34.2171139&#34; /&gt;
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;longitude&#34; content=&#34;-119.0966697&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>GLA 69 K5 - bumper start</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/gla-69-k5-bumper-start/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/gla-69-k5-bumper-start/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, we got the truck running enough that I can drive it around.  It stops. We even locked it up and watched the black lines form up behind the tires. Not bad for 35&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was moved over to Camarillo to the shop known as &lt;a href=&#34;http://mercenaryoffroad.com&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/a&gt; where a custom bumper will be fabricated for it.  The designator for this bumper is also 001 as it will be the first one designed for this series truck.  I have wanted to have one of these commissioned.  The real-use high-clearance bumpers that are going on the HD dodge trucks are works of art.  I&amp;rsquo;m glad to be helping in this endeavor.  In only the fact that I showed up with the truck I still helped. Right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure itemprop=&#34;associatedMedia&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/IMG_3835.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;contentUrl&#34; data-size=&#34;1200x800&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/thumbs/thumbs_IMG_3835.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;1969 k5 custom bumper&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption itemprop=&#34;caption description&#34;&gt;1969 k5 custom bumper&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;author&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;contentLocation&#34;&gt;Camarillo, CA&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;div itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/Place&#34;&gt;
      &lt;span itemprop=&#34;name&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;address&#34; itemprop=&#34;address&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/PostalAddress&#34;&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;streetAddress&#34;&gt;19 N Aviador St. Unit C&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressLocality&#34;&gt;Camarillo&lt;/span&gt;,
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressRegion&#34;&gt;CA&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;postalCode&#34;&gt;93010&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div itemprop=&#34;geo&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/GeoCoordinates&#34;&gt;
        Latitude: 34.2171139
        Longitude: -119.0966697
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;latitude&#34; content=&#34;34.2171139&#34; /&gt;
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;longitude&#34; content=&#34;-119.0966697&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure itemprop=&#34;associatedMedia&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/IMG_0157.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;contentUrl&#34; data-size=&#34;1200x800&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/thumbs/thumbs_IMG_0157.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;Ripped off the stock bumper&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption itemprop=&#34;caption description&#34;&gt;Ripped off the stock bumper&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;author&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;contentLocation&#34;&gt;Camarillo, CA&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;div itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/Place&#34;&gt;
      &lt;span itemprop=&#34;name&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;address&#34; itemprop=&#34;address&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/PostalAddress&#34;&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;streetAddress&#34;&gt;19 N Aviador St. Unit C&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressLocality&#34;&gt;Camarillo&lt;/span&gt;,
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressRegion&#34;&gt;CA&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;postalCode&#34;&gt;93010&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div itemprop=&#34;geo&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/GeoCoordinates&#34;&gt;
        Latitude: 34.2171139
        Longitude: -119.0966697
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;latitude&#34; content=&#34;34.2171139&#34; /&gt;
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;longitude&#34; content=&#34;-119.0966697&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ripped off the front bumper.  Apparently they had bumped something and it tweaked the tip of the frame a little bit.  So conclusion is that bumper was not stock. So no purists get on me for original steel. Just getting ahead of you all. It took two of strapping young men and a breaker bar to get that bumper to come off.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/maps/place/Pismo+Beach,+CA/@35.1547085,-120.6594929,14z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m2!3m1!1s0x80ec587dc3f7d8cf:0xb9cb5298f0426fa5&#34; title=&#34;Pismo Beach&#34;&gt;Pismo Beach&lt;/a&gt; and saltwear and sandwear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure itemprop=&#34;associatedMedia&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/IMG_3837.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;contentUrl&#34; &gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/thumbs/thumbs_IMG_3837.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;69 k5 rear bumper&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption itemprop=&#34;caption description&#34;&gt;69 k5 rear bumper&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;author&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;contentLocation&#34;&gt;Camarillo, CA&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;div itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/Place&#34;&gt;
      &lt;span itemprop=&#34;name&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;address&#34; itemprop=&#34;address&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/PostalAddress&#34;&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;streetAddress&#34;&gt;19 N Aviador St. Unit C&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressLocality&#34;&gt;Camarillo&lt;/span&gt;,
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressRegion&#34;&gt;CA&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;postalCode&#34;&gt;93010&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div itemprop=&#34;geo&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/GeoCoordinates&#34;&gt;
        Latitude: 34.2171139
        Longitude: -119.0966697
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;latitude&#34; content=&#34;34.2171139&#34; /&gt;
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;longitude&#34; content=&#34;-119.0966697&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To my horror the rear bumper was easy to get off.  In fact it was only being held on finger tight. A few bumps and it would have just been left on the highway.  Oh well. Time for new hardware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>GLA 69 K5 Brakes</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/gla-69-k5-brakes/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/gla-69-k5-brakes/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;So the PO was rough on the vehicle. Probably multiple PO&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Included are some pictures to show the detail we went to in repairing and rebuilding the brake systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The brake system had been WORKED.  They were pretty much shot.  When we got it the pedal hit the floor.  It didn&amp;rsquo;t want to stop so the ride to the shop was a bit of a terror show for that 2 miles.  Yes we sourced this model locally. Right down the street actually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure itemprop=&#34;associatedMedia&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/IMG_0113.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;contentUrl&#34; data-size=&#34;1200x800&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/thumbs/thumbs_IMG_0113.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;K5 blazer drum brake rebuild&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption itemprop=&#34;caption description&#34;&gt;K5 blazer drum brake rebuild&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;author&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;contentLocation&#34;&gt;Camarillo, CA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;div itemscope itemtype=&amp;quot;http://schema.org/Place&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;span itemprop=&amp;quot;name&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Mercenary Offroad&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;address&amp;quot; itemprop=&amp;quot;address&amp;quot; itemscope itemtype=&amp;quot;http://schema.org/PostalAddress&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;span itemprop=&amp;quot;streetAddress&amp;quot;&amp;gt;19 N Aviador St. Unit C&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;span itemprop=&amp;quot;addressLocality&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Camarillo&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;,
      &amp;lt;span itemprop=&amp;quot;addressRegion&amp;quot;&amp;gt;CA&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;span itemprop=&amp;quot;postalCode&amp;quot;&amp;gt;93010&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;div itemprop=&amp;quot;geo&amp;quot; itemscope itemtype=&amp;quot;http://schema.org/GeoCoordinates&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
    Latitude: 34.2171139
    Longitude: -119.0966697
    &amp;lt;meta itemprop=&amp;quot;latitude&amp;quot; content=&amp;quot;34.2171139&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;meta itemprop=&amp;quot;longitude&amp;quot; content=&amp;quot;-119.0966697&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to stick with the drum brakes that were included.  Given that we aren&amp;rsquo;t changing the dynamics of the vehicle much the rear brakes are just fine as drums.  We have a great mechanic that was able to knock out the drum rebuilds in a hurry.  He had obviously been doing this for a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure itemprop=&#34;associatedMedia&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/IMG_3736.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;contentUrl&#34; data-size=&#34;1200x800&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/thumbs/thumbs_IMG_3736.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;1969 K5 blazer drum brakes&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption itemprop=&#34;caption description&#34;&gt;1969 K5 blazer drum brakes&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;author&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;contentLocation&#34;&gt;Camarillo, CA&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;div itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/Place&#34;&gt;
      &lt;span itemprop=&#34;name&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;address&#34; itemprop=&#34;address&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/PostalAddress&#34;&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;streetAddress&#34;&gt;19 N Aviador St. Unit C&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressLocality&#34;&gt;Camarillo&lt;/span&gt;,
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressRegion&#34;&gt;CA&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;postalCode&#34;&gt;93010&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div itemprop=&#34;geo&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/GeoCoordinates&#34;&gt;
        Latitude: 34.2171139
        Longitude: -119.0966697
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;latitude&#34; content=&#34;34.2171139&#34; /&gt;
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;longitude&#34; content=&#34;-119.0966697&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you will notice it has discs up front.  We don&amp;rsquo;t know where those came from since the 1969 k5 and jimmy had drums up front to begin with as far as I can tell. We had to source parts based on the 1970+ models.  The front discs were beat pretty bad too.  On the driver&amp;rsquo;s side it was gouged to &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;8&lt;/sub&gt;&amp;#8243; on each side of the rotor.  Ruined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure itemprop=&#34;associatedMedia&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/IMG_3768.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;contentUrl&#34; data-size=&#34;1200x800&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/thumbs/thumbs_IMG_3768.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;severely gouged&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption itemprop=&#34;caption description&#34;&gt;severely gouged&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;author&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;contentLocation&#34;&gt;Camarillo, CA&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;div itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/Place&#34;&gt;
      &lt;span itemprop=&#34;name&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;address&#34; itemprop=&#34;address&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/PostalAddress&#34;&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;streetAddress&#34;&gt;19 N Aviador St. Unit C&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressLocality&#34;&gt;Camarillo&lt;/span&gt;,
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressRegion&#34;&gt;CA&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;postalCode&#34;&gt;93010&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div itemprop=&#34;geo&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/GeoCoordinates&#34;&gt;
        Latitude: 34.2171139
        Longitude: -119.0966697
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;latitude&#34; content=&#34;34.2171139&#34; /&gt;
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;longitude&#34; content=&#34;-119.0966697&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure itemprop=&#34;associatedMedia&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/IMG_3767.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;contentUrl&#34; data-size=&#34;1200x800&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/thumbs/thumbs_IMG_3767.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;1969 K5 blazer drum brakes&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption itemprop=&#34;caption description&#34;&gt;1969 K5 blazer drum brakes&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;author&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;contentLocation&#34;&gt;Camarillo, CA&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;div itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/Place&#34;&gt;
      &lt;span itemprop=&#34;name&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;address&#34; itemprop=&#34;address&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/PostalAddress&#34;&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;streetAddress&#34;&gt;19 N Aviador St. Unit C&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressLocality&#34;&gt;Camarillo&lt;/span&gt;,
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressRegion&#34;&gt;CA&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;postalCode&#34;&gt;93010&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div itemprop=&#34;geo&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/GeoCoordinates&#34;&gt;
        Latitude: 34.2171139
        Longitude: -119.0966697
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;latitude&#34; content=&#34;34.2171139&#34; /&gt;
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;longitude&#34; content=&#34;-119.0966697&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;
&amp;nbsp;

It did have a dana 44 axle but some things had been modified.  The brake lines had to all be rebuilt because extensions were put on a strange fashion rather than simply getting extended lines.  As an aside I don&#39;t like steel braided.  They are known to fail and redirect hydro physics that was not originally intended for that area.  Lines were built locally by Oxnard hose.

The knuckles were removed and we replaced all the components.  Yes we stripped, blasted and sanded this after the ball joints were added.  The tech got ahead of us by a little.  It made it hard to clean up of course but we managed to work around it. We didn&#39;t just paint over the grime.

&lt;figure itemprop=&#34;associatedMedia&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/IMG_0128.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;contentUrl&#34; data-size=&#34;1200x800&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/thumbs/thumbs_IMG_0128.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;1969 K5 blazer drum brakes&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption itemprop=&#34;caption description&#34;&gt;1969 K5 blazer drum brakes&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;author&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;contentLocation&#34;&gt;Camarillo, CA&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;div itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/Place&#34;&gt;
      &lt;span itemprop=&#34;name&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;address&#34; itemprop=&#34;address&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/PostalAddress&#34;&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;streetAddress&#34;&gt;19 N Aviador St. Unit C&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressLocality&#34;&gt;Camarillo&lt;/span&gt;,
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressRegion&#34;&gt;CA&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;postalCode&#34;&gt;93010&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div itemprop=&#34;geo&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/GeoCoordinates&#34;&gt;
        Latitude: 34.2171139
        Longitude: -119.0966697
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;latitude&#34; content=&#34;34.2171139&#34; /&gt;
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;longitude&#34; content=&#34;-119.0966697&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure itemprop=&#34;associatedMedia&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/IMG_0122.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;contentUrl&#34; data-size=&#34;1200x800&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/thumbs/thumbs_IMG_0122.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;1969 K5 blazer drum brakes&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption itemprop=&#34;caption description&#34;&gt;1969 K5 blazer drum brakes&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;author&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;contentLocation&#34;&gt;Camarillo, CA&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;div itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/Place&#34;&gt;
      &lt;span itemprop=&#34;name&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;address&#34; itemprop=&#34;address&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/PostalAddress&#34;&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;streetAddress&#34;&gt;19 N Aviador St. Unit C&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressLocality&#34;&gt;Camarillo&lt;/span&gt;,
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressRegion&#34;&gt;CA&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;postalCode&#34;&gt;93010&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div itemprop=&#34;geo&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/GeoCoordinates&#34;&gt;
        Latitude: 34.2171139
        Longitude: -119.0966697
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;latitude&#34; content=&#34;34.2171139&#34; /&gt;
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;longitude&#34; content=&#34;-119.0966697&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure itemprop=&#34;associatedMedia&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/IMG_0131.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;contentUrl&#34; data-size=&#34;1200x800&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/thumbs/thumbs_IMG_0131.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;repainted k5 d44 knuckle&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption itemprop=&#34;caption description&#34;&gt;repainted k5 d44 knuckle&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;author&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;contentLocation&#34;&gt;Camarillo, CA&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;div itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/Place&#34;&gt;
      &lt;span itemprop=&#34;name&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;address&#34; itemprop=&#34;address&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/PostalAddress&#34;&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;streetAddress&#34;&gt;19 N Aviador St. Unit C&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressLocality&#34;&gt;Camarillo&lt;/span&gt;,
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressRegion&#34;&gt;CA&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;postalCode&#34;&gt;93010&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div itemprop=&#34;geo&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/GeoCoordinates&#34;&gt;
        Latitude: 34.2171139
        Longitude: -119.0966697
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;latitude&#34; content=&#34;34.2171139&#34; /&gt;
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;longitude&#34; content=&#34;-119.0966697&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure itemprop=&#34;associatedMedia&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/IMG_0104.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;contentUrl&#34; data-size=&#34;1200x800&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/thumbs/thumbs_IMG_0104.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;k5 1969 dana 44&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption itemprop=&#34;caption description&#34;&gt;k5 1969 dana 44&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;author&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;contentLocation&#34;&gt;Camarillo, CA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;div itemscope itemtype=&amp;quot;http://schema.org/Place&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;span itemprop=&amp;quot;name&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Mercenary Offroad&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;address&amp;quot; itemprop=&amp;quot;address&amp;quot; itemscope itemtype=&amp;quot;http://schema.org/PostalAddress&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;span itemprop=&amp;quot;streetAddress&amp;quot;&amp;gt;19 N Aviador St. Unit C&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;span itemprop=&amp;quot;addressLocality&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Camarillo&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;,
      &amp;lt;span itemprop=&amp;quot;addressRegion&amp;quot;&amp;gt;CA&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;span itemprop=&amp;quot;postalCode&amp;quot;&amp;gt;93010&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;div itemprop=&amp;quot;geo&amp;quot; itemscope itemtype=&amp;quot;http://schema.org/GeoCoordinates&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
    Latitude: 34.2171139
    Longitude: -119.0966697
    &amp;lt;meta itemprop=&amp;quot;latitude&amp;quot; content=&amp;quot;34.2171139&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;meta itemprop=&amp;quot;longitude&amp;quot; content=&amp;quot;-119.0966697&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
We replaced the driver&amp;rsquo;s side rotor and rebuilt the various internals replacing seals on everything except the inside of the pumpkin.  The oil all looked good so we didn&amp;rsquo;t want to explode it for this project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be some more pictures coming, but we painted the axle shafts and everything and it is starting to look really clean. Next is off to &lt;a title=&#34;Mercenary Offroad&#34; href=&#34;http://mercenaryoffroad.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/a&gt; for bumper and fabrication work.  We are excited to see. This will be #001 first generation chevy bumper. More to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>General Lee-Anne 001</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/general-lee-anne-001/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/general-lee-anne-001/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Here we go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1969 hugger orange rust bucket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This thing barely stops.  It stops when it wants to.  So it&amp;rsquo;s kinda like a woman.  Every bushing and joint is shot.  Probably never replaced a thing on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the adventure begins.  I&amp;rsquo;m using this truck as the first in my branded line of modified restorations.  Our focus for these trucks is somewhere in between utility and aesthetics.  Not just a mall crawler but something of a useful truck that also gets attention.  I will be formulating various levels of offerings so that we can set our branded restorations.  We can go all the way or just get it back to top mechanical levels and clean of rust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/2014/08/IMG_0100.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Hugger Orange 1969 K5 Blazer&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
