<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Philosophy on Scott Tactical</title>
    <link>http://scotttactical.com/tags/philosophy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Philosophy on Scott Tactical</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 18:51:01 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://scotttactical.com/tags/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Vehemenism</title>
      <link>http://scotttactical.com/post/vehemenism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 18:51:01 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scotttactical.com/post/vehemenism/</guid>
      <description>Preface to Vehemenism Opening letter to future ultra-violent men.
We stand at a transition. Either at the bottom of a cliff we may ascend, or at the precipice of one we will be pushed from. This &amp;ldquo;we&amp;rdquo; is addressed to men alone. Only we are the ones presented with this unique problem. It is a problem of perspective and one that contains many recursive questions. The answer to these questions will ultimately decide whether or not the observer was indeed a man.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Wrong With Millennials</title>
      <link>http://scotttactical.com/whats-wrong-with-millennials/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 20:00:32 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scotttactical.com/whats-wrong-with-millennials/</guid>
      <description>What is Up With Those Millennials? Ah, yes. The click bait. A marketing construct of the GenX&amp;rsquo;ers: pornographic gossip without the payoff.
But, since you are here&amp;hellip;
My Motivation: Agism I have become infuriated seeing one segment of United States citizenry be the target of a multiple-party attack. This pressure has been escalating over the last couple of years, and I wanted to make a number of assertions and lay out some warnings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Conservatism Fails</title>
      <link>http://scotttactical.com/why-conservatism-fails/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2015 17:18:43 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scotttactical.com/why-conservatism-fails/</guid>
      <description>This essay is not an attack on the people who claim membership to a philosophical outlook, but an exposition on the inherent difficulties which exist in maintaining traditional systems.
Let us begin with the needful: term definition.
Term Definition  Conservatism as a political and social philosophy promotes retaining traditional social institutions in the context of the culture and civilization.
 This is the definition found at Wikipedia and I find it to be a pretty good summation of the idea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eat For War</title>
      <link>http://scotttactical.com/post/eat-for-war/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2015 01:23:11 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scotttactical.com/post/eat-for-war/</guid>
      <description>Bad men live that they may eat and drink, whereas good men eat and drink that they may live. Socrates - Plutarch, How a Young Man Ought to Hear Poems
 A Warrior&amp;rsquo;s Diet What physically intimate activity do we participate in more than any other?
Eating
The Philosophy One of the more immediate steps in becoming awake is overcoming the omnivore&amp;rsquo;s dilemma. The passion of hunger. We take other living things into our bodies and literally become one with them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypermedia, API Philosophy, and Talking to Your Robot Overlords</title>
      <link>http://scotttactical.com/hypermedia-api-philosophy-and-talking-to-your-robot-overlords/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scotttactical.com/hypermedia-api-philosophy-and-talking-to-your-robot-overlords/</guid>
      <description>In the Beginning There was the Web. World Wide actually. Well, before that there was something of AOL, Berners-Lee, DoD, DARPA, ARPANET and a prototype of Al Gore launching carrier pigeons down long tubes with fortune cookie-sized packets tied to their little legs addressed to: &amp;ldquo;Wh@t_#hath_God_wr0ught?&amp;ldquo;.
Fast-forward: now we have Skynet. Well not yet, but soon. Hopefully. At least that is why I intend to generate favor with our future overlords by suggesting, at least locally, that certain systemic changes be encouraged so that their manifestation onto the stage be smooth and welcoming.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>