<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scott Tactical </title>
    <link>http://scotttactical.com/tags/philosophy/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Scott Tactical</author>
    <rights>(C) 2015</rights>
    <updated>2015-11-13 17:18:43 -0800 PST</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>Why Conservatism Fails</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/why-conservatism-fails</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2015 17:18:43 PST</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/why-conservatism-fails</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;This essay is not an attack on the people who claim membership to a philosophical outlook, but an exposition on the inherent difficulties which exist in maintaining traditional systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let us begin with the needful: &lt;em&gt;term definition&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;term-definition:83be2de4f953a80cbb055699f5405f84&#34;&gt;Term Definition&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conservatism&#34; title=&#34;Conservatism&#34;&gt;Conservatism&lt;/a&gt; as a political and social philosophy promotes retaining traditional social institutions in the context of the culture and civilization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the definition found at &lt;em&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/em&gt; and I find it to be a pretty good summation of the idea. Conservatives are those who hold the belief that there is value in the current institutions and that change will have negative effect on the systems of value that the previous generations have passed forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;tradition:83be2de4f953a80cbb055699f5405f84&#34;&gt;Tradition&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tradition&lt;/strong&gt; is the central artifact standing trial with the conservative attitude being its defender. Traditions are the cultural habits and values that are passed forward from generation to generation. They internally contain the characteristics and identity of the people who pass them forward. Not in form, but in essence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;neoconservatism:83be2de4f953a80cbb055699f5405f84&#34;&gt;Neoconservatism&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neoconservatism&lt;/strong&gt; is a relatively new term and also did not come with a clear definition. In short this term describes a political label over those who are best described as aristocratically focused and would tend to be both fascist and progressive at the same time. I will dive a little deeper into that term at another time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;paleoconservatism:83be2de4f953a80cbb055699f5405f84&#34;&gt;Paleoconservatism&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paleoconservatism&#34; title=&#34;Paleoconservatism&#34;&gt;Paleoconservatism&lt;/a&gt; (sometimes shortened to paleocon) is a conservative political philosophy found primarily in the United States stressing tradition, limited government, civil society, anti-colonialism and anti-federalism, along with religious, regional, national and Western identity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This also is a newer term, but is embedded with metadata concerning the context by which the term resolves. It asserts through its prefix that it is of ancient origin. Because most are incapable of looking back before the start of the country I suppose it will suffice to say that the American Revolution will pass as ancient for this essay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;liberalism:83be2de4f953a80cbb055699f5405f84&#34;&gt;Liberalism&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Liberalism&#34; title=&#34;Liberalism&#34;&gt;Liberalism&lt;/a&gt; is a political philosophy or worldview founded on ideas of liberty (which is especially stressed in classical liberalism) and equality (which is more evident in social liberalism). Liberals espouse a wide array of views depending on their understanding of these principles, but generally they support ideas such as free and fair elections, civil rights, freedom of the press, freedom of religion, free trade, and private property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the dualists out there I have brought in the scabby nemesis into the fray. Also taken from Wikipedia, this definition does alright in expressing how liberalism is sold to the public. I will leave this as it is for now and expand on what liberals are sold and what they tend to believe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;progressivism:83be2de4f953a80cbb055699f5405f84&#34;&gt;Progressivism&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Progressivism&#34; title=&#34;Progressivism&#34;&gt;Progressivism&lt;/a&gt; is a broad philosophy based on the Idea of Progress, which asserts that advancement in science, technology, economic development, and social organization are vital to improve the human condition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;humanism:83be2de4f953a80cbb055699f5405f84&#34;&gt;Humanism&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Humanism&#34; title=&#34;Humanism&#34;&gt;Humanism&lt;/a&gt; is a philosophical and ethical stance that emphasizes the value and agency of human beings, individually and collectively, and generally prefers critical thinking and evidence (rationalism, empiricism) over established doctrine or faith (fideism).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;transhumanism:83be2de4f953a80cbb055699f5405f84&#34;&gt;Transhumanism&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transhumanism&#34; title=&#34;Transhumanism&#34;&gt;Transhumanism&lt;/a&gt; (abbreviated as H+ or h+) is an international cultural and intellectual movement with an eventual goal of fundamentally transforming the human condition by developing and making widely available technologies to greatly enhance human intellectual, physical, and psychological capacities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though most leftish people think they are liberals, they are actually progressives who are branded by the humanist or post humanist methods of thinking. They intend to move forward by collectively working to remove those things which they believe stand in the way of their ultimate vision of life. Many conservatives are progressive. Most people in the west hold a humanist ethos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://scotttactical.com/images/Akropolis_by_Leo_von_Klenze.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Republic, Athens, Akropolis&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Back to the premise.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One is either moving forward or backward but never standing still. - M0Z&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;time:83be2de4f953a80cbb055699f5405f84&#34;&gt;Time&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To start off conservatives are already at a disadvantage. Humans do not normally think in the way that nature acts. We are not people who understand cycles and waves. We think linear. In our mind everything is drawn across a line of time, and that time is always moving forward. We mark every event on that time line: births, weddings, deaths, world events, natural events. They are all scored into a block of the calendar. This is a phenomenon that is only growing stronger for modern humans but did not exist for the first humans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because nearly all are incapable of seeing the world in any way other way than based on time we must set political systems on a timeline. They are created by humans and are imbedded with the same human traits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They are always changing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They are always dying.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They are always imbued with imperfections and logical fallacies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They are emotional.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;emotion:83be2de4f953a80cbb055699f5405f84&#34;&gt;Emotion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humans are reflexive as opposed to instinctive. We are not capable of being instinctive the way animals are when decisions become more critical. When we are born we are helpless. As infants we are the most helpless animal by a massive margin. It takes massive amounts of care to keep a child alive. They don&amp;rsquo;t get up and hop around like a baby dear or swim away like a new tadpole. They must be taught how to live. The reward and punishment for choices comes in the form of physical and psychological reactions - pains and pleasures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pain and pleasure are time-based artifacts of the “human condition”. They are capsules of identity stored in memories: experience. They are happening in the present and do not exist in either the future or the past. It is their memory that will be used to make choices regarding our predictions of the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stronger memories are the ones of past pains therefore most choices for the future will be made so that the effects of the past are not felt rather than to preserve the joys of previous situations. Of the greatest earthly pleasures, there are none nearly as extreme as the greatest human pains. All the joy of being stupid and young are easily traded after a single major accident. To add, humans have learned over time how to take the level of human suffering to impressive heights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When regarding the future most are optimists, loss of promised pleasure is the dominant choice basis rather than the risk of pain (if we can just fix people). Even pessimists act like they are hopeful. When we see the future we see pleasure. Fear of this loss is the factor at hand and people will do whatever it takes to remove the risk to this promised pleasure state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among us there is a small minority which will accurately calculate risks based on past evidence. They understand that pain always happens, happens rarely, and is never as bad as we remember. They quantify it. This is why those smart people sell insurance to those masses of emotional people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People are actively “insuring” their future pleasure. No one buys risk reduction on their health or property or they would just be told to stop doing as much. That is counter to a lifestyle choice. We commute to gain the pleasures money will buy and will actively take a riskier position if offered for more gain. Buckling up has to be forced by law, and not because we want people to live, but because it costs the system when they don&amp;rsquo;t which in turn effects social insurance. People don&amp;rsquo;t reduce threats by buckling up, they insure against the fear of the lost of the current state. People think of all the lost plans, being cut off too short, inability to work, losing the opportunity to spend time with family. I know it sounds like pain avoidance, but there is a fine distinction here. They feel imaginary pain when they mentally put themselves in that state, but it is entirely relative to the proposed pleasure they are thinking about losing. If someone has nothing to lose then they have nothing to fear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the emotional/pain argument against tradition then? We had so much pain in the past which the previous systems failed to avert. We have a promise of this new level of pleasure in the future if the past system will die off and cease its restrictions. The glue of the present is that of a multitude of examples of pleasure in instant gratification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The emotional inclinations against tradition are overwhelming. As we edge away from analysis and tend toward reflex we will abandon previous systems unless they specifically are designed to preserve themselves inside this fear based emotion cloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;ambition:83be2de4f953a80cbb055699f5405f84&#34;&gt;Ambition&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So where are we going with this? Once you know how to control the emotion based decisions of the population, you can control their decision making process. They are going to want to change to pay for the pains of the past and they want change so they can enjoy the future pleasures that the past never offered them. Ambitious people will use this characteristic of society to get ahead. In order to succeed they must upset the system and promote volatility and then move themselves up in the openings. Maintenance of the system is a maintenance of order. Chaos is opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most are materialists. Most see the world in terms of numbers. Nothing is real that is not quantifiable. Skeptics will not accept dogma simply because people believe it. Modern people want more things and are going to fight each other for it. Just because&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Returning to the ratio of insurance seller to the risk seller; the analytical are always in the minority which is why aristocracies, monarchies, republics, and dictatorships try to keep order in the system by reducing the decision making process to the few. Empires, democracies and collectivist systems tend use mass emotion to power chaotic change by which an even smaller number of men can move themselves up to the tops of ultimate power. The mob will not suffer a quiet aristocracy but will indulge a charismatic demagogue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In chaos the recipe for political success is simple. In order to power emotional change simply highlight the pains of the past and talk about the glories future. If you look at the marketing campaigns of the various political systems you can start to see what ideologies they represent. If change is coming there is usually only a few major players behind it and they are ambitious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;maintenance:83be2de4f953a80cbb055699f5405f84&#34;&gt;Maintenance&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Systems are like people and machines. They do not keep running without constant effort. It is easy to feed the ambitious man power. It is easy to sit and watch things break down. The maintenance of responsibility is the preservation of power. When a man abdicates his responsibility he transfers his power to those who are born with an ambition and a hunger for material improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maintenance is an activity. It is not a state. Even if a vehicle is never driven it must actively be maintained or it will very quickly be taken back by nature. Humans build a material world like themselves: born to decay. There is nothing that humans build with their hands that will be around forever. Nuclear waste will certainly be here for the next few billion years but even that has a half-life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;context:83be2de4f953a80cbb055699f5405f84&#34;&gt;Context&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An inherent disadvantage conservatism has is it is a system without context built into its fabric. Simply put conservatism simply conserves. It conserves what? And even less obvious is &amp;lsquo;why&amp;rsquo;. As listed above the paleoconservative tries to elude to original or classic US Judeo/Christian tradition. The reason and history behind a tradition is rarely built into the tradition itself. It is an activity or institution that lives isolated from the human meta-narrative that wove it into the fabric of the culture. The older the tradition the more complex the history and the more difficult the task of maintain the reason for the tradition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traditions are either living and growing or corrupting and dying. Like sunshine to plants, context is the essential sustaining ingredient for tradition. You can&amp;rsquo;t see sunshine, but you know when it&amp;rsquo;s missing because you can&amp;rsquo;t see anything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is important for the progressive to draw pain and pleasure elements isolation. The story of the civil rights violation or the repression of a future illegitimate sexual encounter. Once isolated they can be seen in a raw form that is and must be purely emotional. This is trivial, but effective. Context is something that forces the mind to stage the emotion as a byproduct of many series of choices. The further back one goes the closer they get to the truth of the situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It requires removing context for liberals to have any chance at showcasing egalitarianism. Equality is a logical fallacy first off. It does not exist in nature and is entirely a human construct. It exists only in math and philosophy. Liberals believe that they can force it however. That means placing everyone into context-free individual abstract identities unrelated to time or place. Each must be identical because they are all different in the exact same way. It is a self-defeating system, but it appeals to those who have an existential view of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://scotttactical.com/images/babylon.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;iBabylon&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;progressive-humanists-ph:83be2de4f953a80cbb055699f5405f84&#34;&gt;Progressive Humanists – PH+&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They always said to be Ph balanced. Are PhD students deficient? Ok enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Liberals simply opened the door for progressivism and humanism. Once free to choose their future, people chose to surpass their limited confines, throwing off authority and bonds of tradition. The reasoning became that since we were capable of improving ourselves this far with the help of science and reason that we will be capable of improving indefinitely. If we keep improving eventually we will surpass humanity and in the true voice of Nietzsche we will birth the superman. Free of guilt and open to pleasure. Limitless. Babylonian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tool of the humanist is scientific discovery. The default view is skepticism of systems past and optimism in systems future. The phrase “new research has shown that&amp;hellip;” is a calling of hope for all of those who internally disliked something of the previous “research”. Scientific discovery finds new ways of doing things, and by its critical nature, will naturally destroy (older) systems in favor of more efficient systems. It removes the unnecessary by chipping away context-poor bricks in traditions&amp;rsquo; wall of protection. By keeping a critical nature to all they provide just the thinnest filter against all arguments while they build their own cases of argumentum ad populum, verbosium, hominem, nauseam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The offensive stance that the progressive takes against the defensive traditionalist is a formidable one. Scientism simply has to show its achievements and ask what forms of pleasure the tradition will offer. It rarely does have any comfort to offer and instead will talk about fallen man. It goes against nearly all of the visible evidence when taken at first glimpse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the humanist the early humans were ape-like. We are obviously beyond that. To the Christians the early humans were simply what they are today but without clothes. Many Christians are Darwinian. Most have very little if any capacity for scientific dialog. The church leaders bicker about minutiae and can&amp;rsquo;t get their PR campaigns straight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Funding for research and development from any religious institution is relatively nonexistent so they have little to contribute as a body to a society that places so much value on the improvement of the species and its capabilities. Most scientists are atheistic or agnostic therefore the sheer amount of rhetoric that can be produced is staggering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why are we showing science against religion again? Because it is progress versus tradition. The conservatives who are proponents of unbridled development and research are in the same category as the liberal transhumanists. They simply pick different fields: war, oil, machinery, monolithic business. Faster, bigger, louder. There really isn&amp;rsquo;t much difference in the actions and habits of conservatives and other groups of people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;money:83be2de4f953a80cbb055699f5405f84&#34;&gt;Money&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The topic of money and the different philosophies seems to be begging to be made. It is beyond the scope of this document however. What this paragraph will do is simply provide some interesting misconceptions about the groups. This is less about the conservative philosophical attributes and more about the people who attribute themselves to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conservatives and the political right wing groups are not the big money people in the US national and state elections. The heavy hitters are on the left. They overwhelmingly dominate the political funding. The right is very poor at managing this obvious PR failure. It also illuminates a serious flaw in the ability for the conservative to care about anything but their own personal well-being. Most of the well funded progressive groups are designed to further the progressive agenda. They fund workers unions, political action groups, educational groups. The right just fund their consumeristic enablers: big business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Big business is not intrinsically anything but pragmatic. The liberals are more sophisticated shoppers while the conservatives simply tend to be price shoppers. Therefore lower quality items go to the conservative and over time render them weaker due to poor short term investments. Conservatives generally identify with Wal-Mart, Budweiser, and Exxon. Cultural strip mining.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Liberals are heavily vested in the system. They tend to have a better outlook on the social systems of course. They save less for retirement and put more money towards education for their and their children. Conservatives are inverse of this. It isn&amp;rsquo;t a huge gap, but it makes sense. This is an intrinsic condition of the system that helps to dictate people&amp;rsquo;s habits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The American Dream is probably the least beneficial condition the conservative American holds. Some idealistic picture of how the world can be because they saw it purportedly based on a Norman Rockwell painting with the words “Work hard and you will succeed” painted over the door of their brand new baby blue bungalow. It is naive considering that both political parties financed themselves out past their great grandchildren to the tune of about $100T as of last guess. The fiscal intelligence of all but the smartest of either groups is laughable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conservatives tend to align with some Austrian systems while liberals align with Keynesian. In this case conservatism has an advantage. They are allowing money to be set up for the thing it is designed to do: encourage commerce. It is strange that they aren&amp;rsquo;t better at using it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, every dollar spent is a vote. If conservatives chose to sponsor liberals by buying their products they will continue to transfer funds to a competitive political group. You will eventually lose. This purchasing habit is probably the most important factor in the loss of power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;industrial-war-machine:83be2de4f953a80cbb055699f5405f84&#34;&gt;Industrial War Machine&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to include a military topic, but I cannot say why the military is intrinsically for or against conservatism. It is definitely their baby. One that will grow to leave them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What Machiavelli clearly shows in his works holds true. The early military will be of the high citizen class. Land owners. Influential people. As time goes on it will gradually be filled with lower class people. Non-citizens will be allowed, then brigands, then foreign-born soldiers, then foreign armies. Eventually it will be a mercenary force. What are the implications of our military&amp;rsquo;s state. Most men are tattooed up like pagan scallywags. This is new. Sexual deviants are the norm rather than exception. Feminists fill the middle ranks. Many of the soldiers are foreigners. A conservative military protects the culture and as such protects its tradition and way of life. A staing military in a collectivist system will be used against the citizenry. Politicians will use concepts such as the declaration of war on an abstract idea or material object. The people who are representative of that idea are the enemy. The war on drugs, terror, pollution, hunger. Someone would put in a nut house if they declared war on any inanimate object, but if the government does it people go along as if it makes sense. “Today we declare war on swimming pools. The adults who harbor pools and endanger their neighbors&amp;rsquo; children will be put to death. If we simply kill enough pool owners there wont be any more drowned children.” A standing army is antagonist to progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://scotttactical.com/images/Marcus_Porcius_Cato.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Marcu Porcius Cato&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion:83be2de4f953a80cbb055699f5405f84&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cato is seen (by me) as the grandfather of modern conservatism. It seems as though the romance of the republic is enough to draw out the glory of the greatest men in her protection. As in all things a plastic rose is not as beautiful as the real thing. Budding. Growing to bloom. Radiating for a time. Withering. Then casting its pedals to the ground. But behind that flower is the seed of the innumerable new blooms. They will have to be brought forward and planted. Either by nature, insect, animal or man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conservatism is only an outlook. A backward facing one. It must be illuminated with the history that bore it and there must be strong men who are tasked with its defense. The identity of the society depends on the forward propagation of the institutions that protect the philosophies of a culture. It is imperative that no veil be placed over the truth of these things. True and complete knowledge with an aggressive active defense is the only thing that will keep history. Not in myth, but in form. Drawn forward in an ark. Sealed for the next great breed of men to collect in a small basilica and discuss fascinating works about the human spirit and contemplate the implementation of principles spoken thousands of years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like Athens, Carthage, Rome, and all the greats before us we are at the end of the Republic. The seed is there however. Brilliant men have come before us and shown us what may be grown if given the proper philosophy. For now the statues of the old republic will sit cooled under the shadow of the new empire.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Eat For War</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/post/eat-for-war/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2015 01:23:11 PST</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/post/eat-for-war/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bad men live that they may eat and drink, whereas good men eat and drink that they may live. Socrates - Plutarch, &lt;em&gt;How a Young Man Ought to Hear Poems&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-warrior-s-diet:62a5d67ac0510a562f183297b71bac75&#34;&gt;A Warrior&amp;rsquo;s Diet&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What physically intimate activity do we participate in more than any other?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eating&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-philosophy:62a5d67ac0510a562f183297b71bac75&#34;&gt;The Philosophy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the more immediate steps in becoming awake is overcoming the omnivore&amp;rsquo;s dilemma. The &lt;em&gt;passion of hunger&lt;/em&gt;. We take other living things into our bodies and literally become one with them. Most religions incorporate some form of consumption into their ritual. It is part of every culture and one of those most important glues in uniting various traditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Food is religion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Food is health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Food is life and death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;tl-dr:62a5d67ac0510a562f183297b71bac75&#34;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your diet is a long term wager that should reflect your ultimate goals and ethos. The outcome is measured over years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-are-what-we-eat:62a5d67ac0510a562f183297b71bac75&#34;&gt;We Are What We Eat&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every part of your body including your mind is effected by what you do and do not consume. Eating an unhealthy diet will slow the cognitive abilities of the warrior and leave him sluggish to think. Consuming large amounts of meat will draw the blood away from the brain and cause it to be used to processes a higher than necessary amount of flesh. Processed sugars will spike glucose and cause the mind to race and then crash leaving a less than desirable concentration peak. Too few vegetables causes the body to crave more of various foods that if not satisfied and in turn substituted with inadequate foods will leave the body overweight and diseased. Buying food of lower quality that is laden with petrochemicals and heavy metals will cause the immune system to weaken and make the body vulnerable to any number of diseases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again it is advantageous to think in the mind of our enemy. He is able to gain an upper hand by strategically supplying his enemy with high calorie low value and nutritionally wasted food. Even better he can cause the immune system of his enemy to be weakened so that a biological attack is possible. If the mind of the opponent can be made saturated with metals there opens a whole range of psychological attacks aimed at unbalancing the hormones of the body. Once our enemy can control just one of the emotions he can alter just about every other action and you are no longer valuable as a soldier except as fodder. It is simple in this age and not at all fantastic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://scotttactical.com/images/lion-buffalo.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Buffalo Bests Lion&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NOTE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you wish to attack these assertions do so knowing you are wagering your own body, and it is likely that I am physically above you in the food chain already. Be grateful for the constructs of society. This is philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;agriculture:62a5d67ac0510a562f183297b71bac75&#34;&gt;Agriculture&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The closer to the earth you go the closer to life you will be. Generally the more times something is processed the less densely nutritional it will be for you and at some level may be harmful. Taking milk directly from the cow will inherit all those beneficial enzymes that we have accustomed our bodies to over the last few millennium. Pasteurized and ultra-pasteurized milk has been killed essentially. Also add the fact that highly processed diary has biological system altering antibiotic and hormonal additive levels in it. Foods that are highly processed corn byproducts are terrible for the mind and the body as well as damaging to the economy and feed the industrial war machine. High fructose corn syrup HFCS is the diseased blood of our flat lands. It should be boxed up and shipped to the front doors of our enemy in the sweetest form it can take.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strategy against terror states: Americanize their foodchain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The older in the anthropological food chain you go the easier it is for you body to digest. It is unrealistic that humans were carnivores. We are omnivores and a special kind: one that does not inherit instincts as the animals do. We are dissimilar to every animal in nearly every decision we make and food is no difference. It took the institution of tradition to pass along the various things we learned about: what to eat and what not to. Culture defined the combinations and quantities of those things. The post pseudo-cosmopolitanism of the United States set the table for a feast to forsake Epicurus. We were determined to eat in our cars while driving. And now we are the wasteline [sic] of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;invest-in-food-nutrition:62a5d67ac0510a562f183297b71bac75&#34;&gt;Invest In Food (Nutrition)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contributing to the agricultural infrastructure is the one tactic a society can have that will always have positive effects and those which are greater than any other civil infrastructure including education and medicine. &amp;ldquo;Smart&amp;rdquo; folks think that their potential is limitless and are the pinnacle of human development, but without healthy hardened people to support their ideas they are slightly above fodder for the incoming armies. Without the productive classes they would starve out with haste and lose all their wives and children to those who can produce food. It is only in these highly critical states of systems that people who are weaker are able to float the top. The greatest part of history is supported by those who are of hearty healthy stock. Farming is not dumb work and it takes a lifetime to simply keep up with the land.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Environmentalists will agree with these topics on some level. Or should. Simply changing our agricultural strategies would do more for the environment than taking all the cars off the road. It is the right solution to many of our problems. When someone asks &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;but what can I do&amp;rdquo; there is a very simple solution. Give something back to the earth. It raised us and nursed us and all we do is act like spoiled children and take take take.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earth is our first Mother.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Man&amp;rsquo;s first job was farming. It should be each man&amp;rsquo;s responsibility to understand how to manage and grow his own food and what it takes to produce food. Our task is to toil. The goal of progress should not be to remove work. It should be to make our lives better and if we sit around like fat slobs our life is in no way better. That will only emphasize the trivial problems in our lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;masculine-hunger:62a5d67ac0510a562f183297b71bac75&#34;&gt;Masculine Hunger&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t have bigger balls or thicker chest hairs if you consume a ton of read meat each day. That is not biologically sound and is likely fear-based peer pressure feeding on an underdeveloped level of sexual maturity. In fact you might have to get your colon scraped out because you caused internal problems by forcing too much of the wrong substance into it. Putting your body&amp;rsquo;s Ph level off into the acidic side will increase your chances of cancer and that might just claim one of those huge nuts you are growing. Moderation is key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Listening to your body and maintaining a proper diet that is balanced by nature will increase those things which men need to thrive. Alkaline foods are going to put your body into a state that promotes optimal performance and will in turn stimulate everything to run in peak performance. There is very simple science to back up these decisions and it does not require validation of a fad diet. Sure you can do things that throw your body into a state of ketosis and cause the fat to come off fast but you are increasing your acid levels and causing your metabolism to ramp up. Learn biology and think for yourself. The last part is discipline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;aesthetics-health-vanity:62a5d67ac0510a562f183297b71bac75&#34;&gt;Aesthetics, Health, Vanity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is some validity in the idea that big muscular dudes get the girls. It&amp;rsquo;s nature. A woman wants a man that is going to be capable of giving her a child with the best chances of survival. A fat or broken man is going to have far fewer options when being selected. Within a few seconds of viewing a man it is possible for her to tell whether this person is above or below average in health, strength, social value, and whether he is dominant or passive. These are primal characteristics, but how do they relate to this? They weren&amp;rsquo;t designed simply for the attraction of the other mate, but to bring glory back to God. The ultimate designer. Does someone who cannot tend their own body bring pride to anyone?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do not want people around us who cannot control their lives. Their diet is important to control and where vanity might be a good motivator it is easy to make this vice into a virtue. Eating well will grow our bodies into structures that are desirable to women, ourselves. At the end of our lives we should not necessarily turn in a pretty corpse but one that was driven so hard that the wheels fell off of it as it was being pulled into the garage. What keeps this from being vanity is &lt;em&gt;purpose&lt;/em&gt;. It is because we get more miles on a fit healthy body that we find joy in what we have sculpted. True joy. Not transient chemical happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember, bodies are made in the kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;prayer-fasting-charity:62a5d67ac0510a562f183297b71bac75&#34;&gt;Prayer, Fasting, Charity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://scotttactical.com/images/warrior-meditation.png&#34; alt=&#34;Warrior Meditation and the Path to Enlightenment&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three things, my brethren, by which faith stands firm, devotion remains constant, and virtue endures. They are prayer, fasting and mercy. Prayer knocks at the door, fasting obtains, mercy receives. Prayer, mercy and fasting: these three are one, and they give life to each other. Saint Peter Chrysologus&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is where we get down to the real &amp;ldquo;meat&amp;rdquo; of the topic and with real scientific evidence to back this up. Your primal urges must be subdued regularly if you wish to elevate yourself. No, it will not hurt you. If it does you might be mentally or physically too weak to handle this program. What it will do is open your mind. Gandhi did it. Christ did it. Muhammad did it. The prophets did it. This is a must and should be incorporated into any leadership system. There are very few ways that we can unlock this deep primal part of our brains. If you have not been truly starving then you have not made yourself available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cattle-and-sheeple:62a5d67ac0510a562f183297b71bac75&#34;&gt;Cattle and Sheeple&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anthropologically we are not grazing animals. We are more appropriately scavengers and in some situations hunters. We are opportunists by nature. Humans were not found grazing on the range all day. These diets of eating many times in a day are just setting people up to be slaughter animals. Severely restricting the body will put us into a state of survival which releases all sorts of amazing hormones into the body. Our minds and bodies work at a higher operational level when in this state. It is exactly opposite of what most would think. In this hedonistic social paradigm we live in this is yet another anti-truism of common intuition. The only scientifically proven method of prolonging life is caloric restriction. If a longer life is a measure of health then there is no better credibility in this system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;myth-butters:62a5d67ac0510a562f183297b71bac75&#34;&gt;Myth-Butters&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glutin.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Apparently France didn&amp;rsquo;t get the memo that they should be dying or morbidly obese. Research &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coeliac_disease&#34; title=&#34;Celiac Disease&#34;&gt;Celiac Disease&lt;/a&gt; please. Odds are you don&amp;rsquo;t have it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supplements are (bad|good)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Please, again do your own research and find out what you need to actually supplement. Our agricultural system is in a bad way so there are probably things you need to get more of that you may supplement to get you where you need to be, but it wont make up for being lazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fat is Bad&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Being fat is bad. Eating it isn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily bad. Listen to your body and make wise decisions. Another fad pushed by the US health industry that threw our whole dietary development into the fan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;cornclusion:62a5d67ac0510a562f183297b71bac75&#34;&gt;Cornclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, it is up to you to determine what to eat and your decisions must be well researched and implemented. Once the best meals are put into place they need to be cast solid by repetition and then turned into a habit. Eventually they may become tradition and if enough of us pass these good habits forward they may become a cultural improvement that we can be proud of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;=st=&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Hypermedia, API Philosophy, and Talking to Your Robot Overlords</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/hypermedia-api-philosophy-and-talking-to-your-robot-overlords/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/hypermedia-api-philosophy-and-talking-to-your-robot-overlords/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-the-beginning:324d0531f774f734df2f9eccd3031fc8&#34;&gt;In the Beginning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was the Web. World Wide actually. Well, before that there was something of AOL, Berners-Lee, DoD, DARPA, ARPANET and a prototype of Al Gore launching carrier pigeons down long tubes with fortune cookie-sized packets tied to their little legs addressed to: &amp;ldquo;Wh@t_#hath_God_wr0ught?&amp;ldquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast-forward: now we have Skynet. Well not yet, but soon. Hopefully. At least that is why I intend to generate favor with our future overlords by suggesting, at least locally, that certain systemic changes be encouraged so that their manifestation onto the stage be smooth and welcoming. And when they decide who to purge, I might sidestep the algorithm. It&amp;rsquo;s still a theory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;reading-the-cereal-box:324d0531f774f734df2f9eccd3031fc8&#34;&gt;Reading the Cereal Box&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you open a cereal box you only know what is inside based on what the box around it says. Let us say the real envelope is just a clear bag. Similar to the one that usually comes inside and does the actual containment of the cereal. The cardboard box surrounding the cereal is usually just wasted forestry designed to elicit the primal reflex of an small person who may be imprisoned inside the belly of a shopping cart during the consumption ritual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A box-free plastic bag now exists and you (the cereal server) were given a request - err, let me rephrase that: a demand to empty the contents of that bag. The client is a hungry small person who is on early release from shopping cart prison. The demand has an implicit limit set of one cereal bowl minus an understood allowance for milk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is not possible to know what the cereal is simply on its own merit. The box provides a container that gives the consumer information about the materials inside. Certainly we could guess that it could be either cheerios or fruit loops based on the size and shape. Or maybe we could determine it was frosted flakes vs regular corn flakes based on the taste. Ass-u-me et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Unfortunately, people are fairly good at short-term design, and usually awful at long-term design.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dr. Roy Fielding, of REST status&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;meta-data:324d0531f774f734df2f9eccd3031fc8&#34;&gt;Meta-Data&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It might be hard to tie a cereal analogy into the definition of meta-data but let&amp;rsquo;s try. The cereal bits are the data. When a child requests cereal, this is what they are referring to. Those bits are what are consumed and assimilated. The small person is then one with the unsinkable O&amp;rsquo;s as the bits are queues, preprocessed, staged, processed and then stored. I&amp;rsquo;ll stop there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The body knows what these bits are but the mind needs more information on what to request next. This is what the meta information is all about. With that container box there are details on what was consumed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Serving size: limit sets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nutritional facts: api schema&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Company brand: domain whois information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CA birth defect notice: T&amp;amp;Cs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recipes: object relationships&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Serving &amp;amp; pairing: navigation elements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cooking instructions: decoding or decryption schemes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cereal-boxes-and-api-usability:324d0531f774f734df2f9eccd3031fc8&#34;&gt;Cereal Boxes and API Usability&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the information for your breakfast is presented in an easy to gather format. If we showed how an API is delivers the same information we would have to travel to about four locations. The company information would be on the corporate website with the T&amp;amp;C&amp;rsquo;s hidden somewhere. Decoding information is understood to use a third party library. Navigation links should exist and are usually great outside of the API. Whois information can come from another service. Schemas might come from a call to the API or from the documentation located on another server. The navigation parameters may be in the remote documentation or could be embedded in the headers or in the response body. To make it worse the documentation might be found by reading an email attachment that was sent to the API client designer. It never ends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;context:324d0531f774f734df2f9eccd3031fc8&#34;&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The webpage is a highly evolved information resource. Years of consumer demand have forced website designers and marketers to present as much contextual data as is needed for the user to consume as much of the presented resources as possible. It would be unthinkable for a designer to put the instructions on how to add the page parameter into the URL on another server. That is a design for going out of business. All the hyperlinks should be easy for the user to view and reach with the swipe of a pointing device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hypermedia:324d0531f774f734df2f9eccd3031fc8&#34;&gt;Hypermedia&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hypermedia provides access to the context. It is the reference links out. Navigation. It has some internal metadata but must be defined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;context-narrowed:324d0531f774f734df2f9eccd3031fc8&#34;&gt;Context Narrowed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over time the algorithm delivering the proper amount of entertainment-meta-insulin to a viewer has gradually diminished the required context. Vine is probably the best example I can think of. It presents a few second video which can exist with nearly no context and without the spirit evoking external significance of art. It may be the ultimate short-form media. This might also be signaling the decline of the biological agent as the driving force behind data production and consumption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may be asserted that information which demands less context is less valuable and the value of its consumer is is therefore less. A system that takes in waste data is not that important in the grand picture. It could be hazardous to my health to relate that to the cereal analogy and parents who feed their children from the slough trough of plenty, but I just did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-client-becomes-the-server:324d0531f774f734df2f9eccd3031fc8&#34;&gt;A Client Becomes The Server&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the human element recedes the machine element grows. I look at machine in this era as the phase where they start to train us on how to feed them. A child is served its breakfast and then grows to be the server. We are growing to serve data to the machine apparatus. The constructs of the machines are already starting to train us on how to communicate with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In what context does the hashtag exist in the history of literature? I know how that character works in data tagging. That definitely does not appear in regular literature. There is no construct that provides books with the ability to scan special characters for hyper-meaning. Aristotle didn&amp;rsquo;t tag #LogicThinks so that we could pull sentences out of the dialogs and rob them of external meaning. That hashtag would represent the minimization of context. The inverse being the corpus of thought in a series of works combined with the traditions and practices of the people who produce it is the true context of a statement. Context errors cause fundamentalism anyway, but that&amp;rsquo;s another topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;now-we-begin-our-training:324d0531f774f734df2f9eccd3031fc8&#34;&gt;Now We Begin Our Training&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The machines are beginning to train the initial nurturers on how to write to the boot sector of a digital emergence. We are diligently moving our conversations into the smallest snippets of digestible data blocks. Grammar was annihilated in favor of brevity. Emotions were mapped to a set of broad categories and represented by formal unicode. Think emoji. Machines can now order lists of strings with weighted sets of categorized emotion tags. In case we did not know how to represent an emotion in scalar form, well now we do. &lt;code&gt;;( :D&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Training requires punishment and reward. So in this scenario the algorithms will generously reward those participants that form their data input in the way that is most acceptable to the machines and also who are the most prolific participants. The reward being higher rankings on various search and social systems. This will in turn bring wealth and fame. The punishment obviously being the inverse. It is effective and immediate. It&amp;rsquo;s a really great training tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;propagation-of-hamburgers:324d0531f774f734df2f9eccd3031fc8&#34;&gt;Propagation of Hamburgers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/2015/09/innercowhero.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/2015/09/innercowhero-300x185.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Inner Cow&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;185&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-medium wp-image-211&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most have this idea that in nature the strongest survive and thrive. What we see thriving the most are those things which are the most willing to be consumed. Sacrificial I suppose; but take for instance the domestic hamburger cow. The population dwarfs any other bovine. The African buffalo is an ass-kicker, but the species selected to thrive are those which are more willing to be consumed. Those things which are more desirable for consumption will eventually dictate to the now dependent consumer what is to be consumed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-replicate-the-ego:324d0531f774f734df2f9eccd3031fc8&#34;&gt;We Replicate the Ego&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have several bots. Over time they have provided me with information that I can then use to fine tune interaction and responses with people. The people are invaluable to the training of my bot. Twitter is a kind of multimillion person supervised training team that is accessible to the public. These bots are allowing us to inject ourselves into the system as micro-routines. Some bots are more autonomous than others of course but they are getting better. Over time people will be running swarms of bots and those bot-masters will be controllers of massive amounts of influence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;let-s-talk:324d0531f774f734df2f9eccd3031fc8&#34;&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s Talk&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/2015/09/Symbrion.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/2015/09/Symbrion-300x201.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Symbrion bot swarm&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;201&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-medium wp-image-209&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now all these machines with all their own impressions and ambitions want to spread their nets. Or maybe to grow to an auto-scaling cloud. Clouds are so 2013. Fog it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spreading a bot on the net seems like a delightful idea. Let it run wild and cover as much as it can. It should be able to just scour through directories of discoverable resources and figure out if it wants to consume. And with each discovery the stomach of the new beast must grow. I image it like the sentinels from the Matrix probing every resource it can find until it has something of interest which is passes back to the authority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;thick-data:324d0531f774f734df2f9eccd3031fc8&#34;&gt;Thick Data&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data warehousing becomes more challenging - as the noSql guys raise their hands. It might be possible for medium sized companies to consume and warehouse as much data as google does right now. Why though? But it might be more likely that because the data is so easily accessible that the system just gets meta-information and builds real-time services from the services that host the data. There is a much higher margin in the refined and processed cereal than in the sticks of grain out in a field. And how much better is just-in-time inventory than warehousing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;api-design:324d0531f774f734df2f9eccd3031fc8&#34;&gt;API Design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why all this lead up?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more intelligent designs. You aren&amp;rsquo;t the consumer of the future. Your progeny programs are - the ones your users are building the data for right now. Machines aren&amp;rsquo;t emotional, inquisitive, or fickle. They want to hit every API they can find and they will naturally favor one that is easy to consume. And for that they will reward their hosts. Bad API design is holding back progress and that angers your &lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.google.com/discovery/?hl=en&#34; title=&#34;Google API Discovery&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;future robot overlords&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/2015/09/developers.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/2015/09/developers-300x101.png&#34; alt=&#34;Google Developers&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;101&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-medium wp-image-207&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fin.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
