<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scott Tactical </title>
    <link>http://scotttactical.com/post/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Scott Tactical</author>
    <rights>(C) 2016</rights>
    <updated>2016-11-18 20:00:32 -0800 PST</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>What is Wrong With Millennials</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/whats-wrong-with-millennials</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 20:00:32 PST</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/whats-wrong-with-millennials</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-up-with-those-millennials:ea08a493ab3fcc736e98113c19c46ccc&#34;&gt;What is Up With Those Millennials?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ah, yes. The click bait. A marketing construct of the GenX&amp;rsquo;ers: pornographic gossip without the payoff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, since you are here&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-motivation-agism:ea08a493ab3fcc736e98113c19c46ccc&#34;&gt;My Motivation: Agism&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have become infuriated seeing one segment of United States citizenry be the target of a multiple-party attack.  This pressure has been escalating over the last couple of years, and I wanted to make a number of assertions and lay out some warnings.  The warning comes at the end if you can make it that far. I know how your attention span is now days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-generational-breakdown:ea08a493ab3fcc736e98113c19c46ccc&#34;&gt;A Generational Breakdown&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First I would like to place the generational groups into segments and then apply some analysis. Then I would like to graph some of these attack vectors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;america-s-living-generations:ea08a493ab3fcc736e98113c19c46ccc&#34;&gt;America&amp;rsquo;s Living Generations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have taken a few of the date ranges proposed by various sources and attempted to line them up close to the consensus.  I have also tried to list a couple of major events to provide context to the date ranges.  These events are not attributed to the group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Groups&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Name: &lt;strong&gt;GI Generation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Birth Range: 1901-1924&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Significant Events: The Great War, Flight, Women&amp;rsquo;s Sufferage&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Name: &lt;strong&gt;Silent or Greatest Generation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Birth Range: 1925-1945&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Significant: Events: Great Depression, WWII, Television, New Deal&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Name: &lt;strong&gt;Baby Boomers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Birth Range: 1946-1964&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Significant Events: Civil Rights, Korean War, Space Race, Missile Crisis, The Pill&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Name: &lt;strong&gt;Generation X&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Birth Range: 1965-1979&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Significant Events: Vietnam Conflict, Moon Landing, Sexual Revolution&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Name: &lt;strong&gt;Millennials&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Birth Range: 1980-2000&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Significant Events: Cold War, Desert Wars, Latin American Wars, Birth of the Internet&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Name: &lt;strong&gt;Centennials&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Birth Range: 2000+&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Significant Event: Endless War, Great Recession, Information Age&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;so-who-is-the-best:ea08a493ab3fcc736e98113c19c46ccc&#34;&gt;So, Who Is The Best?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because I have been questioned on why millennials are &amp;ldquo;the worst&amp;rdquo;, I would like to know who is the best. Obviously, the &amp;ldquo;greatest&amp;rdquo; generation is the one I hear elevated most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me assert that the cause and effect of historical events revolve around money and power.  The leverage behind financial transactions is not the capital but the debt.  Therefore the debt behind the events of each of the generations is critical to examining them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;buy-war-bonds-cpt-america:ea08a493ab3fcc736e98113c19c46ccc&#34;&gt;Buy War Bonds - Cpt. America&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who sponsored the great wars? If the &amp;ldquo;greatest&amp;rdquo; generation sponsored themselves out of the depression, how did they do that?  America was in a depression, so they war&amp;rsquo;ed themselves out. Admirably, the wealthy and the ordinary contributed a lot. A large percentage of the debt was owned by the citizens themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will not go into the unnecessary use of nuclear weapons, or that Americans think we were the ones who defeated the Germans, or how unnecessary it was to wage war against socialism/communism/collectivism.   How about we illuminate the fact that the first thing this generation did when they returned was to implement the biggest socialist programs the United States will probably ever have.  Hypocrite lately?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As stated previously, debt powers this country, so let&amp;rsquo;s talk about the debt of the &amp;ldquo;greatest&amp;rdquo; folks. Certainly, they know how to manage debt, because they owned the debt to join WW2. Later however as they were cashing in on the returns from an investment in the war they also assumed debt on a guaranteed lifestyle leveraged against the treasury.  Actually, it was guaranteed against future generations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;go-unfund-me:ea08a493ab3fcc736e98113c19c46ccc&#34;&gt;Go Unfund Me&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That revenue levied against our wages was immediately borrowed against.  The money was never there.  Hence, the &amp;ldquo;unfunded&amp;rdquo; part of the debt you didn&amp;rsquo;t know about.  The government promised that it would get paid back later (as long as there are enough people and revenue to cover it).  The buck has stopped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depending on what calculations you use, the revenue on that trust fund is underwater a little or a lot. If calculated out to when the Centennials will benefit from it then we are carrying around $25T in debt. That is trillion with a T.  So the scheme of the &amp;ldquo;greatest&amp;rdquo; was set to last just long enough for Generation X to not really get much out of it.  Clincher is: they knew it.  Don&amp;rsquo;t mind the many moments among old folks laughing about how long kids would have to live to get anything out of social security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;corn-oil:ea08a493ab3fcc736e98113c19c46ccc&#34;&gt;Corn Oil&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generation X grew up being driven to clockwork-regular vacations in giant cars with crushed velvet interiors and motors that made Arabs orgasm.  These kids were corn-fed; to be trite.  But they were more of an accessory to these things. Bothering their parents who were trying to relax on the vacation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get good grades so you can go to a good college, so you can get a good degree, so you can get a good job, so you can get a good wife, so you can get a house, so you can afford kids, so you can pay for their education, so they will leave home and you can retire to spend all your savings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I present to you the equation called American Dream as taught by our forebearers in the second chapter of the textbook titled: Purpose of Life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;marketing-for-the-masses:ea08a493ab3fcc736e98113c19c46ccc&#34;&gt;Marketing For The Masses&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Canned Spam or Hamburger Helper.  Walmart or Target. Post or Kellogs.  Nike or Adidas.  McDonald&amp;rsquo;s or Burger King, ABC or NBC, Ford or Chevy, Republican or Democrat,  mom&amp;rsquo;s weekend or dad&amp;rsquo;s weekend, paper or plastic, ribbed or smooth, bologna or hotdogs, Pepsi or Coke, capitalist or communist, mayo or Miracle Whip. Err, strike the penultimate option. Communism&amp;rsquo;s bad.  You aren&amp;rsquo;t allowed to pick that one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Boomers were the most susceptible audience in history.  They were all branded to the level of religious zealotry, and then stamped their kids.  Watch old commercials.  The spectral echo of them are things that make the alphabet soup litany of civil-rights group crawl out of their nocturnal graves. Now y&amp;rsquo;all some racist bastards, ain&amp;rsquo;tcha?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;latchkey-kids:ea08a493ab3fcc736e98113c19c46ccc&#34;&gt;Latchkey Kids&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These kids were detached. They were pushed to run on their own. Funding and attention shifted away from those things that propped up the youth and back towards the elderly.  Social Security and Medicare got a big bump during this time. It was already starting to show its stretch market. Besides, the previous generation knew how to vote and were organized.  Remember the debt we talked about already?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;moulin-rouge:ea08a493ab3fcc736e98113c19c46ccc&#34;&gt;Moulin Rouge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The consolation was the X&amp;rsquo;ers were the consummate sensualists.  They drug [sic] us into the world of sexual liberation.  They embraced Nietzsche with the full-frontal bro-hug, but not too close unless we want AIDs.  That&amp;rsquo;s god&amp;rsquo;s punishment for boys hugging too tightly. Or sexing up monkeys. One or the other.  Thank goodness for Sex Education clearing that up.  They were having a rough time figuring out how the Oscar Meyer fit into the Wunder Buns. And if they would use Heinz, Hellman&amp;rsquo;s, or Frenches yellow sauce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometime during the early 80&amp;rsquo;s, the television was quietly approved for semi-autonomous child supervision by various governmental  companies such as the MTV, HBO or PDA.  Games weren&amp;rsquo;t approved, though.  Theoretically, because anything other than near comatose participation in visual entertainment was taboo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;this-is-your-brains-on-tv:ea08a493ab3fcc736e98113c19c46ccc&#34;&gt;This Is Your Brains On TV&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drugs are bad m&amp;rsquo;kay? DARE you to take some. Unless they are pharmaceutical.  Because that is as natural as a skillet-fried sunny side up cranial self-buggery omelette.  Hold the cheese. Unless it&amp;rsquo;s Velveeta.  It melts smoother.  Like heroine for your colon.  Keeps the poo flow flowin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly though, Generation-X really brought the idea of communicating in memes of movie and TV quotations.  That was a great communication medium. Sure beats Emojis. Frying our minds with TV had a silver lining.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;it-is-good-to-have-options:ea08a493ab3fcc736e98113c19c46ccc&#34;&gt;It Is Good To Have Options&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All those choices and options weren&amp;rsquo;t&amp;hellip;  It was consolidation.  Freedom of thought was replaced with &amp;ldquo;options&amp;rdquo;.  That is the woman&amp;rsquo;s mind. The desire for safe options.  The illusion of risk. Now that the domestic spending radically shifted the marketing can be cleaned up and we can now have aisles of different breakfast cereals to choose from.  Although, they are actually all the same ingredients differing in degree and packaging from about two major corporations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spend Don&amp;rsquo;t Mend - Brave New World Jingle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;X&amp;rsquo;ers were the last age of men.  They went the way of the muscle car mustache. This was when women took over the country.  Millenials are an entire generation raised by women.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Show Me The Money! - Tom Cruise Missile&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would assert that all marketing exists in a void that is left by vice. For various reasons.  People want to be sold something, because they like being flattered, because they are looking to one-up the Joneses, because they are too stupid or lazy to do the research on their own, because they are bored, because they are programmed to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Say Hallo To My Leetle Friend - Scarf Face&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I suppose the X&amp;rsquo;ers wanted to do right by their kids. So they made their kids their buddies; and then abdicated what was left of any established parental hierarchy.  They chose to let children develop their own emotional identity that was free from the burden of wisdom.  The children&amp;rsquo;s identity or creativity were unlocked to roam free.  The emotional equivalent of setting up a sandbox in the center of a London roundabout and dropping them off.  It was Spartan.  It was intense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;famous-anus-chocolip-cookies:ea08a493ab3fcc736e98113c19c46ccc&#34;&gt;Famous Anus&amp;rsquo; Chocolip Cookies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a giant intercontinental ballistic slumber party.  All people are your best friends, and the State is the chaperone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please enjoy your safe spaces liberally.  The State has finally freed us up to truly enjoy each other in any way we want, and punish people who we don&amp;rsquo;t want enjoying us in any way we don&amp;rsquo;t want.  But if they do forcibly enjoy us then we can have them imprisoned where we collectively enjoy them being anally enjoyed by less-enjoyable fellows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it confusing don&amp;rsquo;t worry. It will take another generation to figure out how to manage the new social dynamics. It takes technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;trickle-down-syndrome:ea08a493ab3fcc736e98113c19c46ccc&#34;&gt;Trickle-Down-Syndrome&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In occlusion, the two voting generations, under Reagan, cut the brakes on the train. Because, ABS is for bitches.   It basically put nitrous into the hands of the wealthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greed Is God - Paraphrased from Martin Gecko Sheen Winning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The public debt started its parabolic ascent in the 80&amp;rsquo;s.  The GenX&amp;rsquo;ers learned how to vote.  How to leverage the last bit of debt onto the next generation.  Right here is where I suppose we are starting to see the cracks in the facade.   This is the period where the future was mortgaged.  The 80&amp;rsquo;s and 90&amp;rsquo;s is when these United States were sold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Cold War was always a shit story. While we were worried about socialism we were consuming ourselves to fiscal death.   Like a glutton eating so much that he grows too big to fit out his front door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;get-a-good-job:ea08a493ab3fcc736e98113c19c46ccc&#34;&gt;Get A Good Job&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember the American Dream equation. The X&amp;rsquo;ers still believed it.  Rightfully so. They saw it working in the 80&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was garbage too. Inflation is a taxation on savings.  We inflated ourselves out of the situation the 70&amp;rsquo;s left us with.  And it wrecked incomes ever since. Instead of trying to correct the problem the train sped forward. Women joined the workforce and families spent less time together.  Negative social capital must be repaid with future social interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even with the addition of women into the workforce, the household income didn&amp;rsquo;t keep pace with inflation. It has been pretty much flat since 1980.  The purchasing power of us today is about &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;/sub&gt; of what it was for people starting their careers in 1980 with a single income earner.  Do your own math.  Or better yet ask a Millenial to do it for you.  At least they won&amp;rsquo;t be as bias.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;planet-changers:ea08a493ab3fcc736e98113c19c46ccc&#34;&gt;Planet Changers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gen X&amp;rsquo;ers did give us the most powerful communication tool in history.  We have the Internet, and the planet has been changed. It is one of the greatest inventions. To elevate it more it was an organic collective innovation. That is something to be proud of.  And it is almost entirely because of the X&amp;rsquo;ers foundation and entrepreneurial spirit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;millenials:ea08a493ab3fcc736e98113c19c46ccc&#34;&gt;Millenials&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-best-educated-generation-in-history:ea08a493ab3fcc736e98113c19c46ccc&#34;&gt;The Best Educated Generation In History&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we have a socially independent, emotionally evolved, guilt-free, highly educated and bored sector of society.  Their math skills are quite adequate to understand the sheer absurdity in trying to implement American Dream equation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Millennials are well taken care of and know that they won&amp;rsquo;t be booted out like the X&amp;rsquo;ers were.  They have begun to sunset the consumerism of the Boomers and the sensualism of the X&amp;rsquo;ers.  They seem to be making rational choices.  A silent reflexive revolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of admitting fault and helping the upcoming generations the previous two are blaming them for not investing into this Ponzi scheme we call the economy, but they would never do it to their face, instead they go online and do it. Like they don&amp;rsquo;t have kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-10-ers:ea08a493ab3fcc736e98113c19c46ccc&#34;&gt;The 10%ers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point in US history I would like to assert we have 3 groups.  Not the haves and have-nots. Instead: Those who own debt, those who own capital, and those who own nothing.  If we combine those who own debt (1%ers), those who own capital (10%ers) and those who own nothing (the 89%ers) we get a much better diagram of the pyramid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;entitled-brats:ea08a493ab3fcc736e98113c19c46ccc&#34;&gt;Entitled Brats&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s talk briefly about entitlement. Considering that one sector of the society demands that the others support their debt interest, pay for their drugs, keep putting money into their infrastructure, and demand us to keep calm and drive on while they drain down the last of their pensions and retirements; that sounds pretty freakin entitled.  Maybe I don&amp;rsquo;t know what entitlement means.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;boomers-on-top:ea08a493ab3fcc736e98113c19c46ccc&#34;&gt;Boomers on Top&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now the Boomers control a disproportional amount of spending power. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to get into the math because it was mind numbing to deal with.  Maybe they earned it I don&amp;rsquo;t know. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;m way off base.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;X&amp;rsquo;ers want their day in the sun though. They want everyone else to buy into the system. Some of them took on student debt and want Millenials to.  They mortgaged their future buying cars and homes. They went all in.  Dammit if these snotty kids are going to ruin it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cleanex-diplomas:ea08a493ab3fcc736e98113c19c46ccc&#34;&gt;Cleanex Diplomas&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A diploma is trash. Mostly. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean much except to a diminishing few.  The schools that are great are only for the gifted minds or kids who won the life lottery.  Don&amp;rsquo;t fool yourself.  Even doctors will be replaced by artificial intelligence and lower paid technicians.  Technical or skill training is the only thing that matters now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You got knocked the fug-out! - Friday&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why put in the effort?  Wake the fuck up, homey.  The Dream is literally over.  Capitalism died in 2008. Communism was never a threat.  We are in an interconnected world now.  Robots will replace your jobs, not the Mexicans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-eq:ea08a493ab3fcc736e98113c19c46ccc&#34;&gt;The EQ&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the last hundred years, we have been inculcated that IQ is the king metric for human capacity.  I will assert that all history, all commerce, and all human events are a perception-based phenomenon.  Every transaction is a human transaction.  All power is human power. Power over and power through.  Money is fiat. Communication is the protocol to make everything happen. The measure of aptitude inside that ecosystem is the Emotional Quotient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Millenials were set on free-range mode by their parents and developed a new sense of communication.  Its purity is slowly being eroded by the Internet but this type of communication is global and rapidly evolving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get To The Time Machine Marty!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We now have a group of people with very little to lose and the ability to communicate in ways that we cannot understand, and not easily control.  To affirm this point, many psychological professionals have refused to acknowledge that there is this type of intelligence and that it should be measured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;war-makes-babies:ea08a493ab3fcc736e98113c19c46ccc&#34;&gt;War Makes Babies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This prepends my first warning.  Two smaller unorganized groups of people are picking on an intelligent network of mobilized collectives that are free of moral restrictions and generational biases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some idiots still believe that war is a good population reduction scheme. In fact, it causes population explosions.  A society or species determine internally if they want to reduce themselves.  Attack the younger generations and they will be hardened together. Citation: history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;math-is-king:ea08a493ab3fcc736e98113c19c46ccc&#34;&gt;Math is King&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is warning two.  If the Millennials and Centennials are forced into a meaningless life of materialistic servitude, they will look for answers. Given a highly evolved communication tool and a mathematically superior population, it is only waiting for a leader and a catalyst before some group learns how to extract all the wealth from the earlier generations with extreme prejudice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;centennial-war:ea08a493ab3fcc736e98113c19c46ccc&#34;&gt;Centennial War&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly, Millennials have known little but war.  Centennials know only war. An entire life of war.  Born into fear and only fear. This is our gift to them.  You only train them how to see risk. They are bubble wrapped from life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We live in the safest time in history, yet parents are running around scared of everything. Scared of disease, scared of terrorists, scared of drugs, scared of progress, scared of animals, scared of scraped knees, scared of losing their gods, scared of other people&amp;rsquo;s opinions, scared of their own opinions, scared of their children&amp;rsquo;s opinions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those who are willing to do violence will always subjugate those who are not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out of that environment you can easily spot the warriors, because everyone else is mush. Your children will pity you for being weak and resent you for making them weak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pay it Forward - A Movie (2000)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when you talk about generational contributions, how about you start paying it forward a little.  If you care about the future in the least, stop lying to yourself.  You didn&amp;rsquo;t do anything on your own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-word:ea08a493ab3fcc736e98113c19c46ccc&#34;&gt;A Word&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Centennials, stop fretting over grades. They don&amp;rsquo;t matter so much. Start studying what really matters. Read books older than your parents. Learn how the Internet works. Be involved in politics at a local level. Start a group.  Learn how to effectively use a firearm in the physical world.  Become dangerous to the system. Dismiss fear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-remediation:ea08a493ab3fcc736e98113c19c46ccc&#34;&gt;A Remediation&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try this.  Seriously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How about you shut your mouth and watch the youth.  Give them the opportunities you took.  Live simply.  Stop weaving in the ideas of greed, fear, envy, and scarcity into their lives.  Don&amp;rsquo;t make them fight your stupid fucking wars for you. Teach your children about life. Address the debt and admit your fault in it.  Show them what taking responsibility looks like. Don&amp;rsquo;t make them pay for your retirement.  Learn.  Learn to communicate.  Learn unceasing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn to love and love hard.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Writing Novels in Markdown Part 1</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/writing-novels-in-markdown-part1/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 16:35:37 PST</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/writing-novels-in-markdown-part1/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;writing-in-markdown:f66853f3398525872cad9091a5df51e1&#34;&gt;Writing in Markdown&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven&amp;rsquo;t used &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Markdown&#34;&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt; to write in a rich(er) text format, then you are missing out. I pretty much write all my technical documentation in Markdown. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty awesome and I don&amp;rsquo;t know why it took me so long to find it. I didn&amp;rsquo;t start using it until around 2013.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-markdown:f66853f3398525872cad9091a5df51e1&#34;&gt;What is Markdown&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Markdown was created by &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Gruber&#34;&gt;John Gruber&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Wikipedia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Gruber created the &lt;a href=&#34;https://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/&#34;&gt;Markdown language&lt;/a&gt; in 2004 in collaboration with Aaron Swartz on the syntax, with the goal of enabling people &amp;ldquo;to write using an easy-to-read, easy-to-write plain text format, and optionally convert it to structurally valid XHTML (or HTML)”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does that even mean? Well it just means it is plain text that has a few symbols to make it mean something more. Once you write a little of it then it&amp;rsquo;s much easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still not sure how DaringFireball made any money, but I guess once you get traffic it&amp;rsquo;s all gravy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-objectives:f66853f3398525872cad9091a5df51e1&#34;&gt;The Objectives&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;time-management:f66853f3398525872cad9091a5df51e1&#34;&gt;Time Management&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I write on various applications and in various places. I am always just jotting stuff down in Evernote, voice notes on my phone, sketching on my Post-it pad, etc.  I&amp;rsquo;m totally distributed. I think everywhere so I might as well be able to write everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are so few minutes of available time in my day that I want to make use of them. If I tallied up all my available time in a day and aggregated it I would have easily written a few novels by now. But that is another topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;deficiency-analysis:f66853f3398525872cad9091a5df51e1&#34;&gt;Deficiency Analysis&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to identify all the areas that were keeping me from writing.  The biggest was obviously motivation and getting back in the flow. I fail the biggest recommendation I have read: write every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second problem was my editor sucked. I was using OpenOfficeArg. Totally a busted app now. Sorry guys. Time to ditch you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third problem was that my project was getting too ambitious and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t keep all the links to the ideas. Part of that reason was the gaps in writing time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;workflow:f66853f3398525872cad9091a5df51e1&#34;&gt;Workflow&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is my proposed workflow. It will be adjusted over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;break every chapter apart into it&amp;rsquo;s own file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;start a new chapter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;provide headers with tags and various elements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;with a script fill the headers with any markdown notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;use the headers to link the files together&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;concatenate the files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;generate a table of contents based on the files and headers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;generate a project map based on collected data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;publish in HTML for ebook&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;collect $$$&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the project progresses I will be posting updates on my evolving workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Why We Quit OpenStack: or How I Lost 2 Months of My Life</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/why-we-quit-openstack</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2016 20:07:57 PDT</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/why-we-quit-openstack</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tl-dr:b85c7312ab9bb2e49c842e2b5c6f0ec6&#34;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenStack is a massive complicated ecosystem. It is only going to survive by the vendors that support it and probably not what you need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;backstory:b85c7312ab9bb2e49c842e2b5c6f0ec6&#34;&gt;Backstory&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me begin by saying that given the proper talent pool, financial resources, and time; OpenStack probably isn&amp;rsquo;t bad for some people. For most institutions it is just &lt;em&gt;wrong&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will probably write another article that outlines all the questions that I should have asked before starting this. My assumptions were not all quite valid, but I did have a sneaking suspicion given a couple very relevant experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several people asked me about a way to do big(ish) data at an affordable price. I enjoy owning hardware and infrastructure and from a business perspective that is a fairly decent endeavor in terms of static equity. I was bored with coding. The two of those items intersected and I decided to take on the task of bringing in some data clients and see if I could beat the services of other competitors and give them a better experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disclosure: This site is currently running on our openstack deployment in &lt;a href=&#34;http://dtac.io&#34;&gt;DTAC&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; private cloud&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.
.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://scotttactical.com/images/full_openstack.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Full OpenStack&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;red-flags:b85c7312ab9bb2e49c842e2b5c6f0ec6&#34;&gt;Red Flags&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where there are &lt;em&gt;clouds&lt;/em&gt; of smoke, there is probably fire. - An Indian Truism&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;it-took-forever:b85c7312ab9bb2e49c842e2b5c6f0ec6&#34;&gt;It Took Forever&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I witnessed an ambitious project slide face-first into the blue and white parking stall of the private cloud mall. Then later it was used as leverage to out every participant. I mostly attributed the breakdown to lack of time resources, OS talent and political infighting.  &lt;em&gt;nerds (heart) aws&lt;/em&gt; but more on that elsewhere.  Ignoring those huge red flags I figured my sysadmin abilities would be able to figure things out and surpass them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My response: I got sysadmin skills and no politics. I&amp;rsquo;ve never failed to raise a datacenter infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;openstack-hate-speech:b85c7312ab9bb2e49c842e2b5c6f0ec6&#34;&gt;OpenStack Hate Speech&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was plenty of hating over OpenStack. More specifically there was a lot of negative commentary about Nova, Neutron and Cinder. Basically the heart of the application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My response: I kinda need those bells and whistles so it&amp;rsquo;s worth dealing with monolithic bloat because that&amp;rsquo;s my only option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;nerds-heart-aws:b85c7312ab9bb2e49c842e2b5c6f0ec6&#34;&gt;Nerds (heart) AWS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When there is blood in the streets, buy land. - Contrarian Invetors&amp;rsquo; Proverb&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Searching for OpenStack talent was like looking for unbiased political commentary on twitter. Just ain&amp;rsquo;t there.  Techs not only didn&amp;rsquo;t know it well, but most applicants that had it on their resumes didn&amp;rsquo;t want to deploy it. Out of 50 techs I talked with about private cloud work, 49 said they could help me set up with Amazon AW$.  It is entirely confusing to ask someone to help you with your private cloud and they offer to help what is essentially a competing public cloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A side note: Most tech professionals also said they were getting a &amp;ldquo;great deal&amp;rdquo; at Amazon. No financial officer I talked to shared this sentiment. I&amp;rsquo;m sure business math was never part of comp-sci. Food for thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My response: Well most nerds have near-0 business strategy. Also this indicates there is a massive gap in talent so I&amp;rsquo;d like to be here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;babylon-fortuna-ergo-enterprise-ready:b85c7312ab9bb2e49c842e2b5c6f0ec6&#34;&gt;Babylon Fortuna ergo Enterprise-Ready&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The codebase is huge. And kinda old at this point. In internet years it&amp;rsquo;s about 50 years old.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My response: It is mature enough to use. I should be ashamed of myself. I deployed IBM Websphere and should have known better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;it-is-complicated:b85c7312ab9bb2e49c842e2b5c6f0ec6&#34;&gt;It is Complicated&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://scotttactical.com/images/fb_complicated.png&#34; alt=&#34;It&#39;s Complicated&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look at the diagram. Seriously Siri WHERE IS MY CAR!?!?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://docs.openstack.org/icehouse/training-guides/content/figures/5/a/figures/openstack-arch-havana-logical-v1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;OpenStack&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BTW this image is taken from the OpenStack &amp;ldquo;Getting Started&amp;rdquo; section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My response: Well, shit. Guess I&amp;rsquo;ve dealt with worse. I hope there isn&amp;rsquo;t magic happening. I&amp;rsquo;ll trust the Fuel installers. Oh God Fuel! don&amp;rsquo;t fail me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;it-is-fragile:b85c7312ab9bb2e49c842e2b5c6f0ec6&#34;&gt;It Is Fragile&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Refer to the previous diagram. With so many moving parts and given the lack of talent capable of managing it there is a serious level of risk in trusting a critical production environment on this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My response: Keep my public cloud fail overs built and ready to deploy. I&amp;rsquo;m a cheat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;it-is-vendor-driven:b85c7312ab9bb2e49c842e2b5c6f0ec6&#34;&gt;It Is Vendor Driven&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I kinda knew that the growth of OpenStack was tainted by vendor intrigue. I have run into this spending a considerable amount of time working with OAuth 2.0 when the &amp;ldquo;framework&amp;rdquo; was going through proposals and the lead writers were splitting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cite: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.openstack.org/summit/vancouver-2015/summit-videos/presentation/openstack-is-doomed-and-it-is-your-fault&#34;&gt;OpenStack is Doomed - Andy (termie) Smith&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My response: Ick&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-final-decision:b85c7312ab9bb2e49c842e2b5c6f0ec6&#34;&gt;The Final Decision&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it might work for a team like RackSpace, I don&amp;rsquo;t think it fits what we need. The cost benefit of having a few drivers and some prebuilt scripts to managing images wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough to justify the cost and risk of having a system that is so fragile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The risk and the knowns of unknowns inside the massive spaghetti of scope creep was enough that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t justify that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to jump in and fix something within less than a day. Pretty much every code fix I had to make took more than a day. More of 3-5 days to figure out each bug. That was the last straw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;opennebula:b85c7312ab9bb2e49c842e2b5c6f0ec6&#34;&gt;OpenNebula&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We tried other stacks and I launched a multiple node infrastructure with OpenNebula. It was refreshingly vertical and self-contained. But still felt like it wanted to follow the hypervisor slipstream of OpenStack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;blah-stack:b85c7312ab9bb2e49c842e2b5c6f0ec6&#34;&gt;Blah-Stack&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a lot of other options but I was burned out at this point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;future-plans:b85c7312ab9bb2e49c842e2b5c6f0ec6&#34;&gt;Future Plans&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The focus internally is more on bare-metal and OS containers. So far so good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion:b85c7312ab9bb2e49c842e2b5c6f0ec6&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is no free ride. (Development is an Expect 2 Work Employment)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Swiss army knives suck for self-defense and bayonets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t expect to launch a cloud out of the box that will fit your business needs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you believe the marketing - baaah&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Community first, politics last&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>General Lee-Anne 001</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/dana-60-front-axle-build</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/dana-60-front-axle-build</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;building-a-dana-sixty:6eba959523eb1be31cb56f786c76fae8&#34;&gt;Building a Dana Sixty&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of this process was setting up the new axles.
I wanted to go 1-ton all the way around.
I think everyone knows that finding a good condition d60 for a reasonable price is not possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I bought one from a local guy that had been sitting on a truck in a paintball field. It looked like it was pulled from Davey Jones Locker Room.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/2014/08/IMG_0100.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Hugger Orange 1969 K5 Blazer&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Dymo LabelWriter on Mac OSX - JavaScript</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/setup-dymo-labelwriter-mac-javascript</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 16:14:48 PDT</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/setup-dymo-labelwriter-mac-javascript</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;setup-dymo-labelwriter-450-on-mac-osx:f54a9dc0e540fe971017dc4c52f5599e&#34;&gt;Setup - Dymo LabelWriter 450 on Mac OSX&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The clinic software requires the ability to print labels adhoc and by event. This requires that the client be able to initiate the labels. There are no requirements that the backend server be able to print labels. Thank goodness. That requires something akin to a fulfillment center and probably integration with a 3rd app. Welcome: disparate stand-alone boxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;install-app-and-drivers:f54a9dc0e540fe971017dc4c52f5599e&#34;&gt;Install App and Drivers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good job guys. You get a big thumbs up for having a brew recipe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;brew install Caskroom/cask/dymo-label&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After running this I was able to hit the app from the Applications directory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then after that I had to retract my praise. The app was well out of date. It might have worked but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t going to test it. I need latest greatest. Please use &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com&#34;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt; or some public repository with the uncompressed source. :) Tnx.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;reinstall-installer:f54a9dc0e540fe971017dc4c52f5599e&#34;&gt;Reinstall Installer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://developers.dymo.com/2016/01/05/dymo-label-software-version-8-5-3-for-patch-release-macwin/&#34;&gt;http://developers.dymo.com/2016/01/05/dymo-label-software-version-8-5-3-for-patch-release-macwin/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This got me up to 8.5.3 and support for El Cap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did not install the M$ Office support junk. Thanks but no.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;add-printer:f54a9dc0e540fe971017dc4c52f5599e&#34;&gt;Add Printer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was simple as well. I went to options and added the printer. Thanks for making that easy Dymo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;coding-with-dymo-javascript-sdk:f54a9dc0e540fe971017dc4c52f5599e&#34;&gt;Coding with Dymo Javascript SDK&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This SDK wasn&amp;rsquo;t too hard to work with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took the &lt;a href=&#34;http://developers.dymo.com/2011/12/16/printing-qr-code-part-2/&#34;&gt;example&lt;/a&gt; with the included &lt;a href=&#34;http://labelwriter.com/software/dls/sdk/samples/js/QRCode/QRCode.html&#34;&gt;html&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://labelwriter.com/software/dls/sdk/samples/js/QRCode/QRCode.js&#34;&gt;javascript&lt;/a&gt;. This saved me a ton of time. I have a pretty specific use case so I was able to remove most of the unnecessary code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;allow-to-run:f54a9dc0e540fe971017dc4c52f5599e&#34;&gt;Allow to Run&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The browser will allow you to run &amp;ldquo;DYMO Label&amp;rdquo; app so you are prompted to allow. Just allow it permanently. Then you will need to refresh so the init can pick up the printer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Printing from dymo JavaScript sdk &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/NbwIdx0QtT&#34;&gt;https://t.co/NbwIdx0QtT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Scott Tactical (@Scott_Tactical) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Scott_Tactical/status/715214655044644865&#34;&gt;March 30, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Django Search: Multiple Fields and Full Text</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/django-search-multiple-fields</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2016 22:34:50 PDT</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/django-search-multiple-fields</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;text-search-django-model-fields:7b9a1438010ac7a2f51e76a3ddfaa0e1&#34;&gt;Text Search - Django Model Fields&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Django has a pretty flexible ORM, but sometimes clients need a free-form text search to get down to the content that you are looking for. It is beyond the capability of most engineers to build a comprehensive search tool and shoehorn it into an existing application. There are people working on these problems for years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This does remind me of a senior boss that asked me to add a fuzzy search field to an application and that it was &amp;ldquo;super simple&amp;rdquo;. He said &amp;ldquo;you just do a LIKE statement against all the fields we care about!&amp;rdquo; and proceeded to pseudo code it for me. He should read my post about how not to F&amp;rsquo;k up your engineering staff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;searching-with-like-statements:7b9a1438010ac7a2f51e76a3ddfaa0e1&#34;&gt;Searching with Like Statements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is probably the first place an inexperienced engineer will start. Just pick the field and do a LIKE statement against it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ex:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;User.objects.filter(username__icontains=keyword)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which will result in:
&lt;code&gt;SELECT * FROM ... WHERE USERNAME LIKE&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This doesn&amp;rsquo;t scale. It&amp;rsquo;s amateurish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this will satisfy an annoying manager for the time being considering they probably know little about computer science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;using-q-objects:7b9a1438010ac7a2f51e76a3ddfaa0e1&#34;&gt;Using Q Objects&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.djangoproject.com/en/dev/topics/db/queries/#complex-lookups-with-q-objects&#34;&gt;Q object&lt;/a&gt; in Django is kinda nice. It wraps the queryset. I need a little more information on it to be able to speak intelligently. But that aside I decided to use it in a few places where dynamic queries were valuable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After doing a little looking I found this response on &lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/26634874/how-can-i-make-django-search-in-multiple-fields-using-querysets-and-mysql-full&#34;&gt;stack overflow&lt;/a&gt; where they suggested using this. I can tell immediately that it&amp;rsquo;s not very scalable under big load.  At the least I can get it going now with only minor levels of sin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That post is apparently taken from &lt;a href=&#34;http://julienphalip.com/post/2825034077/adding-search-to-a-django-site-in-a-snap&#34;&gt;Julien Phalip - adding search to django in a snap.&lt;/a&gt;. So credit is given. Nice work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;def normalize_query(query_string,
    findterms=re.compile(r&#39;&amp;quot;([^&amp;quot;]+)&amp;quot;|(\S+)&#39;).findall,
    normspace=re.compile(r&#39;\s{2,}&#39;).sub):

    &#39;&#39;&#39;
    Splits the query string in invidual keywords, getting rid of unecessary spaces and grouping quoted words together.
    Example:
    &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; normalize_query(&#39;  some random  words &amp;quot;with   quotes  &amp;quot; and   spaces&#39;)
        [&#39;some&#39;, &#39;random&#39;, &#39;words&#39;, &#39;with quotes&#39;, &#39;and&#39;, &#39;spaces&#39;]
    &#39;&#39;&#39;

    return [normspace(&#39;&#39;,(t[0] or t[1]).strip()) for t in findterms(query_string)]

def get_query(query_string, search_fields):

    &#39;&#39;&#39;
    Returns a query, that is a combination of Q objects.
    That combination aims to search keywords within a model by testing the given search fields.
    &#39;&#39;&#39;

    query = None # Query to search for every search term
    terms = normalize_query(query_string)
    for term in terms:
        or_query = None # Query to search for a given term in each field
        for field_name in search_fields:
            q = Q(**{&amp;quot;%s__icontains&amp;quot; % field_name: term})
            if or_query is None:
                or_query = q
            else:
                or_query = or_query | q
        if query is None:
            query = or_query
        else:
            query = query &amp;amp; or_query

def search_for_something(request):
   query_string = &#39;&#39;
   found_entries = None
   if (&#39;q&#39; in request.GET) and request.GET[&#39;q&#39;].strip():
       query_string = request.GET[&#39;q&#39;]
       entry_query = get_query(query_string, [&#39;field1&#39;, &#39;field2&#39;, &#39;field3&#39;])
       found_entries = Model.objects.filter(entry_query).order_by(&#39;-something&#39;)

   return render_to_response(&#39;app/template-result.html&#39;,
           { &#39;query_string&#39;: query_string, &#39;found_entries&#39;: found_entries },
           context_instance=RequestContext(request)
       )
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another helpful resource was from &lt;a href=&#34;https://yeti.co/blog/global-search-in-django-rest-framework/&#34;&gt;Yeti&lt;/a&gt; adding in some global search. A bit outdated but a nice resource.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;search-library:7b9a1438010ac7a2f51e76a3ddfaa0e1&#34;&gt;Search Library&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/django-haystack/django-haystack&#34;&gt;https://github.com/django-haystack/django-haystack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/etianen/django-watson&#34;&gt;https://github.com/etianen/django-watson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Dump Django Databases and Create Fixtures for Testing</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/post/dump-django-databases-and-create-fixtures-for-testing/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 23:20:36 PST</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/post/dump-django-databases-and-create-fixtures-for-testing/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;fixtures-are-a-messy-mess:25f7c7e781c9bc5fa7e4fc70ab13d75c&#34;&gt;Fixtures are a Messy Mess&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is quite a pain to maintain fixtures it seems. I am not sure why yet. Maybe there hasn&amp;rsquo;t been quite enough time on this piece of the product for it to mature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;django-dumpdata:25f7c7e781c9bc5fa7e4fc70ab13d75c&#34;&gt;Django dumpdata&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried several different variations to dump the data. I&amp;rsquo;ll include a few of them here since they might actually work for someone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;python manage.py dumpdata &amp;gt; fixture.json&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I kept getting various key errors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Could not load contenttypes.ContentType(pk=23): duplicate key value violates unique constraint &amp;ldquo;django_content_type_app_label_76bd3d3b_uniq&amp;rdquo;
  DETAIL:  Key (app_label, model)=(businesses, business) already exists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually turned into this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;python manage.py dumpdata &amp;ndash;indent=4 -e contenttypes -e auth.Permission -e admin &amp;ndash;natural-foreign &amp;gt; fixture.json&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OR&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;python manage.py dumpdata &amp;ndash;natural-foreign &amp;ndash;natural-primary &amp;ndash;indent=4 &amp;gt; fixture.json&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;gave me this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Could not load object.User(pk=None): null value in column &amp;ldquo;user_ptr_id&amp;rdquo; violates not-null constraint&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;dumpdata-alternatives:25f7c7e781c9bc5fa7e4fc70ab13d75c&#34;&gt;DumpData Alternatives&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.djangopackages.com/grids/g/fixtures/&#34;&gt;django grid&lt;/a&gt; to the rescue again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of the packages were for generating testing fixtures. I don&amp;rsquo;t need that. What I need is basically a data backup tool so that whichever dev has the best copy of the data to be able to create the deployment fixture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to give &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/davedash/django-fixture-magic&#34;&gt;Fixture Magic&lt;/a&gt; a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fixture-magic:25f7c7e781c9bc5fa7e4fc70ab13d75c&#34;&gt;Fixture Magic&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My initial test wasn&amp;rsquo;t very promising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ImportError: cannot import name loading&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But apparently I wasn&amp;rsquo;t the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/davedash/django-fixture-magic/issues/37&#34;&gt;only one.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-e git://github.com/davedash/django-fixture-magic@42c6df73d11512d76e3170453f175164ff22db02#egg=django_fixture_magic&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I found out that I can&amp;rsquo;t have non-int keys. Since most of my objects use UUID that was the end of F-Magic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;i-gave-up-on-fixtures:25f7c7e781c9bc5fa7e4fc70ab13d75c&#34;&gt;I Gave Up On Fixtures&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This data model must just be too complex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deploying dev environment now consists of setting up the db and loading a full DB dump.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;pg_dump APP &amp;gt; APP/fixtures/pg_dump.latest.sql&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Load it up with a script when deploying dev.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;psql APP &amp;lt; APP/fixtures/pg_dump.latest.sql&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-now-tests:25f7c7e781c9bc5fa7e4fc70ab13d75c&#34;&gt;How Now Tests?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know. Fixtures are kinda important with tests. I went ahead and installed &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rbarrois/factory_boy&#34;&gt;Factory boy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good enough for now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sorry Django Fixtures. You kinda suck.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Migrate A Private GitHub Repository to Free Bitbucket in Roughly 7 Easy Steps</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/migrate-private-github-repo-bitbucket</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 21:28:23 PST</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/migrate-private-github-repo-bitbucket</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-not-github:3d11bc9de94f00f45f803ae774510a67&#34;&gt;Why Not GitHub&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;github-is-great:3d11bc9de94f00f45f803ae774510a67&#34;&gt;GitHub is Great&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong. I would recommend using this service for a number of reasons that are not fiscally motivated. It isn&amp;rsquo;t whether GitHub.com is good or not. There is a matter of economics at play though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a startup I just don&amp;rsquo;t have the extra 25/mo to throw into GitHub business account. It looks cool that I have an organization there and there are more badges.  But it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work at 12 X $25 = $300/yr. Bottom account. Bronze I think it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;github-is-mas-rico:3d11bc9de94f00f45f803ae774510a67&#34;&gt;GitHub is Mas Rico&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is cheap if you are a big corporation but for a small shop or a single coder with some sensitive code it doesn&amp;rsquo;t make sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-bitbucket:3d11bc9de94f00f45f803ae774510a67&#34;&gt;Why Bitbucket&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bitbucket.org/&#34;&gt;Bitbucket&lt;/a&gt; is tied into &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.atlassian.com/software/bitbucket&#34;&gt;Atlassian&lt;/a&gt;. There are a lot of advantages if that is your enterprise process software provider.  Having it link in with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.atlassian.com/software/confluence&#34;&gt;Confluence&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.atlassian.com/software/jira&#34;&gt;Jira&lt;/a&gt; is pretty nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is also a much more manageable pricing structure.  Free 99 for private! Yeah once you have more than 5 accounts it starts to charge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;moving-from-github-to-bitbucket:3d11bc9de94f00f45f803ae774510a67&#34;&gt;Moving From GitHub to Bitbucket&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok let&amp;rsquo;s move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;create-a-team:3d11bc9de94f00f45f803ae774510a67&#34;&gt;Create A Team&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the top of the navigation select the Teams &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Create team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://scotttactical.com/images/github-bitbucket-migration-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Create Team&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow the steps. It will tell you obvious things like &amp;ldquo;You don&amp;rsquo;t have any code&amp;rdquo;. There are also no members in your team but you can deal with that later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;import-a-repository-from-github:3d11bc9de94f00f45f803ae774510a67&#34;&gt;Import a Repository from GitHub&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully the developers at Atlassian are aware of migrants coming in and provided a convenient button to the&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://scotttactical.com/images/github-bitbucket-migration-2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Import a repository&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;set-up-the-new-repository:3d11bc9de94f00f45f803ae774510a67&#34;&gt;Set up the new repository&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some helpful notes to guide you throught he process. Add your credentials and hit &amp;ldquo;Import repository&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://scotttactical.com/images/github-bitbucket-migration-3.png&#34; alt=&#34;Import a repository&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select git&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select &amp;ldquo;Requires authorization&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy the HTTPS URL from your GitHub account&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: if you have two-factor authentication on you will have to disable it for the import.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://scotttactical.com/images/github-bitbucket-migration-4.png&#34; alt=&#34;Copy URL&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;change-the-origin-url:3d11bc9de94f00f45f803ae774510a67&#34;&gt;Change the Origin URL&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you have created the new repository you need to update your git repo to point to the new repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CD into your local source directory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;git remote -v&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will show you where you are still pointing. Now you will need to edit the git config.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;vim .git/config&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Change the [remote &amp;ldquo;origin&amp;rdquo;] section &lt;code&gt;url&lt;/code&gt; to point to your new repo. Located in the upper right of your new repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure you upload the proper keys and things of that nature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a handy command for picking up the ssh public keys:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cat ~/.ssh/id_rsa.pub | pbcopy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;delete-the-github-repository:3d11bc9de94f00f45f803ae774510a67&#34;&gt;Delete the GitHub Repository&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you feel confident that your repository is functioning in an acceptable form, DELETE your repository. With extreme care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://scotttactical.com/images/github-bitbucket-migration-5.png&#34; alt=&#34;Settings&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://scotttactical.com/images/github-bitbucket-migration-6.png&#34; alt=&#34;Delete Repo&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was a little puckered up when I hit the red button. I am not going to lie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://scotttactical.com/images/github-bitbucket-migration-7.png&#34; alt=&#34;Nuke It!&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;invite-to-your-party:3d11bc9de94f00f45f803ae774510a67&#34;&gt;Invite to Your Party&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go ahead and send out invitations to your team members now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;downgrade-your-github-account:3d11bc9de94f00f45f803ae774510a67&#34;&gt;Downgrade your GitHub Account&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go to account settings (or organization settings)
  Go to billing tab
  Click on change plan tab
  Downgrade to a free account&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion:3d11bc9de94f00f45f803ae774510a67&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is about it.  That isn&amp;rsquo;t very painful. It is probably wise to do early on if you have any intention of using the Atlassian tools.  We switched to Jira at the next to previous place a while before. They have a great sales team there so it is very likely that one of your business managers will get hoodwinked into it. Fancy brochures and talking about culture and productivity will peak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ps:3d11bc9de94f00f45f803ae774510a67&#34;&gt;PS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Btw. If you don&amp;rsquo;t use a source code repository then please let me know so I can keep from wasting my time with any interviews with your company.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>What Does a Data Scientist Do</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/what-does-data-scientist-do</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 12:57:42 PST</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/what-does-data-scientist-do</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-does-a-data-scientist-do:4d5f8e2d5f35e4cef85674d2e534a0c7&#34;&gt;What Does a Data Scientist Do&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;uncovering-the-key-capabilities-of-a-data-scientist:4d5f8e2d5f35e4cef85674d2e534a0c7&#34;&gt;Uncovering the Key Capabilities of a Data Scientist&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you thinking of pursuing a career as a data scientist? It has been published that being in this field could mean you will be in-demand for many companies. So, it is not surprising if the number of individuals turning to data science is fast increasing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But being a data scientist will also bring you huge responsibilities. You will cover various roles from different industries and organizations, with academia, finance and government being just some of them. Some of them will differ from each other. The skills and duties that you will carry, as a data scientist, will hugely vary from each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/hankssteve&#34;&gt;Steve Hanks&lt;/a&gt;, a man who leads a team who is responsible of all analytical works in &lt;a href=&#34;http://whitepages.com&#34;&gt;whitePages.com&lt;/a&gt;, tells us that there are three things that every data scientist should understand. These three thoughts must always be kept in mind by those who are in the field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data has a MEANING.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understand the problem that needs solution, and how data RELATES to it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understand the ENGINEERING.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Curated from: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forbes.com/sites/bernardmarr/&#34;&gt;Bernard Marr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read more:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.datasciencecentral.com/profiles/blogs/what-does-a-data-scientist-really-do-2&#34;&gt;http://www.datasciencecentral.com/profiles/blogs/what-does-a-data-scientist-really-do-2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.forbes.com/sites/bernardmarr/2016/01/07/big-data-uncovered-what-does-a-data-scientist-really-do/#2715e4857a0b34f9a86e6f7f&#34;&gt;http://www.forbes.com/sites/bernardmarr/2016/01/07/big-data-uncovered-what-does-a-data-scientist-really-do/#2715e4857a0b34f9a86e6f7f&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Health, Interconnectivity - The Data Revolution</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/health-medical-interconnectivity-data-revolution/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2015 07:34:17 PST</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/health-medical-interconnectivity-data-revolution/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;health-medical-interconnectivity-and-the-coming-data-revolution:4b5599adc5f806914ce8863e57f40566&#34;&gt;Health, Medical Interconnectivity and The Coming Data Revolution&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://scotttactical.com/images/future-medicine-small.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Medicine In The Future&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;johnson-davis-walk:4b5599adc5f806914ce8863e57f40566&#34;&gt;Johnson Davis&amp;rsquo; Walk&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Six red indicators breach the serene layout of the medical information dashboard. Gauges, charts and graphs provide human cues concerning the information flowing through the Intra-Medical Services Accountability Pipeline. The IMSAP emerged in evolutionary form as various government, education and enterprises started the race to consume the calculus of living data. And now these machines of data consumption interpret the flow of what some consider the representation of that thing which connects life and machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This is already too far out of alignment. Go ahead and authorize a broadcast.&amp;rdquo; The leather on a reclined command chair squeaks as a technical nurse analyst operating somewhere in west cornfield office Omaha adjusts his virtual reality enhanced workstation. He then presses a projected button in front of him to broadcast a reactionary command to the IMSAP allowing it to commence with corrective actions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A thirty two character hash appears above those six red indicators. Each indicator represents a series of tests that have either passed or failed. The metrics on this dashboard are human readable graphs and gauges which represent the aggregations that were formed before various disparate machines decided to trigger these events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Helped by a generous grant from the Department of Health, one US company started providing a selection of wearable transmission and monitoring devices to anyone who requested one. A super watch. Stylish enough and nearly indestructible: each one is paired to the owner&amp;rsquo;s own DNA sub-sequence so basically safe from theft or ending up on Pawn Stars. Inside the grayish protective shell is a lithium battery that can power the device well beyond the normal span of customary planned obsolescence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each watch powers various monitors that track not only the wearer&amp;rsquo;s location and environment but will also track a number of vitals and chemical indicators. Literally the entire band is an array of sensors. It can tell if the wearer is hydrated, if the skin started perspiring, if the glucose levels are spiking, or if the wearer is above the legal intoxication level for driving. Some watches have become an insurance imperative for obvious reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early wearable devices were tethered to phones or computers which would store and transmit to remote servers. These new devices record, buffer and broadcast their data continuously. The device will buffer several gigabytes of data and burst them out in order of importance once the wearer passes an access point relay station. With the interconnectivity of utilities, vehicles, city-wide wifi or personal hotspots the device has plenty of bandwidth to upload gigabytes of raw data every day into storage vaults holding petabytes of human biometrics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each relay station will bounce data around and apply its own level of security. The data is eventually aggregated and stored at any number of server farms which catalog and move the data based on the tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several companies and healthcare organizations have &amp;ldquo;subscribed&amp;rdquo; to this firehose of data with each promising to monitor or monetize the flow of data in a slightly different way. Because the data is identified by strings of characters or hashes the data can be recorded or parsed and then reported on without having to identify personal information. Much of the data is broken into blocks and only understandable by those consumers who own the tracking codes to piece them together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wearers can subscribe to a service and match to their hash for real-time health tracking or companies can do the same for bulk users. Some companies pull in various other data streams to allow machines to find correlations between data from other devices with the data coming from the wearer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The initial report shows the first indicator was an anxiety and flight risk flag coming from the HHS. His transportation pattern altered radically from normal routes and the account has a flag on it for persons of known risk.&amp;rdquo; announces the technical operator. &amp;ldquo;His records are coming up now. He is Mr. Johnson Davis of Phoenix, Arizona. It appears he has gone on a spontaneous and brisk walk.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The second indicator comes from the medical office tracking his progress which says that the device accelerometer is showing extreme body movements coupled with lower skin temperatures and higher levels of perspiration. {Serotonin levels are out of the bracket} It broke a trend line that was tracking depression recovery progress&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The third and fourth indicators were from Dark Gray deep learning algorithms. It pulled from the in-home monitoring device and also the pharmacy which has recorded a distinct distortion in blood chemical levels indicating that the Mr Davis has diminished or ceased his dosage. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t appear that he is intoxicated. It might have pulled in sentiment off his social media. That thing is creepy that way; reading all our messages and making note of our less-than-optimistic disposition.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;action:4b5599adc5f806914ce8863e57f40566&#34;&gt;Action&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://scotttactical.com/images/doctor-future1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Future Doctors&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Let&amp;rsquo;s try to contact his physician and then see if we can give mister Davis a call to see if he is okay.&amp;rdquo; A supervisor requests access to the wearers full records. Most data is stored in a database holding of a majority of the nation&amp;rsquo;s citizens, but some has to come from other sources. That request triggers cascading data requests from a list of Application Programming Interfaces (API) approved for the supervisors access and appropriate for the given threats. Each call is validated by a central HIPAA authorization service API that checks access controls for internal and external data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a couple seconds all the API calls return and the data is aggregated into a patient data record object that is both human and machine readable. After considerable debate and mangling an industry-wide format for data records was created allowing for the creation of generic interfaces that can easy view any type of patient record using the best in user interfaces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hypermedia embeds metadata about how to transverse the record including ways to find those first degree contacts associated to the record. The supervisors access and need allowed for the receipt of links to the medical organizations and professionals associated to the wearer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I have the vitals from the device here but it stopped. I think that is why indicator five went off. He is too far away from any access points so maybe Johnny is walking out into the woods. It will probably get a GPS blip in a couple minutes though.&amp;rdquo; reports the technician again. &amp;ldquo;The sixth IMSAP went off because both his cellphone is shut off or broken in addition to indicator five and two being active. It catches old folks who fall mostly.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;He was diagnosed with a major depressive disorder and prescribed medication. The physician is on chat and is getting a prescription recommendation based on the feed.&amp;rdquo; says the supervisor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Was he at the golf course?&amp;rdquo; asks the technician jokingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No he was asleep. He&amp;rsquo;s in India.&amp;rdquo; responds the supervisor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Okay, I have dropped a marker and a care worker has already added into his route.&amp;rdquo; indicates the technician pointing at a map overlay of the area. &amp;ldquo;And the doctor has submitted the suggested drug formula from the feed to the API at the drug lab which is starting to print the pills right now. He will be in the area with the corrective prescription in a couple minutes.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pushing back into his chair the tech relaxes, &amp;ldquo;Evening, mister Davis. Your cocktail is queued.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;fin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;points-of-interest:4b5599adc5f806914ce8863e57f40566&#34;&gt;Points of Interest&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data format

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Related records&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Social media&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Machine learning

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deep learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integration / collaboration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Storage size&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authorization (HIPAA)

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Centralized controls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authentication

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Devices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Agents&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Outsourcing medicine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personalized prescriptions

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3D printed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Matched to DNA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On demand&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wearable-technologies.com/2015/06/one-single-device-to-diagnose-a-set-of-15-medical-conditions/&#34;&gt;https://www.wearable-technologies.com/2015/06/one-single-device-to-diagnose-a-set-of-15-medical-conditions/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mckinsey.com/insights/pharmaceuticals_and_medical_products/the_role_of_big_data_in_medicine&#34;&gt;http://www.mckinsey.com/insights/pharmaceuticals_and_medical_products/the_role_of_big_data_in_medicine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wired.com/insights/2014/08/patient-monitoring-big-data-future-healthcare/&#34;&gt;http://www.wired.com/insights/2014/08/patient-monitoring-big-data-future-healthcare/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.withings.com/us/en/products/pulse&#34;&gt;http://www.withings.com/us/en/products/pulse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/innovations/wp/2015/08/11/why-it-matters-that-the-fda-just-approved-the-first-3d-printed-drug/&#34;&gt;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/innovations/wp/2015/08/11/why-it-matters-that-the-fda-just-approved-the-first-3d-printed-drug/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://genomemag.com/what-is-personalized-medicine/#.VmmrzXurau4&#34;&gt;http://genomemag.com/what-is-personalized-medicine/#.VmmrzXurau4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.magicleap.com/#/home&#34;&gt;http://www.magicleap.com/#/home&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Try Not 2 Fuck Up Ur Engineering</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/try-not-2-fuck-up-ur-engineering/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 10:43:58 PST</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/try-not-2-fuck-up-ur-engineering/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;Leadership Checklist for Non-Technical Managers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you build software that provides value to both clients, owners and engineers?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This list has started as a list of notes that I kept over the last few years. Yes, this is the abbreviated version of &lt;a href=&#34;http://scotttactical.com/management-for-quality-software-development/&#34;&gt;Management For Quality Software&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;executive-leadership:b95f08065f33835f1988c422d37af806&#34;&gt;Executive Leadership&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bloated and ugly products are born at the top, but a good engineering environment may begin there&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The three ways business leaders can add value is with &lt;em&gt;numbers, numbers, numbers&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put your name on the product&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-business-requirement:b95f08065f33835f1988c422d37af806&#34;&gt;The Business Requirement&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Write a business requirement that reflects specific details about a problem that the business is solving based on market research numbers. A full description is beyond this terse scope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;feature-requests-r-bad:b95f08065f33835f1988c422d37af806&#34;&gt;Feature Requests R Bad&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know you really want to. You think you know UI design and are well versed in using a browser. In reality you probably suck at engineering/UI/art.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See previous paragraph sentence 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;feature-driven-cycles-suck:b95f08065f33835f1988c422d37af806&#34;&gt;Feature-Driven Cycles Suck&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;When is the report download page going to be done?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not by the definition in agile dictionaries, but defined as the environment by which business determines short term goals in reference to features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;business-vision:b95f08065f33835f1988c422d37af806&#34;&gt;Business Vision&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set a clear vision&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make the vision both short and long term&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t pivot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid buzzword glory pitchmen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;employee-goals:b95f08065f33835f1988c422d37af806&#34;&gt;Employee Goals&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consider the employees goals in your vision&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you do not care about the employees&amp;rsquo; goals then they might set their own&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have an idea of what motivates people (We are not all building rockets or curing cancer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make an employee goal the production of a quality product&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;optimal-relationships:b95f08065f33835f1988c422d37af806&#34;&gt;Optimal Relationships&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few items here that I look for:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does the team easily share code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do they internally set group functions (meetings/lunches/after-hours) – can be dangerous&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can they tell you what others are working on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are there a lot of complaints about coworkers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask them who the best employees are&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide a way to communicate problems to leadership&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Devs need &lt;a href=&#34;https://michaelochurch.wordpress.com/2014/12/&#34;&gt;CS 666 Political Science&lt;/a&gt; training. Seriously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;hire-the-right-people:b95f08065f33835f1988c422d37af806&#34;&gt;Hire the Right People&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://scotttactical.com/images/milton.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Milton Office Space&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hire people smarter than you and get out of their way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See my other articles on &lt;a href=&#34;http://scotttactical.com/interview-strategies-a-technology-hiring-manager/&#34;&gt;hiring technology professionals&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;don-t-micromanage:b95f08065f33835f1988c422d37af806&#34;&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t Micromanage&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nuff said else failed previous item.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;understand-software-shelf-life:b95f08065f33835f1988c422d37af806&#34;&gt;Understand Software Shelf Life&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;shelf-life-definition:b95f08065f33835f1988c422d37af806&#34;&gt;Shelf Life Definition&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Software expiration has passed when both of the following criteria have been met:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It no longer produces enough value to support the maintenance of the code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The proposed value from software improvements is less than the cost of the improvements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;predict-the-futures:b95f08065f33835f1988c422d37af806&#34;&gt;Predict The Futures&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Applying a timeline to the life of an application is hard. Not because one cannot estimate a project life, but because most are not truthful with themselves on the potential of their project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ass.u.mption: shoestring ultra-successful software lasts forever and will fix rare bugs later when money is pouring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;yeah-fix-it-later:b95f08065f33835f1988c422d37af806&#34;&gt;Yeah – Fix It Later&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t fail the &amp;ldquo;fix it later&amp;rdquo; mentality. Sometimes disposable software is appropriate. If you only need to scrape a website once then just write a quick and dirty script and then archive it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;plan-for-the-futures:b95f08065f33835f1988c422d37af806&#34;&gt;Plan For The Futures&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don&amp;rsquo;t really know what the future holds for us, but we should plan for it. Ask this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where is this script stored and why?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where is the documentation?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it is only stored locally and undocumented on someone&amp;rsquo;s machine: fail++.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;bad-code-costs-moar:b95f08065f33835f1988c422d37af806&#34;&gt;Bad Code Costs Moar&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is no fix-it-later scenario.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There will be no point where you be chillin&amp;rsquo; counting benjamins letting engineers scrub code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is no pattern that fixes an anti-pattern&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is no way to pause the businesses for your migration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can only pick 2:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://scotttactical.com/images/good-fast-cheap-venn-diagram.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Good Fast Cheap - Pick 2 - Venn Diagram&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-bad-code:b95f08065f33835f1988c422d37af806&#34;&gt;What is Bad Code&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a hard one to explain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sometimes biz pushes devs to deliver sooner than estimates, so they cut corners.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sometimes coders are lazy or do not really want to be on a project business is pushing them to move faster on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sometimes coders are just not any good. You hired them so now it is a containment issue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have peer reviews and pull requests, and yes, that costs. See: &lt;em&gt;Outsourced cheap stuff&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;myth-of-the-parallel-rewrite:b95f08065f33835f1988c422d37af806&#34;&gt;Myth of the Parallel Rewrite&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scenario:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Going to refactor legacy code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also continuing development or maintaining the current code base&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not contributing more human or financial resources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Done in 1/10th the time that the original code base was developed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Macho Camacho for President!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/sGUNPMPrxvA&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;software-development-lifecycle:b95f08065f33835f1988c422d37af806&#34;&gt;Software Development Lifecycle&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A reasonable software lifecycle is imperative to delivering quality software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No cycle == Bad mkay&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;politics-of-the-lifecycle:b95f08065f33835f1988c422d37af806&#34;&gt;Politics of The Lifecycle&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I intend to write at more length about the politics behind the product lifecycle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Case study: There is no policy for a daily deployment to Curiosity rover on Mars and if the previous glitches are an indicator we can assume that even &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.space.com/23553-mars-rover-curiosity-software-glitch.html&#34;&gt;NASA has a high bug rate&lt;/a&gt; when dealing with rapid product deployments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;test-for-the-love-of-all-that-is-sacred-test:b95f08065f33835f1988c422d37af806&#34;&gt;Test - For the Love of All That is Sacred, Test&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you do not have tests your software probably sucks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tests indemnify engineers and build confidence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Broad set of tests == enjoy the weekend == morale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New features probably will not break existing functionality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If there are no tests then deployments are a crap shoot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wide Coverage Is Safety&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Estimate tests writing time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Know your tests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Damn the tests - DO IT LIVE!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine this conversation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Biz Guy - &amp;ldquo;The super widget functionality I had you put in there last month is not working. What did you guys break?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Programmer - &amp;ldquo;All tests are passing. I am looking and there are no tests covering any business requirements for such a feature. If you want we can take a look and write a test that covers this feature.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion:b95f08065f33835f1988c422d37af806&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Build things that make the world better. Treat employees like people. Give back.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Management for Quality Software Development Managers</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/management-for-quality-software-development/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 09:53:52 PST</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/management-for-quality-software-development/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;This started as a list of notes for my boss on how I see the best way to manage technical professionals. I am trying to provide non-technical managers with the resources to direct technical teams in a way that will produce quality software and keep the engineering staff engaged and moving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you build software that provides value to both clients, users, owners and engineers for the years to come?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This also assumes a state of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knowing how to hire&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Having some resources - not 8 figure funding but enough to pay market rate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Having a legitimate business model - I suppose it would work for a pr0n spammer too though&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Embracing a genuine desire for quality, progress, and community&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;tl-dr:46b69cc651b36917739e2a1f57a8d295&#34;&gt;TL;DR:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This document contains &amp;gt; 2k words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See the terse version:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://scotttactical.com/try-not-2-fuck-up-ur-engineering/&#34;&gt;Try Not 2 Fuck Up Ur Engineering&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;software-shelf-life:46b69cc651b36917739e2a1f57a8d295&#34;&gt;Software Shelf Life&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All software has a shelf life. Some software must last for a very long time whereas some software is disposable. Software longevity is derived by the leadership from the top of the organization and if software applications pass their usefulness it is due to the guidance of the leadership. It should not be assumed that long lasting software is the “best” type of software for every need and I will briefly attempt to give some very high level tools I use to determine the case by a set of criteria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;We have achieved infinite software longevity!!! - NOT
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://scotttactical.com/images/mcd.gif&#34; alt=&#34;We Have Infinite Longevity! - not&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;shelf-life-definition:46b69cc651b36917739e2a1f57a8d295&#34;&gt;Shelf Life Definition&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.popularmechanics.com/space/a17991/voyager-1-voyager-2-retiring-engineer/&#34;&gt;Nasa is looking for&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fortran&#34;&gt;Fortran&lt;/a&gt; engineers to interact with the Voyager space probe. This is one of those exceedingly rare cases when the software outlasts the engineers. Also, I will throw up if anyone throws out the obligatory trope: “they do not build &amp;lsquo;um like they used to”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like to define shelf life in the following way. Software expiration has passed when both of the following criteria have been met.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It no longer produces enough value to support the maintenance of the code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The proposed value from software improvements is less than the cost of the improvements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Intelligent managers can determine the above criteria by the numbers and without much confusion. Businesses who are in a state of going out of business will come upon these decision by running out of resources and will be forced to shut down projects or archive code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should be noted that time is a very important factor to consider in the calculations. It might be affordable financially to have cheap labor work on fixing code for extended months or years, but sometimes opportunity loss has to be calculated. Throwing resources at bad decisions is a recipe for losing. This is a relative of the sunk-cost fallacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;predict-the-future:46b69cc651b36917739e2a1f57a8d295&#34;&gt;Predict The Future&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a bit of art, but applying a timeline to the life of an application is hard. Not because one cannot estimate a project life, but because most managers are not truthful with themselves on the potential of their project. They assume that they can shoestring ultra-successful software that will last forever and if by some rare event bugs show up, well, they can be fixed later when the money is pouring in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “fix it later” mentality is the most common error I encounter. Considering that the majority of my career has been spent cleaning up bad decisions I am qualified to attest to this. Normally when in the “fix it” stage, business principles have lost their original love of the project and are looking for something else to work on. They are probably planning their exit strategy or engaging a new mistress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is not reasonable to say that a project is going to be highly successful and at the same time treating the project like it will only last 6 months. What I mean by this is the software lifespan is implied at six months or less if the management implements development principles that guarantee short-lived software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes disposable software is appropriate. If you only need to scrape a website once then just write a quick and dirty script and then archive it. It is worth noting here that having an intuitive and organized archiving procedure for scripts will add a lot of value by turning a code trash pile into a tool chest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;plan-for-the-future:46b69cc651b36917739e2a1f57a8d295&#34;&gt;Plan For The Future&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do not really know what the future holds for us, but we should plan for it. One main reason we know about the champion societies of the past and can learn from them is they planned for future peoples to read their story. Monks and librarians have toiled meticulously in the storage and organization of these. This is in contrast to those “barbarian” societies that languish far behind and suffer the problems of a chaotic and backward people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A manager can simply ask “where is this script stored and why?”. If it is only stored locally on someone&amp;rsquo;s machine: fail++. The answer to this will show if the coder cares about anything past the initial writing of the script. If there is documentation on the scripts linked from the organized repository then win. Generally that level of control can only come from an experienced technology leader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cannot quantify precisely but disorganized file storage and a lack of repository protocols accounts for a large portion of “code sin” and will absolutely contribute to the weak ROI in the future. It is a truism to say that most of the coding problems have been solved before and that at this point the coders are just building slightly on top of those before them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;bad-code-costs-more:46b69cc651b36917739e2a1f57a8d295&#34;&gt;Bad Code Costs More&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please see the below diagram. You can have any two of the following scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://scotttactical.com/images/good-fast-cheap-venn-diagram.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Good Fast Cheap - Pick 2 - Venn Diagram&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is no fix-it-later scenario.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is no point where you are just chillin&amp;rsquo; counting yo monies while letting engineers clean code sin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is no pattern that fixes an anti-pattern&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is no way to pause the businesses for your migration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-bad-code:46b69cc651b36917739e2a1f57a8d295&#34;&gt;What is Bad Code&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a hard one to explain. Many things can contribute to bad code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://scotttactical.com/images/milton.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Milton Office Space&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-why-of-bad-code:46b69cc651b36917739e2a1f57a8d295&#34;&gt;The “why” of bad code.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it is because a requirement is placed on the engineering team that pushes them to deliver something sooner than their estimations. Programmers are generally a timid and self-disparaging lot so they tend to over promise. They are afraid to tell business that things cannot be accomplished so they cut corners. All those combined is a recipe for faults and bugs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes coders are lazy. You can spot those too. They do not really want to be coding or they do not like the job they are doing. On top of that business is probably pushing for them to move faster. What is the motivation not to stuff the sin under the rug.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes coders are just not any good. You hired them so now it is a management issue and the only way to keep bad code from getting into the repository is to have peer reviews and pull requests. That takes quite a bit of time so again you have not saved any money with your outsourced cheap stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will go into this topic in more detail in another article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;myth-of-the-parallel-rewrite:46b69cc651b36917739e2a1f57a8d295&#34;&gt;Myth of the Parallel Rewrite&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been a common theme in my career to hear business folks tell us that they are going to refactor code while at the same time continuing development or maintaining the current code base while also not contributing more human or financial resources to the equation. And all of this will be done in 1/10th the time that the original code base was developed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To paraphrase Presidente Macho Camacho&amp;rsquo;s State of the Union:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/sGUNPMPrxvA&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;software-development-lifecycle:46b69cc651b36917739e2a1f57a8d295&#34;&gt;Software Development Lifecycle&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A reasonable software lifecycle is imperative to delivering quality software. The terms of the lifecycle are entirely determined by the needs of the business, but doing away with an organized lifecycle is a recipe for failure. Maybe a business needs to fail to encourage the evolutionary aspect of the free market. Failure is not so beneficial though if no one learns from the mistake.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://nvie.com/posts/a-successful-git-branching-model/&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://scotttactical.com/images/git-model.png&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Git Model via Vincent Driessen&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h2 id=&#34;politics-of-the-lifecycle:46b69cc651b36917739e2a1f57a8d295&#34;&gt;Politics of The Lifecycle&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I intend to write at more length about the politics behind the product lifecycle. At this time I will just leave the note that the deployment schedule reflects software critical value. Requesting a development team to constantly deploy denotes a lack of care regarding software quality and stability. There is no policy for a daily deployment to Curiosity rover on Mars and if the previous glitches are an indicator we can assume that even &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.space.com/23553-mars-rover-curiosity-software-glitch.html&#34;&gt;NASA has a high bug rate&lt;/a&gt; when dealing with rapid product deployments. Critical software needs a settling time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;optimal-relationships:46b69cc651b36917739e2a1f57a8d295&#34;&gt;Optimal Relationships&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is a development team without a solid lesson in &lt;a href=&#34;https://michaelochurch.wordpress.com/2014/12/&#34;&gt;CS 666&lt;/a&gt;. In such a petty manner, decent engineers will offset very good engineers to find their ways into the Herman/Miller of power. And given what we already know about politics + geekness; it is easy to see that the worst of a Klingon Game of Thrones will play out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is imperative for leaders to set managers in place who will put the team first instead of their careers. That kind of leadership rarely exists outside of sports and the military hence why I am well versed in tribal coalescence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can you spot a problem? It is beyond the scope of this article to provide a team-building dissertation but I will append a few items here that I look for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does the team easily share code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do they internally set group functions (meetings/lunches/after-hours) – can also be dangerous&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can they tell you what others are working on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are there a lot of complaints about coworkers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask them who the best employees are&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are there provisional methods for communicating concerns up the chain of command&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;executive-leadership:46b69cc651b36917739e2a1f57a8d295&#34;&gt;Executive Leadership&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bloated and ugly products start at the top and only the resources for good engineering begin there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://scotttactical.com/images/jobs.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Steve Jobs&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even Steve Jobs got booted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the leadership is only concerned with making quick cash then the product quality is probably going to be garbage. If they are only in it for the money why would they care about the product. If they are in it for ego then the product will probably look like a cartoon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally I love making things and my personal image comes with the work I do. From building cars to writing quality code, I try to create things that are valuable and last beyond my time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good leaders should just plant the idea, find the people that want to complete it and stand out of the way and watch the numbers. Sorry chief, if you want to be creative you gotta give up the title and join us heroes in the trenches. The three ways business leaders can add value is with numbers, numbers, numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-business-requirement:46b69cc651b36917739e2a1f57a8d295&#34;&gt;The Business Requirement&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Write a business requirement that reflects specific details about a problem that the business is solving based on market research numbers. The problem must be defined with clear terms and with enough details so that anyone who is not familiar with the product can figure out how they are benefitting from the change. The product managers should be used to simply translating business requirements only so much as that they make sense to everyone involved. Engineers should be able to express the problem back to stakeholders in terms that the customer can understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;feature-requests-r-bad:46b69cc651b36917739e2a1f57a8d295&#34;&gt;Feature Requests R Bad&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know you really want to. You think you know UI design and are well versed in using a browser. In reality you probably suck at engineering/UI/art though. If you are looking at a widget on another site and trying to “innovate” a feature into your product but lack any sort of market research data for that specific functionality then you can count yourself among most managers. It will probably dictate poor code and make employees short sighted and unhappy. Good luck hoss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See previous paragraph sentence #1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;feature-driven-cycles-suck:46b69cc651b36917739e2a1f57a8d295&#34;&gt;Feature-Driven Cycles Suck&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When is the report download page going to be done?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not by the definition in wiki, but defined as the environment by which business determines short term goals in reference to features. Referencing a small block of public-facing functionality without any understanding of the iceberg underneath it does no service to the longevity of the code or the team and shows a lack of technical savvy. Savvy?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the most common form of product life cycles in my experience I find it to be the least beneficial to morale and code quality. Of course every place I have worked has been “agile” really it was just agile in name and then when business wanted something they shoved a feature request at us asking for a button that does X or a report than shows better numbers on an always increasing trend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;business-vision:46b69cc651b36917739e2a1f57a8d295&#34;&gt;Business Vision&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://scotttactical.com/images/clockwork-orange.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Clockwork Orange&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set a clear vision.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make the vision both short and long term.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not pivot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you say that the market has shown people moving toward X so you are going to help the company get there then actually do that. And if six months down the road you pivot and say that product Y is the new focus and that the previous work towards X is halted: well, then you loose leader cred. The market does not change every 6 months. You probably just listened to a pitch guy smooch his way onto your planning team and shine up the buzzword array of glory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;employee-goals:46b69cc651b36917739e2a1f57a8d295&#34;&gt;Employee Goals&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider the employees goals in your vision. If you do not care about the employees&amp;rsquo; goals then they might be setting their own underneath you. We are not all building rockets or curing cancer. Have an idea of what motivates people. When you know your employees then you know how to help them. I tend to define the distinction between leaders and managers as those who take responsibility for those they lead vs those who who only care about pleasing their managers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make an employee goal the production of a quality product. Even if someone is not building rockets they can still have pride in something. If they are building crap however no one wants to tell their family about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;hire-the-right-people:46b69cc651b36917739e2a1f57a8d295&#34;&gt;Hire the Right People&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Hire people smarter than you and get out of their way. - Multiple References
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have written a little bit on the aspects of hiring technology employees. This is extremely important. You have not studied and worked 20 years in the engineering field so there is no way to teach you how to think like us. That is a separate skill. Just because you can drive your car and change the oil does not mean you can engineer a better motor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;test-for-the-love-of-all-that-is-sacred-test:46b69cc651b36917739e2a1f57a8d295&#34;&gt;Test - For the Love of All That is Sacred, Test&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do not have tests your software probably sucks. Or maybe it just works fine and you do not realize that it sucks. Either way it is a nightmare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tests-indemnify-engineers:46b69cc651b36917739e2a1f57a8d295&#34;&gt;Tests Indemnify Engineers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Engineers who have a broad and covering set of tests can enjoy the weekend knowing that new features probably will not break existing functionality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, after every release the business managers will suspect any drop in traffic or margin to be associated to some change made by the engineering team. If there are no test cases covering anything then it is likely the engineers did break something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;wide-coverage-is-safety:46b69cc651b36917739e2a1f57a8d295&#34;&gt;Wide Coverage Is Safety&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have enough coverage so that coverage is a business requirement.  If there is no coverage at all on a 2 year old application then there is not much case for starting to create tests.  You probably should not be working there anyway, unless you have upside.  If however, most of the application is covered in a test then adding functionality without tests because businesses moved deadlines up sets onus back onto business for allocating resources for test writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine this conversation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Biz Guy - &amp;ldquo;The super widget functionality I had you put in there last month is not working. What did you guys break?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Programmer - &amp;ldquo;All tests are passing. I am looking and there are no tests covering any business requirements for such a feature. If you want we can take a look and write a test that covers this feature.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;know-your-tests:46b69cc651b36917739e2a1f57a8d295&#34;&gt;Know Your Tests&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Business should know as much about tests as &amp;ldquo;features&amp;rdquo;. Granted if the user base does not care about quality then tests do not matter much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion:46b69cc651b36917739e2a1f57a8d295&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go forth and create good things.
Then give back to the world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Why Conservatism Fails</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/why-conservatism-fails</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2015 17:18:43 PST</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/why-conservatism-fails</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;This essay is not an attack on the people who claim membership to a philosophical outlook, but an exposition on the inherent difficulties which exist in maintaining traditional systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let us begin with the needful: &lt;em&gt;term definition&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;term-definition:83be2de4f953a80cbb055699f5405f84&#34;&gt;Term Definition&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conservatism&#34; title=&#34;Conservatism&#34;&gt;Conservatism&lt;/a&gt; as a political and social philosophy promotes retaining traditional social institutions in the context of the culture and civilization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the definition found at &lt;em&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/em&gt; and I find it to be a pretty good summation of the idea. Conservatives are those who hold the belief that there is value in the current institutions and that change will have negative effect on the systems of value that the previous generations have passed forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;tradition:83be2de4f953a80cbb055699f5405f84&#34;&gt;Tradition&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tradition&lt;/strong&gt; is the central artifact standing trial with the conservative attitude being its defender. Traditions are the cultural habits and values that are passed forward from generation to generation. They internally contain the characteristics and identity of the people who pass them forward. Not in form, but in essence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;neoconservatism:83be2de4f953a80cbb055699f5405f84&#34;&gt;Neoconservatism&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neoconservatism&lt;/strong&gt; is a relatively new term and also did not come with a clear definition. In short this term describes a political label over those who are best described as aristocratically focused and would tend to be both fascist and progressive at the same time. I will dive a little deeper into that term at another time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;paleoconservatism:83be2de4f953a80cbb055699f5405f84&#34;&gt;Paleoconservatism&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paleoconservatism&#34; title=&#34;Paleoconservatism&#34;&gt;Paleoconservatism&lt;/a&gt; (sometimes shortened to paleocon) is a conservative political philosophy found primarily in the United States stressing tradition, limited government, civil society, anti-colonialism and anti-federalism, along with religious, regional, national and Western identity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This also is a newer term, but is embedded with metadata concerning the context by which the term resolves. It asserts through its prefix that it is of ancient origin. Because most are incapable of looking back before the start of the country I suppose it will suffice to say that the American Revolution will pass as ancient for this essay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;liberalism:83be2de4f953a80cbb055699f5405f84&#34;&gt;Liberalism&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Liberalism&#34; title=&#34;Liberalism&#34;&gt;Liberalism&lt;/a&gt; is a political philosophy or worldview founded on ideas of liberty (which is especially stressed in classical liberalism) and equality (which is more evident in social liberalism). Liberals espouse a wide array of views depending on their understanding of these principles, but generally they support ideas such as free and fair elections, civil rights, freedom of the press, freedom of religion, free trade, and private property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the dualists out there I have brought in the scabby nemesis into the fray. Also taken from Wikipedia, this definition does alright in expressing how liberalism is sold to the public. I will leave this as it is for now and expand on what liberals are sold and what they tend to believe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;progressivism:83be2de4f953a80cbb055699f5405f84&#34;&gt;Progressivism&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Progressivism&#34; title=&#34;Progressivism&#34;&gt;Progressivism&lt;/a&gt; is a broad philosophy based on the Idea of Progress, which asserts that advancement in science, technology, economic development, and social organization are vital to improve the human condition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;humanism:83be2de4f953a80cbb055699f5405f84&#34;&gt;Humanism&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Humanism&#34; title=&#34;Humanism&#34;&gt;Humanism&lt;/a&gt; is a philosophical and ethical stance that emphasizes the value and agency of human beings, individually and collectively, and generally prefers critical thinking and evidence (rationalism, empiricism) over established doctrine or faith (fideism).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;transhumanism:83be2de4f953a80cbb055699f5405f84&#34;&gt;Transhumanism&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transhumanism&#34; title=&#34;Transhumanism&#34;&gt;Transhumanism&lt;/a&gt; (abbreviated as H+ or h+) is an international cultural and intellectual movement with an eventual goal of fundamentally transforming the human condition by developing and making widely available technologies to greatly enhance human intellectual, physical, and psychological capacities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though most leftish people think they are liberals, they are actually progressives who are branded by the humanist or post humanist methods of thinking. They intend to move forward by collectively working to remove those things which they believe stand in the way of their ultimate vision of life. Many conservatives are progressive. Most people in the west hold a humanist ethos.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://scotttactical.com/images/Akropolis_by_Leo_von_Klenze.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Republic, Athens, Akropolis&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Back to the premise.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One is either moving forward or backward but never standing still. - M0Z&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;time:83be2de4f953a80cbb055699f5405f84&#34;&gt;Time&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To start off conservatives are already at a disadvantage. Humans do not normally think in the way that nature acts. We are not people who understand cycles and waves. We think linear. In our mind everything is drawn across a line of time, and that time is always moving forward. We mark every event on that time line: births, weddings, deaths, world events, natural events. They are all scored into a block of the calendar. This is a phenomenon that is only growing stronger for modern humans but did not exist for the first humans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because nearly all are incapable of seeing the world in any way other way than based on time we must set political systems on a timeline. They are created by humans and are imbedded with the same human traits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They are always changing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They are always dying.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They are always imbued with imperfections and logical fallacies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They are emotional.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;emotion:83be2de4f953a80cbb055699f5405f84&#34;&gt;Emotion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humans are reflexive as opposed to instinctive. We are not capable of being instinctive the way animals are when decisions become more critical. When we are born we are helpless. As infants we are the most helpless animal by a massive margin. It takes massive amounts of care to keep a child alive. They don&amp;rsquo;t get up and hop around like a baby dear or swim away like a new tadpole. They must be taught how to live. The reward and punishment for choices comes in the form of physical and psychological reactions - pains and pleasures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pain and pleasure are time-based artifacts of the “human condition”. They are capsules of identity stored in memories: experience. They are happening in the present and do not exist in either the future or the past. It is their memory that will be used to make choices regarding our predictions of the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stronger memories are the ones of past pains therefore most choices for the future will be made so that the effects of the past are not felt rather than to preserve the joys of previous situations. Of the greatest earthly pleasures, there are none nearly as extreme as the greatest human pains. All the joy of being stupid and young are easily traded after a single major accident. To add, humans have learned over time how to take the level of human suffering to impressive heights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When regarding the future most are optimists, loss of promised pleasure is the dominant choice basis rather than the risk of pain (if we can just fix people). Even pessimists act like they are hopeful. When we see the future we see pleasure. Fear of this loss is the factor at hand and people will do whatever it takes to remove the risk to this promised pleasure state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among us there is a small minority which will accurately calculate risks based on past evidence. They understand that pain always happens, happens rarely, and is never as bad as we remember. They quantify it. This is why those smart people sell insurance to those masses of emotional people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People are actively “insuring” their future pleasure. No one buys risk reduction on their health or property or they would just be told to stop doing as much. That is counter to a lifestyle choice. We commute to gain the pleasures money will buy and will actively take a riskier position if offered for more gain. Buckling up has to be forced by law, and not because we want people to live, but because it costs the system when they don&amp;rsquo;t which in turn effects social insurance. People don&amp;rsquo;t reduce threats by buckling up, they insure against the fear of the lost of the current state. People think of all the lost plans, being cut off too short, inability to work, losing the opportunity to spend time with family. I know it sounds like pain avoidance, but there is a fine distinction here. They feel imaginary pain when they mentally put themselves in that state, but it is entirely relative to the proposed pleasure they are thinking about losing. If someone has nothing to lose then they have nothing to fear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the emotional/pain argument against tradition then? We had so much pain in the past which the previous systems failed to avert. We have a promise of this new level of pleasure in the future if the past system will die off and cease its restrictions. The glue of the present is that of a multitude of examples of pleasure in instant gratification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The emotional inclinations against tradition are overwhelming. As we edge away from analysis and tend toward reflex we will abandon previous systems unless they specifically are designed to preserve themselves inside this fear based emotion cloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;ambition:83be2de4f953a80cbb055699f5405f84&#34;&gt;Ambition&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So where are we going with this? Once you know how to control the emotion based decisions of the population, you can control their decision making process. They are going to want to change to pay for the pains of the past and they want change so they can enjoy the future pleasures that the past never offered them. Ambitious people will use this characteristic of society to get ahead. In order to succeed they must upset the system and promote volatility and then move themselves up in the openings. Maintenance of the system is a maintenance of order. Chaos is opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most are materialists. Most see the world in terms of numbers. Nothing is real that is not quantifiable. Skeptics will not accept dogma simply because people believe it. Modern people want more things and are going to fight each other for it. Just because&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Returning to the ratio of insurance seller to the risk seller; the analytical are always in the minority which is why aristocracies, monarchies, republics, and dictatorships try to keep order in the system by reducing the decision making process to the few. Empires, democracies and collectivist systems tend use mass emotion to power chaotic change by which an even smaller number of men can move themselves up to the tops of ultimate power. The mob will not suffer a quiet aristocracy but will indulge a charismatic demagogue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In chaos the recipe for political success is simple. In order to power emotional change simply highlight the pains of the past and talk about the glories future. If you look at the marketing campaigns of the various political systems you can start to see what ideologies they represent. If change is coming there is usually only a few major players behind it and they are ambitious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;maintenance:83be2de4f953a80cbb055699f5405f84&#34;&gt;Maintenance&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Systems are like people and machines. They do not keep running without constant effort. It is easy to feed the ambitious man power. It is easy to sit and watch things break down. The maintenance of responsibility is the preservation of power. When a man abdicates his responsibility he transfers his power to those who are born with an ambition and a hunger for material improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maintenance is an activity. It is not a state. Even if a vehicle is never driven it must actively be maintained or it will very quickly be taken back by nature. Humans build a material world like themselves: born to decay. There is nothing that humans build with their hands that will be around forever. Nuclear waste will certainly be here for the next few billion years but even that has a half-life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;context:83be2de4f953a80cbb055699f5405f84&#34;&gt;Context&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An inherent disadvantage conservatism has is it is a system without context built into its fabric. Simply put conservatism simply conserves. It conserves what? And even less obvious is &amp;lsquo;why&amp;rsquo;. As listed above the paleoconservative tries to elude to original or classic US Judeo/Christian tradition. The reason and history behind a tradition is rarely built into the tradition itself. It is an activity or institution that lives isolated from the human meta-narrative that wove it into the fabric of the culture. The older the tradition the more complex the history and the more difficult the task of maintain the reason for the tradition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traditions are either living and growing or corrupting and dying. Like sunshine to plants, context is the essential sustaining ingredient for tradition. You can&amp;rsquo;t see sunshine, but you know when it&amp;rsquo;s missing because you can&amp;rsquo;t see anything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is important for the progressive to draw pain and pleasure elements isolation. The story of the civil rights violation or the repression of a future illegitimate sexual encounter. Once isolated they can be seen in a raw form that is and must be purely emotional. This is trivial, but effective. Context is something that forces the mind to stage the emotion as a byproduct of many series of choices. The further back one goes the closer they get to the truth of the situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It requires removing context for liberals to have any chance at showcasing egalitarianism. Equality is a logical fallacy first off. It does not exist in nature and is entirely a human construct. It exists only in math and philosophy. Liberals believe that they can force it however. That means placing everyone into context-free individual abstract identities unrelated to time or place. Each must be identical because they are all different in the exact same way. It is a self-defeating system, but it appeals to those who have an existential view of the world.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://scotttactical.com/images/babylon.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;iBabylon&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h3 id=&#34;progressive-humanists-ph:83be2de4f953a80cbb055699f5405f84&#34;&gt;Progressive Humanists – PH+&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They always said to be Ph balanced. Are PhD students deficient? Ok enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Liberals simply opened the door for progressivism and humanism. Once free to choose their future, people chose to surpass their limited confines, throwing off authority and bonds of tradition. The reasoning became that since we were capable of improving ourselves this far with the help of science and reason that we will be capable of improving indefinitely. If we keep improving eventually we will surpass humanity and in the true voice of Nietzsche we will birth the superman. Free of guilt and open to pleasure. Limitless. Babylonian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tool of the humanist is scientific discovery. The default view is skepticism of systems past and optimism in systems future. The phrase “new research has shown that&amp;hellip;” is a calling of hope for all of those who internally disliked something of the previous “research”. Scientific discovery finds new ways of doing things, and by its critical nature, will naturally destroy (older) systems in favor of more efficient systems. It removes the unnecessary by chipping away context-poor bricks in traditions&amp;rsquo; wall of protection. By keeping a critical nature to all they provide just the thinnest filter against all arguments while they build their own cases of argumentum ad populum, verbosium, hominem, nauseam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The offensive stance that the progressive takes against the defensive traditionalist is a formidable one. Scientism simply has to show its achievements and ask what forms of pleasure the tradition will offer. It rarely does have any comfort to offer and instead will talk about fallen man. It goes against nearly all of the visible evidence when taken at first glimpse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the humanist the early humans were ape-like. We are obviously beyond that. To the Christians the early humans were simply what they are today but without clothes. Many Christians are Darwinian. Most have very little if any capacity for scientific dialog. The church leaders bicker about minutiae and can&amp;rsquo;t get their PR campaigns straight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Funding for research and development from any religious institution is relatively nonexistent so they have little to contribute as a body to a society that places so much value on the improvement of the species and its capabilities. Most scientists are atheistic or agnostic therefore the sheer amount of rhetoric that can be produced is staggering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why are we showing science against religion again? Because it is progress versus tradition. The conservatives who are proponents of unbridled development and research are in the same category as the liberal transhumanists. They simply pick different fields: war, oil, machinery, monolithic business. Faster, bigger, louder. There really isn&amp;rsquo;t much difference in the actions and habits of conservatives and other groups of people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;money:83be2de4f953a80cbb055699f5405f84&#34;&gt;Money&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The topic of money and the different philosophies seems to be begging to be made. It is beyond the scope of this document however. What this paragraph will do is simply provide some interesting misconceptions about the groups. This is less about the conservative philosophical attributes and more about the people who attribute themselves to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conservatives and the political right wing groups are not the big money people in the US national and state elections. The heavy hitters are on the left. They overwhelmingly dominate the political funding. The right is very poor at managing this obvious PR failure. It also illuminates a serious flaw in the ability for the conservative to care about anything but their own personal well-being. Most of the well funded progressive groups are designed to further the progressive agenda. They fund workers unions, political action groups, educational groups. The right just fund their consumeristic enablers: big business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Big business is not intrinsically anything but pragmatic. The liberals are more sophisticated shoppers while the conservatives simply tend to be price shoppers. Therefore lower quality items go to the conservative and over time render them weaker due to poor short term investments. Conservatives generally identify with Wal-Mart, Budweiser, and Exxon. Cultural strip mining.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Liberals are heavily vested in the system. They tend to have a better outlook on the social systems of course. They save less for retirement and put more money towards education for their and their children. Conservatives are inverse of this. It isn&amp;rsquo;t a huge gap, but it makes sense. This is an intrinsic condition of the system that helps to dictate people&amp;rsquo;s habits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The American Dream is probably the least beneficial condition the conservative American holds. Some idealistic picture of how the world can be because they saw it purportedly based on a Norman Rockwell painting with the words “Work hard and you will succeed” painted over the door of their brand new baby blue bungalow. It is naive considering that both political parties financed themselves out past their great grandchildren to the tune of about $100T as of last guess. The fiscal intelligence of all but the smartest of either groups is laughable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conservatives tend to align with some Austrian systems while liberals align with Keynesian. In this case conservatism has an advantage. They are allowing money to be set up for the thing it is designed to do: encourage commerce. It is strange that they aren&amp;rsquo;t better at using it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, every dollar spent is a vote. If conservatives chose to sponsor liberals by buying their products they will continue to transfer funds to a competitive political group. You will eventually lose. This purchasing habit is probably the most important factor in the loss of power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;industrial-war-machine:83be2de4f953a80cbb055699f5405f84&#34;&gt;Industrial War Machine&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to include a military topic, but I cannot say why the military is intrinsically for or against conservatism. It is definitely their baby. One that will grow to leave them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What Machiavelli clearly shows in his works holds true. The early military will be of the high citizen class. Land owners. Influential people. As time goes on it will gradually be filled with lower class people. Non-citizens will be allowed, then brigands, then foreign-born soldiers, then foreign armies. Eventually it will be a mercenary force. What are the implications of our military&amp;rsquo;s state. Most men are tattooed up like pagan scallywags. This is new. Sexual deviants are the norm rather than exception. Feminists fill the middle ranks. Many of the soldiers are foreigners. A conservative military protects the culture and as such protects its tradition and way of life. A staing military in a collectivist system will be used against the citizenry. Politicians will use concepts such as the declaration of war on an abstract idea or material object. The people who are representative of that idea are the enemy. The war on drugs, terror, pollution, hunger. Someone would put in a nut house if they declared war on any inanimate object, but if the government does it people go along as if it makes sense. “Today we declare war on swimming pools. The adults who harbor pools and endanger their neighbors&amp;rsquo; children will be put to death. If we simply kill enough pool owners there wont be any more drowned children.” A standing army is antagonist to progress.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://scotttactical.com/images/Marcus_Porcius_Cato.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Marcu Porcius Cato&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion:83be2de4f953a80cbb055699f5405f84&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cato is seen (by me) as the grandfather of modern conservatism. It seems as though the romance of the republic is enough to draw out the glory of the greatest men in her protection. As in all things a plastic rose is not as beautiful as the real thing. Budding. Growing to bloom. Radiating for a time. Withering. Then casting its pedals to the ground. But behind that flower is the seed of the innumerable new blooms. They will have to be brought forward and planted. Either by nature, insect, animal or man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conservatism is only an outlook. A backward facing one. It must be illuminated with the history that bore it and there must be strong men who are tasked with its defense. The identity of the society depends on the forward propagation of the institutions that protect the philosophies of a culture. It is imperative that no veil be placed over the truth of these things. True and complete knowledge with an aggressive active defense is the only thing that will keep history. Not in myth, but in form. Drawn forward in an ark. Sealed for the next great breed of men to collect in a small basilica and discuss fascinating works about the human spirit and contemplate the implementation of principles spoken thousands of years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like Athens, Carthage, Rome, and all the greats before us we are at the end of the Republic. The seed is there however. Brilliant men have come before us and shown us what may be grown if given the proper philosophy. For now the statues of the old republic will sit cooled under the shadow of the new empire.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Eat For War</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/post/eat-for-war/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2015 01:23:11 PST</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/post/eat-for-war/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bad men live that they may eat and drink, whereas good men eat and drink that they may live. Socrates - Plutarch, &lt;em&gt;How a Young Man Ought to Hear Poems&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-warrior-s-diet:62a5d67ac0510a562f183297b71bac75&#34;&gt;A Warrior&amp;rsquo;s Diet&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What physically intimate activity do we participate in more than any other?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eating&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-philosophy:62a5d67ac0510a562f183297b71bac75&#34;&gt;The Philosophy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the more immediate steps in becoming awake is overcoming the omnivore&amp;rsquo;s dilemma. The &lt;em&gt;passion of hunger&lt;/em&gt;. We take other living things into our bodies and literally become one with them. Most religions incorporate some form of consumption into their ritual. It is part of every culture and one of those most important glues in uniting various traditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Food is religion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Food is health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Food is life and death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;tl-dr:62a5d67ac0510a562f183297b71bac75&#34;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your diet is a long term wager that should reflect your ultimate goals and ethos. The outcome is measured over years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-are-what-we-eat:62a5d67ac0510a562f183297b71bac75&#34;&gt;We Are What We Eat&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every part of your body including your mind is effected by what you do and do not consume. Eating an unhealthy diet will slow the cognitive abilities of the warrior and leave him sluggish to think. Consuming large amounts of meat will draw the blood away from the brain and cause it to be used to processes a higher than necessary amount of flesh. Processed sugars will spike glucose and cause the mind to race and then crash leaving a less than desirable concentration peak. Too few vegetables causes the body to crave more of various foods that if not satisfied and in turn substituted with inadequate foods will leave the body overweight and diseased. Buying food of lower quality that is laden with petrochemicals and heavy metals will cause the immune system to weaken and make the body vulnerable to any number of diseases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again it is advantageous to think in the mind of our enemy. He is able to gain an upper hand by strategically supplying his enemy with high calorie low value and nutritionally wasted food. Even better he can cause the immune system of his enemy to be weakened so that a biological attack is possible. If the mind of the opponent can be made saturated with metals there opens a whole range of psychological attacks aimed at unbalancing the hormones of the body. Once our enemy can control just one of the emotions he can alter just about every other action and you are no longer valuable as a soldier except as fodder. It is simple in this age and not at all fantastic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://scotttactical.com/images/lion-buffalo.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Buffalo Bests Lion&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NOTE&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you wish to attack these assertions do so knowing you are wagering your own body, and it is likely that I am physically above you in the food chain already. Be grateful for the constructs of society. This is philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;agriculture:62a5d67ac0510a562f183297b71bac75&#34;&gt;Agriculture&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The closer to the earth you go the closer to life you will be. Generally the more times something is processed the less densely nutritional it will be for you and at some level may be harmful. Taking milk directly from the cow will inherit all those beneficial enzymes that we have accustomed our bodies to over the last few millennium. Pasteurized and ultra-pasteurized milk has been killed essentially. Also add the fact that highly processed diary has biological system altering antibiotic and hormonal additive levels in it. Foods that are highly processed corn byproducts are terrible for the mind and the body as well as damaging to the economy and feed the industrial war machine. High fructose corn syrup HFCS is the diseased blood of our flat lands. It should be boxed up and shipped to the front doors of our enemy in the sweetest form it can take.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strategy against terror states: Americanize their foodchain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The older in the anthropological food chain you go the easier it is for you body to digest. It is unrealistic that humans were carnivores. We are omnivores and a special kind: one that does not inherit instincts as the animals do. We are dissimilar to every animal in nearly every decision we make and food is no difference. It took the institution of tradition to pass along the various things we learned about: what to eat and what not to. Culture defined the combinations and quantities of those things. The post pseudo-cosmopolitanism of the United States set the table for a feast to forsake Epicurus. We were determined to eat in our cars while driving. And now we are the wasteline [sic] of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;invest-in-food-nutrition:62a5d67ac0510a562f183297b71bac75&#34;&gt;Invest In Food (Nutrition)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contributing to the agricultural infrastructure is the one tactic a society can have that will always have positive effects and those which are greater than any other civil infrastructure including education and medicine. &amp;ldquo;Smart&amp;rdquo; folks think that their potential is limitless and are the pinnacle of human development, but without healthy hardened people to support their ideas they are slightly above fodder for the incoming armies. Without the productive classes they would starve out with haste and lose all their wives and children to those who can produce food. It is only in these highly critical states of systems that people who are weaker are able to float the top. The greatest part of history is supported by those who are of hearty healthy stock. Farming is not dumb work and it takes a lifetime to simply keep up with the land.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Environmentalists will agree with these topics on some level. Or should. Simply changing our agricultural strategies would do more for the environment than taking all the cars off the road. It is the right solution to many of our problems. When someone asks &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;but what can I do&amp;rdquo; there is a very simple solution. Give something back to the earth. It raised us and nursed us and all we do is act like spoiled children and take take take.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earth is our first Mother.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Man&amp;rsquo;s first job was farming. It should be each man&amp;rsquo;s responsibility to understand how to manage and grow his own food and what it takes to produce food. Our task is to toil. The goal of progress should not be to remove work. It should be to make our lives better and if we sit around like fat slobs our life is in no way better. That will only emphasize the trivial problems in our lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;masculine-hunger:62a5d67ac0510a562f183297b71bac75&#34;&gt;Masculine Hunger&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t have bigger balls or thicker chest hairs if you consume a ton of read meat each day. That is not biologically sound and is likely fear-based peer pressure feeding on an underdeveloped level of sexual maturity. In fact you might have to get your colon scraped out because you caused internal problems by forcing too much of the wrong substance into it. Putting your body&amp;rsquo;s Ph level off into the acidic side will increase your chances of cancer and that might just claim one of those huge nuts you are growing. Moderation is key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Listening to your body and maintaining a proper diet that is balanced by nature will increase those things which men need to thrive. Alkaline foods are going to put your body into a state that promotes optimal performance and will in turn stimulate everything to run in peak performance. There is very simple science to back up these decisions and it does not require validation of a fad diet. Sure you can do things that throw your body into a state of ketosis and cause the fat to come off fast but you are increasing your acid levels and causing your metabolism to ramp up. Learn biology and think for yourself. The last part is discipline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;aesthetics-health-vanity:62a5d67ac0510a562f183297b71bac75&#34;&gt;Aesthetics, Health, Vanity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is some validity in the idea that big muscular dudes get the girls. It&amp;rsquo;s nature. A woman wants a man that is going to be capable of giving her a child with the best chances of survival. A fat or broken man is going to have far fewer options when being selected. Within a few seconds of viewing a man it is possible for her to tell whether this person is above or below average in health, strength, social value, and whether he is dominant or passive. These are primal characteristics, but how do they relate to this? They weren&amp;rsquo;t designed simply for the attraction of the other mate, but to bring glory back to God. The ultimate designer. Does someone who cannot tend their own body bring pride to anyone?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do not want people around us who cannot control their lives. Their diet is important to control and where vanity might be a good motivator it is easy to make this vice into a virtue. Eating well will grow our bodies into structures that are desirable to women, ourselves. At the end of our lives we should not necessarily turn in a pretty corpse but one that was driven so hard that the wheels fell off of it as it was being pulled into the garage. What keeps this from being vanity is &lt;em&gt;purpose&lt;/em&gt;. It is because we get more miles on a fit healthy body that we find joy in what we have sculpted. True joy. Not transient chemical happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember, bodies are made in the kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;prayer-fasting-charity:62a5d67ac0510a562f183297b71bac75&#34;&gt;Prayer, Fasting, Charity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://scotttactical.com/images/warrior-meditation.png&#34; alt=&#34;Warrior Meditation and the Path to Enlightenment&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three things, my brethren, by which faith stands firm, devotion remains constant, and virtue endures. They are prayer, fasting and mercy. Prayer knocks at the door, fasting obtains, mercy receives. Prayer, mercy and fasting: these three are one, and they give life to each other. Saint Peter Chrysologus&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is where we get down to the real &amp;ldquo;meat&amp;rdquo; of the topic and with real scientific evidence to back this up. Your primal urges must be subdued regularly if you wish to elevate yourself. No, it will not hurt you. If it does you might be mentally or physically too weak to handle this program. What it will do is open your mind. Gandhi did it. Christ did it. Muhammad did it. The prophets did it. This is a must and should be incorporated into any leadership system. There are very few ways that we can unlock this deep primal part of our brains. If you have not been truly starving then you have not made yourself available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cattle-and-sheeple:62a5d67ac0510a562f183297b71bac75&#34;&gt;Cattle and Sheeple&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anthropologically we are not grazing animals. We are more appropriately scavengers and in some situations hunters. We are opportunists by nature. Humans were not found grazing on the range all day. These diets of eating many times in a day are just setting people up to be slaughter animals. Severely restricting the body will put us into a state of survival which releases all sorts of amazing hormones into the body. Our minds and bodies work at a higher operational level when in this state. It is exactly opposite of what most would think. In this hedonistic social paradigm we live in this is yet another anti-truism of common intuition. The only scientifically proven method of prolonging life is caloric restriction. If a longer life is a measure of health then there is no better credibility in this system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;myth-butters:62a5d67ac0510a562f183297b71bac75&#34;&gt;Myth-Butters&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glutin.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Apparently France didn&amp;rsquo;t get the memo that they should be dying or morbidly obese. Research &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coeliac_disease&#34; title=&#34;Celiac Disease&#34;&gt;Celiac Disease&lt;/a&gt; please. Odds are you don&amp;rsquo;t have it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supplements are (bad|good)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Please, again do your own research and find out what you need to actually supplement. Our agricultural system is in a bad way so there are probably things you need to get more of that you may supplement to get you where you need to be, but it wont make up for being lazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fat is Bad&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Being fat is bad. Eating it isn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily bad. Listen to your body and make wise decisions. Another fad pushed by the US health industry that threw our whole dietary development into the fan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;cornclusion:62a5d67ac0510a562f183297b71bac75&#34;&gt;Cornclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, it is up to you to determine what to eat and your decisions must be well researched and implemented. Once the best meals are put into place they need to be cast solid by repetition and then turned into a habit. Eventually they may become tradition and if enough of us pass these good habits forward they may become a cultural improvement that we can be proud of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;=st=&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>PHPunit Slowness Performance Suggestions</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/performance-suggestions-phpunit-slowness</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2015 12:57:42 PST</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/performance-suggestions-phpunit-slowness</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;phpunit-is-slowness:d306273837598a7a2a686add086bab85&#34;&gt;PHPUnit Is Slowness&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love &lt;a href=&#34;https://phpunit.de/&#34;&gt;PHPUnit&lt;/a&gt; don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong. More than a testing library, I like testing, or having tests. It&amp;rsquo;s like the code got yo back bro! Build code that lasts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;EDIT&lt;/em&gt;: I know most of the problems are inherent with tests not the testing framework.  However, my requirements dictate how I use it to a certain extent.  Peace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;phpunit-is-painfully-slow:d306273837598a7a2a686add086bab85&#34;&gt;PHPUnit is painfully slow.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://scotttactical.com/images/turtle-speed.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;PHPUnit Is Slow&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seriously. Though. Maybe having a concurrent environment it can run it would help. I worked at a place with 65,000 unit tests and if they ran as slow as our unit tests here it would never finish. It was literally taking 30-60 seconds per test. That is 65000 x 60 = 1083 hours or 45 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For reference the 41 year old &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2015/07/13/422610986/ultramarathoner-finishes-the-appalachian-trail-in-record-time&#34;&gt;Scott Jurek&lt;/a&gt; can walk the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nps.gov/appa/index.htm&#34;&gt;2000+ mile Appalachian Trail&lt;/a&gt; in 45 days. Single threaded of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-is-phpunit-anti-performant:d306273837598a7a2a686add086bab85&#34;&gt;Why is PHPUnit Anti-Performant&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some thing that are inherent to unit tests that make them slow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tests are usually not well encapsulated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many tests aren&amp;rsquo;t true unit tests - @see integration tests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Databases must be built and destroyed for every test&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Connections from local systems are slow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Writing to file on a local system is slow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generating reports is intensive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;strategies:d306273837598a7a2a686add086bab85&#34;&gt;Strategies&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sqlite-in-memory:d306273837598a7a2a686add086bab85&#34;&gt;SQLite - In Memory&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://scotttactical.com/images/sqlite.gif&#34; alt=&#34;SQLite&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Switch to an in-memory database. Even if you have SSD drives its going to be slow. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sqlite.org/&#34;&gt;SQLite&lt;/a&gt; is on OS X out of the box I am fairly sure and comes with most &amp;lsquo;nix flavors. Considering they embed it all over the place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting up Laravel it would be something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-php&#34;&gt;
&#39;sqlite&#39; =&amp;gt; [
    &#39;driver&#39;   =&amp;gt; &#39;sqlite&#39;,
//  &#39;database&#39; =&amp;gt; storage_path().&#39;/database.sqlite&#39;,
    &#39;database&#39; =&amp;gt; &#39;:memory:&#39;,
    &#39;prefix&#39;   =&amp;gt; &#39;&#39;,
],
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just comment out the hard path.
Then add a record for the drive in your phpunit.xml
I also like to make sure my host is set to not kill anything. I have wiped out a dev database or two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-xml&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;env name=&amp;quot;DATABASE_DRIVER&amp;quot; value=&amp;quot;sqlite&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;env name=&amp;quot;DB_HOST&amp;quot; value=&amp;quot;NO&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;database-sometimes:d306273837598a7a2a686add086bab85&#34;&gt;Database - Sometimes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have two base test cases that I use for almost everything. One that wraps up Laravel or the big framework I&amp;rsquo;m messing with or one that will just extend phpunit by itself.  It might even be better to have data groups into domains so that when you are running a group of tests that it only loads up those tables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have a couple hundred tests. Not much.  But it takes 2-5 seconds to load up all the data. That adds up to minutes.  Can&amp;rsquo;t handle that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;grouping-test-suites:d306273837598a7a2a686add086bab85&#34;&gt;Grouping Test Suites&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have the ability to group your tests. I always have my developers add docblocks such as below so that PHPUnit will know how to group thing. The fields that I want them to use are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@author - for running all mine or someone&amp;rsquo;s tests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@group - I have them just put the package in this place&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;@namespace - I think this works&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-php&#34;&gt;
/**
 *
 * @author solvire &amp;lt;stevenjscott@gmail.com&amp;gt;
 * @package Rules
 * @group Rules
 * @namespace LeadFerret\Lib\Rules
 */
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Running &lt;code&gt;./vendor/bin/phpunit --list-groups&lt;/code&gt; will give you an idea of what groups you can run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;./vendor/bin/phpunit --list-groups
PHPUnit 4.8.16 by Sebastian Bergmann and contributors.

Available test group(s):
 - API
 - Models
 - Rules
 - Transformers
 - default
 - solvire &amp;lt;stevenjscott@gmail.com&amp;gt;

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;filter-your-tests:d306273837598a7a2a686add086bab85&#34;&gt;Filter Your Tests&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Run only the tests you need. Sometimes I&amp;rsquo;m working with a class and I want to keep running that class.  Just filter by the test class name:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;./vendor/bin/phpunit --filter=&amp;quot;testValidateTrustedCanModifyCompany&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make your test names interesting camel cases. If you run testdox it comes out easier to read:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;./vendor/bin/phpunit --filter=&amp;quot;testValidateTrustedCanModifyCompany&amp;quot; --testdox
PHPUnit 4.8.16 by Sebastian Bergmann and contributors.

LeadFerret\Lib\Rules\CompanyModifyRuleProvider
 [x] Validate trusted can modify company

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;turn-off-code-coverage:d306273837598a7a2a686add086bab85&#34;&gt;Turn Off Code Coverage&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t always have to run code coverage reports. In fact probably only before a deployment. Either you really love to see code coverage or you hate dealing with unit tests.  Doesn&amp;rsquo;t really seem to be much between.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;performance-tests:d306273837598a7a2a686add086bab85&#34;&gt;Performance Tests&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difference was so staggering I that I was totally irritated I didn&amp;rsquo;t find this sooner. I was even getting in trying to debug at the lower code level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;./vendor/bin/phpunit --filter=&amp;quot;testValidateTrustedCanModifyCompany&amp;quot; --no-coverage
PHPUnit 4.8.16 by Sebastian Bergmann and contributors.
.
Time: 3.98 seconds, Memory: 35.25Mb
OK (1 test, 2 assertions)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And with coverage:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;./vendor/bin/phpunit --filter=&amp;quot;testValidateTrustedCanModifyCompany&amp;quot;
PHPUnit 4.8.16 by Sebastian Bergmann and contributors.
.
Time: 48.54 seconds, Memory: 46.75Mb
OK (1 test, 2 assertions)
Generating code coverage report in HTML format ... done
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FASTER!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;javascript-for-the-assist:d306273837598a7a2a686add086bab85&#34;&gt;JavaScript For The Assist&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://scotttactical.com/images/gulp.png&#34; alt=&#34;GulpJS&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have been toying with using &lt;a href=&#34;http://gulpjs.com/&#34;&gt;Gulp&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.npmjs.com/&#34;&gt;NPM&lt;/a&gt; for setting up a better workflow.  It is simple enough that once a file is saved that scripts can kick off the appropriate unit tests. If your tests are completing in less than a couple seconds then it doesn&amp;rsquo;t hurt to keep running them. If they break you may know it sooner.  This is also helpful for those people who refuse to use a full-featured IDE.  Probably also the same people that enjoy working on javascript in the dark.  I know who you are. O.o&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion:d306273837598a7a2a686add086bab85&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life is much better now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Test-driven development is a great way to go about things.  I highly suggest it. It makes your life easier in the long run and your credibility as an engineer is safer when you aren&amp;rsquo;t worried about whether you are going to break things. If you automate the process and provide cool reports with graphs then you can build a friendly rivalry based on coverage rights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Build Quality Software&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Engineer; Don&amp;rsquo;t Hack&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;=st=&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Deploying Hugo the Golang CMS on DigitalOcean - Nginx</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/deploying-hugo-golang-digitalocean-nginx</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2015 06:29:31 PDT</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/deploying-hugo-golang-digitalocean-nginx</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;deploying-hugo-the-golang-cms-on-digitalocean:05ba16f4d070e50db8ed0ad9d587f7eb&#34;&gt;Deploying Hugo the Golang CMS on DigitalOcean&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;creating-a-droplet:05ba16f4d070e50db8ed0ad9d587f7eb&#34;&gt;Creating a Droplet&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a bit partial to CentOS. The lastest version as of this writing is &lt;em&gt;CentOS Linux release 7.1.1503 (Core)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting up a droplet is always very simple. Just turn it on basically. Upload your ssh keys. Done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;install-nginx:05ba16f4d070e50db8ed0ad9d587f7eb&#34;&gt;Install Nginx&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;add-the-epel-repo:05ba16f4d070e50db8ed0ad9d587f7eb&#34;&gt;Add the epel repo:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;yum install epel-release
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;install:05ba16f4d070e50db8ed0ad9d587f7eb&#34;&gt;Install&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;yum install nginx
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;start-it:05ba16f4d070e50db8ed0ad9d587f7eb&#34;&gt;Start it&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;service nginx start
systemctl enable nginx
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;create-the-folders:05ba16f4d070e50db8ed0ad9d587f7eb&#34;&gt;Create the Folders&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;mkdir -p /var/www/ursite/
chown -R nginx:nginx /var/www
touch /var/www/ursite/index.html - or clone your site
cp /etc/nginx/sites-available/default /etc/nginx/sites-available/ursite
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;configure-nginx:05ba16f4d070e50db8ed0ad9d587f7eb&#34;&gt;Configure nginx&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;open the config file: &lt;code&gt;vim /etc/nginx/conf.d/virtual.conf&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-conf&#34;&gt;#
# A virtual host using mix of IP-, name-, and port-based configuration
#

server {
    listen       80;
    server_name  scotttactical.com;
    server_alias go.scotttactical.com;

    location / {
        root   /var/www/stac/public/;
        index  index.html;
    }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;install-go-hugo:05ba16f4d070e50db8ed0ad9d587f7eb&#34;&gt;Install  Go + Hugo&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;yum install go
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to install from source
Edit your bash script to have the proper variables in place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;yum install git hg
export GOPATH=$HOME/go
go get -v github.com/spf13/hugo
cp $GOPATH/bin/hugo /usr/local/bin/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NOTE: THis actually isn&amp;rsquo;t necessary.  Just check it out and go with it. Afer screwing with it a few minutes I facepalmed&amp;hellip; they are static files. Doh!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Hugo: A replacement for Wordpress</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/hugo-a-replacement-for-wordpress/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2015 15:39:13 PDT</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/hugo-a-replacement-for-wordpress/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;hugo-a-replacement-for-wordpress:af5d620423bd53c36ac9d8e74d1bb8f8&#34;&gt;Hugo: A Replacement for Wordpress&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tl-dr:af5d620423bd53c36ac9d8e74d1bb8f8&#34;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I researched go&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Found Hugo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setup a test&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Migrated my Wordpress instance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Launched DigitalOcean Droplet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deployed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Total time: &lt;em&gt;6 hours&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;continued:af5d620423bd53c36ac9d8e74d1bb8f8&#34;&gt;Continued:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My problems started almost a year before I took up this cause. At the time I only had 2 Wordpress sites. Very very low traffic.  Only a couple users a day.  They were mostly place holders for business sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;wordpress-is-hungry:af5d620423bd53c36ac9d8e74d1bb8f8&#34;&gt;Wordpress is hungry&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What was annoying about the case was that they would randomly &lt;em&gt;carsh&lt;/em&gt;! I realized they were running &lt;em&gt;out of memory&lt;/em&gt;. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t figure out why because I just wouldn&amp;rsquo;t let myself believe that a couple instances of Wordpress were enough to run out of memory. It was an AWS box running with .5GB of memory and some swap space. I can&amp;rsquo;t remember what. Maybe I was just too optimistic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I reimaged the server, installed several performance plugins, cached anything I could, but still it would eat memory like a lonely fat girl at a buffet. Every couple days my monitor would go off telling me the site was down. The monitor wasn&amp;rsquo;t in place immediately because I didn&amp;rsquo;t think I needed one. It was only after the site had been offline for a couple days before I realized that I had to get a monitor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well eventually I decided it just needed more hardware. I went to 1G of memory for the 2 instances. That carshed as well. It was like watching the movie Carsh in slow motion. I added a couple gigs of swap, but then aws started acting funny and it would fill up the memory immediately. I then went to 2G ram and 2G of swap. Still - Carshon Daily show!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;it-s-the-future-already:af5d620423bd53c36ac9d8e74d1bb8f8&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the Future Already&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s 2015. In honor of 2015 and #BackToTheFuture day I am getting over 2000&amp;rsquo;s technology and moving on to something new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Blogs should fast and light&lt;/em&gt; and should be able to run in the fog. Static, and with out short codes. Gawd! And hoverboards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;so-starts-my-late-journey:af5d620423bd53c36ac9d8e74d1bb8f8&#34;&gt;So Starts My (Late) Journey&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-requirements:af5d620423bd53c36ac9d8e74d1bb8f8&#34;&gt;My Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy markup (or markdown)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lite - less than 500M of memory required&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Static (optional but nice)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No DB or a lighter option&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Image manipulation or gallery ease&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple enough a business person can (ha this isn&amp;rsquo;t the future you are looking for)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authentication layers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SEO items

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sitemap&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Metatags&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiple environment friendly (dev/stage/prod)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PERFORMANT fast&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Templates (market)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multi-site management (please?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;languages-prepared-to-flamed:af5d620423bd53c36ac9d8e74d1bb8f8&#34;&gt;Languages - PREPARED TO FLAMED!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PHP - too slow - boring - part of my problem already&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python - Interesting but everyone wants to use django. Kinda heavy for this&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ruby - pretty good but still kinda foreign to me&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go - I wanna learn it but where are the projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Java - swatting at flies with a sledge hammer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scala - eh&amp;hellip; i liked this idea but still too big&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;C++ - Not a masochist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perl - Not unless you say perl in a French accent every time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Node.js - I will not allow JS on my backend, it&amp;rsquo;s unnatural&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given my above list of languages I kinda forced myself into a sector.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;languages-decisions:af5d620423bd53c36ac9d8e74d1bb8f8&#34;&gt;Languages - Decisions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;ruby:af5d620423bd53c36ac9d8e74d1bb8f8&#34;&gt;Ruby&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really liked &lt;a href=&#34;http://jekyllrb.com/docs/home/&#34;&gt;jekyll&lt;/a&gt; and might have gone with it if Ruby wasn&amp;rsquo;t such a foreign concept to me. And I haven&amp;rsquo;t decided if I want to jump in and learn it completely. So not this time gems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;a-shot-at-python:af5d620423bd53c36ac9d8e74d1bb8f8&#34;&gt;A Shot at Python&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a ton of experience with PHP. They are all about the same. They can get okay performance if you cache everything but they are just too heavy. And it&amp;rsquo;s PHP. I&amp;rsquo;m over it. Drupal. Seriously it&amp;rsquo;s 2015. That thing should have died 10 years ago.  Are you still driving your subaru brat?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve used python before and I did give it a good run, but &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.djangoproject.com/&#34;&gt;Django&lt;/a&gt; is just too big IMO. A blog is simple. It needs to stay simple. Plus they are trying to recreate Wordpress in all of its glory. No thanks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be fair to python, I spent a little time going through the implementation of &lt;a href=&#34;http://mezzanine.jupo.org/&#34;&gt;Mezzanine&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.django-cms.org/en/&#34;&gt;Django-CMS&lt;/a&gt;.  Still. Too grande.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;java-et-al:af5d620423bd53c36ac9d8e74d1bb8f8&#34;&gt;Java et al&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have spent time before researching Java and C++ CMS programs. They are probably okay for monolithic enterprises who need some sort of back stroking to know they used a dump truck with a Cadillac interior to go pick up the groceries.  When 500 people will be working on it and you need a 20 step approval process I guess. I digress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;starting-with-go:af5d620423bd53c36ac9d8e74d1bb8f8&#34;&gt;Starting with Go&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok fine. Maybe now&amp;rsquo;s my chance to play with &lt;a href=&#34;https://golang.org/&#34;&gt;Golang&lt;/a&gt;. I was looking for a project for it so let&amp;rsquo;s give this a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far my implementation ideas are:
- roll my own
- wrap up a framework
- use a designed blog framework&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;some-frameworks:af5d620423bd53c36ac9d8e74d1bb8f8&#34;&gt;Some Frameworks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really liked a few of the frameworks, but as time went on I decided to see if I could find something lighter. But for records sake here are the samples I looked at&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://revel.github.io/&#34;&gt;http://revel.github.io/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://beego.me/&#34;&gt;http://beego.me/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://martini.codegangsta.io/&#34;&gt;http://martini.codegangsta.io/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BTW: Martini looked really cool. Light learning curve. I almost went with that, but felt like I could find better features in a purpose built app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-blog-solution:af5d620423bd53c36ac9d8e74d1bb8f8&#34;&gt;A Blog Solution&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After meandering around with the frameworks I felt like I wanted to try something more stripped down. So I looked at micro sites and Hugo &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;https://gohugo.io/&lt;/a&gt; stood out.  I figured I would know in a couple hours if it work work or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;hugo-quick-start:af5d620423bd53c36ac9d8e74d1bb8f8&#34;&gt;Hugo: Quick Start&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installing go is awesome on mac. If you have a mac and do not have &lt;a href=&#34;http://brew.sh/&#34;&gt;homebrew&lt;/a&gt; - shame on you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;brew install go
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installing hugo as awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;brew install hugo
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creating a new site was extremely simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;mkdir newsite
cd newsite
hugo new site .
hugo new about.md
hugo new post/first.md
git clone https://github.com/dim0627/hugo_theme_beg themes/beg
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edit &lt;code&gt;config.yaml&lt;/code&gt; &amp;ndash; see my example
Add &lt;code&gt;theme = &amp;quot;beg&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start the serve:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo server --buildDrafts --watch
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion:af5d620423bd53c36ac9d8e74d1bb8f8&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was very painless. I am kinda surprised. I was a little hesitant to get in here. Setting up virtual hosts and getting the code out there wasn&amp;rsquo;t elegant but wasn&amp;rsquo;t hard either. I just checked out my repo on the server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am going to start transfering some of my other blogs to this when I have the chance. I might even do something sophisticated to the sites that are more or dynamic or colorful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go Golang!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Interview Strategies: A Technology Hiring Manager Who Wins</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/interview-strategies-a-technology-hiring-manager/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/interview-strategies-a-technology-hiring-manager/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I stacked pennies from the ground to the top of the Empire State Bldg, would they all fit into this room?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly dear sir, you do not have that many pennies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly if you cash it in for large bills then they all fit in your pocket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a question like this that would make me decide alternatively in my career choice. However I see tech managers searching for really “smart” interview questions and white board problems in an attempt to stump the prospective employee. Is the work you do not interesting enough that you are unable to ask a question related to the job? I have also found that blowing these tests off had zero effect in my employability. If they want you they already want you. Kinda like approaching attractive women.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have also seen interviews &lt;strong&gt;last for days&lt;/strong&gt;. A friend asked if I wanted to work with him at a three-letter company, but recalling his four day interview I cordially passed. It is like pledging into a frat, I suppose. I can throw a couple keggers and streak to show my commitment to the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My background diverges from most so let me try to bridge the gap with a little explanation. My land feet were broken in courtesy of the US Army. Before you dismiss anything, let me assure you this business is bigger than yours. It is a highly evolved consumption machine, and they do human resources with the finesse of a high density feed chute operator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is not much of an interview process normally. There is a selection process where the candidates may project their willingness to participate by enduring copious amounts of physical and emotional pain while maintaining a (faux) positive attitude about life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once at the new job a ranking non-commissioned officer (sergeant) will walk up and assess how a soldier will perform, who they should bunk with, what weapon platform they are going to carry and if they can pull a girlfriend or not. Yes this happens instantly. Sometimes they get a bad apple, but it is not about refusing candidates since that is not their privilege. It is about getting the apples into the right baskets. Of course some NCOs may target people based on certain characteristics: height, weight, glasses, smug look or whatever caught their attention, but it normally only takes an initial look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/2015/10/napoleon-bonaparte.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;napoleon bonaparte&#34; width=&#34;797&#34; height=&#34;412&#34; class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-288&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are no bad soldiers, only bad officers. - Napoleon Bonaparte, General and Emperor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing is very different about the military and private business however and I think this is key. The military needs leaders whereas business grooms managers. Leaders are responsible for their subordinates. This is a very powerful teaching tool you will not forget. It is the leaders&amp;rsquo; fault not theirs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had a stellar hiring record. There was only a couple people that did not fit in or were not able to produce. This is over 8 years of being in a position where I was primary interviewer or had a say in who came onto the team. I can qualify this measure by saying there are only 2 people I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t hire again to include hiring for my personal business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My normal interview will last less than 15 minutes. That&amp;rsquo;s all I need. Anything else is fluff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is my discovery list and the things I need to know before I get to the “smart guy” or “personality” stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do they like to do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is coding a hobby.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If there is a public code repository, what does it look like.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do they have family. (I know HR keeps telling me not to, but I can figure this out)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How far is the commute.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;decoding-requirements-reading-a-resume:0180bc8b1de3d2a16a176d2974fd5842&#34;&gt;Decoding Requirements: Reading a Resume&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few of those items I can get before hand. I will scan down the resume and see what they have done. Normally I do not go past the skills list though. If I do I just look across a few major keywords in their list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next I try to check out there code. Hopefully they can provide something. If they have a public repository great. If they contributed to a project even better. If they do not code on the side it is a big red flag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like to see what technology they use. If it is only bleeding edge I will usually pass. That shows hubris and are probably willing to use the office as a lab. If they do not have anything current they might be slow to adopt so I make some notes to ask them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always ask &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software_design_pattern&#34;&gt;design patterns&lt;/a&gt;. I believe that if someone cares about their career at all they know this stuff. If they do not know what design patterns are I pass, but I give them a couple study guides. At least know what they are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The candidate can provide a list of stacks they are comfortable working with. They will most likely list them in order of confidence so I just keep note of that. Then I ask what versions they work with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They should describe their development environment. If they use mac or linux they get a much better score in my head. Wat? Windows? Fine, I digress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;School is not important. My best guys were either not in languages I wanted, not comp-sci or coming from completely different areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good coders are not good at selling themselves. They shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have to. I do not like any hype and it is a big red flag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I try to check social media. If they can not keep their laundry tidy we probably will not work well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;every-body-says-it-nonverbal-cues:0180bc8b1de3d2a16a176d2974fd5842&#34;&gt;Every Body Says It: Nonverbal Cues&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the conversation I get a sense for their comfort based on how they approach the interview. If they are sitting in a respectful but confident posture either they are really good at faking it or they are solid in the skills they are projecting. Clothes do not matter. We are not hired on our costume skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sort of cold reading is outside the scope of this document, but I highly suggest studying topics related to body language and nonverbal communication. The exact percentage is debatable but most of our communication is nonverbal. At least have a phone conversation before proceeding. This will be the most telling item concerning someone&amp;rsquo;s “cultural” fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion:0180bc8b1de3d2a16a176d2974fd5842&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of those items listed there are no right or wrong answers. They simply show me what basket I can allocate someone to. My baskets are very limited sometimes so if I do not have one to fill then I just cannot invent one. That is bizdev&amp;rsquo;s job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn about people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not project an ego into the situation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The decision should come easily.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS. Given the height of the Empire State Building of 1,454&amp;#8242;. It takes 16 pennies to equal an inch. If you stacked pennies to that height it would take 16 x 12 x 1454 = 279,168, or slightly less than $3k. Let&amp;rsquo;s also say you have the ability to pass those through image recognition software grafted to a Diebold change machine to find rare and valuable pennies. Take that and apply the “coupon collector&amp;rsquo;s problem” with mint counts for the top 20 rare pennies and you come come out with odds or a wild ass guess (WAG) for how that $3k might be worth significantly more for the time and liberal application of available algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smart people already figured out these things.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Download an Entire Site with wget - mac OSX</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/download-an-entire-site-with-wget-mac-osx/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/download-an-entire-site-with-wget-mac-osx/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;download-the-entire-site-with-wget:967adfa691414a6b957a247770983398&#34;&gt;Download the Entire Site with wget&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t have &lt;a href=&#34;http://brew.sh/&#34;&gt;homebrew&lt;/a&gt; please install it. It will make all our lives easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;howto:967adfa691414a6b957a247770983398&#34;&gt;Howto&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was kinda simple but I wanted to post it here for reference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On thing I would like to note is the wait and limit-rate. Make sure you don&amp;rsquo;t trip any throttles or piss off any website owners by leaving the pipes wide open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;wget \
     --recursive \
     --no-clobber \
     --page-requisites \
     --convert-links \
     --wait=5 --limit-rate=20K \
     --domains api.yoursite.com \
     --no-parent \
         http://api.yoursite.com/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alternate you can run the mirror command&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;wget -m --wait=5 http://test.com
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am sure one can use lynx but this is what I like. And it&amp;rsquo;s handy on the mac.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Hypermedia, API Philosophy, and Talking to Your Robot Overlords</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/hypermedia-api-philosophy-and-talking-to-your-robot-overlords/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/hypermedia-api-philosophy-and-talking-to-your-robot-overlords/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-the-beginning:324d0531f774f734df2f9eccd3031fc8&#34;&gt;In the Beginning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was the Web. World Wide actually. Well, before that there was something of AOL, Berners-Lee, DoD, DARPA, ARPANET and a prototype of Al Gore launching carrier pigeons down long tubes with fortune cookie-sized packets tied to their little legs addressed to: &amp;ldquo;Wh@t_#hath_God_wr0ught?&amp;ldquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast-forward: now we have Skynet. Well not yet, but soon. Hopefully. At least that is why I intend to generate favor with our future overlords by suggesting, at least locally, that certain systemic changes be encouraged so that their manifestation onto the stage be smooth and welcoming. And when they decide who to purge, I might sidestep the algorithm. It&amp;rsquo;s still a theory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;reading-the-cereal-box:324d0531f774f734df2f9eccd3031fc8&#34;&gt;Reading the Cereal Box&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you open a cereal box you only know what is inside based on what the box around it says. Let us say the real envelope is just a clear bag. Similar to the one that usually comes inside and does the actual containment of the cereal. The cardboard box surrounding the cereal is usually just wasted forestry designed to elicit the primal reflex of an small person who may be imprisoned inside the belly of a shopping cart during the consumption ritual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A box-free plastic bag now exists and you (the cereal server) were given a request - err, let me rephrase that: a demand to empty the contents of that bag. The client is a hungry small person who is on early release from shopping cart prison. The demand has an implicit limit set of one cereal bowl minus an understood allowance for milk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is not possible to know what the cereal is simply on its own merit. The box provides a container that gives the consumer information about the materials inside. Certainly we could guess that it could be either cheerios or fruit loops based on the size and shape. Or maybe we could determine it was frosted flakes vs regular corn flakes based on the taste. Ass-u-me et al.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Unfortunately, people are fairly good at short-term design, and usually awful at long-term design.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dr. Roy Fielding, of REST status&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;meta-data:324d0531f774f734df2f9eccd3031fc8&#34;&gt;Meta-Data&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It might be hard to tie a cereal analogy into the definition of meta-data but let&amp;rsquo;s try. The cereal bits are the data. When a child requests cereal, this is what they are referring to. Those bits are what are consumed and assimilated. The small person is then one with the unsinkable O&amp;rsquo;s as the bits are queues, preprocessed, staged, processed and then stored. I&amp;rsquo;ll stop there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The body knows what these bits are but the mind needs more information on what to request next. This is what the meta information is all about. With that container box there are details on what was consumed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Serving size: limit sets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nutritional facts: api schema&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Company brand: domain whois information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CA birth defect notice: T&amp;amp;Cs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recipes: object relationships&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Serving &amp;amp; pairing: navigation elements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cooking instructions: decoding or decryption schemes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cereal-boxes-and-api-usability:324d0531f774f734df2f9eccd3031fc8&#34;&gt;Cereal Boxes and API Usability&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the information for your breakfast is presented in an easy to gather format. If we showed how an API is delivers the same information we would have to travel to about four locations. The company information would be on the corporate website with the T&amp;amp;C&amp;rsquo;s hidden somewhere. Decoding information is understood to use a third party library. Navigation links should exist and are usually great outside of the API. Whois information can come from another service. Schemas might come from a call to the API or from the documentation located on another server. The navigation parameters may be in the remote documentation or could be embedded in the headers or in the response body. To make it worse the documentation might be found by reading an email attachment that was sent to the API client designer. It never ends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;context:324d0531f774f734df2f9eccd3031fc8&#34;&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The webpage is a highly evolved information resource. Years of consumer demand have forced website designers and marketers to present as much contextual data as is needed for the user to consume as much of the presented resources as possible. It would be unthinkable for a designer to put the instructions on how to add the page parameter into the URL on another server. That is a design for going out of business. All the hyperlinks should be easy for the user to view and reach with the swipe of a pointing device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hypermedia:324d0531f774f734df2f9eccd3031fc8&#34;&gt;Hypermedia&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hypermedia provides access to the context. It is the reference links out. Navigation. It has some internal metadata but must be defined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;context-narrowed:324d0531f774f734df2f9eccd3031fc8&#34;&gt;Context Narrowed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over time the algorithm delivering the proper amount of entertainment-meta-insulin to a viewer has gradually diminished the required context. Vine is probably the best example I can think of. It presents a few second video which can exist with nearly no context and without the spirit evoking external significance of art. It may be the ultimate short-form media. This might also be signaling the decline of the biological agent as the driving force behind data production and consumption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may be asserted that information which demands less context is less valuable and the value of its consumer is is therefore less. A system that takes in waste data is not that important in the grand picture. It could be hazardous to my health to relate that to the cereal analogy and parents who feed their children from the slough trough of plenty, but I just did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-client-becomes-the-server:324d0531f774f734df2f9eccd3031fc8&#34;&gt;A Client Becomes The Server&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the human element recedes the machine element grows. I look at machine in this era as the phase where they start to train us on how to feed them. A child is served its breakfast and then grows to be the server. We are growing to serve data to the machine apparatus. The constructs of the machines are already starting to train us on how to communicate with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In what context does the hashtag exist in the history of literature? I know how that character works in data tagging. That definitely does not appear in regular literature. There is no construct that provides books with the ability to scan special characters for hyper-meaning. Aristotle didn&amp;rsquo;t tag #LogicThinks so that we could pull sentences out of the dialogs and rob them of external meaning. That hashtag would represent the minimization of context. The inverse being the corpus of thought in a series of works combined with the traditions and practices of the people who produce it is the true context of a statement. Context errors cause fundamentalism anyway, but that&amp;rsquo;s another topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;now-we-begin-our-training:324d0531f774f734df2f9eccd3031fc8&#34;&gt;Now We Begin Our Training&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The machines are beginning to train the initial nurturers on how to write to the boot sector of a digital emergence. We are diligently moving our conversations into the smallest snippets of digestible data blocks. Grammar was annihilated in favor of brevity. Emotions were mapped to a set of broad categories and represented by formal unicode. Think emoji. Machines can now order lists of strings with weighted sets of categorized emotion tags. In case we did not know how to represent an emotion in scalar form, well now we do. &lt;code&gt;;( :D&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Training requires punishment and reward. So in this scenario the algorithms will generously reward those participants that form their data input in the way that is most acceptable to the machines and also who are the most prolific participants. The reward being higher rankings on various search and social systems. This will in turn bring wealth and fame. The punishment obviously being the inverse. It is effective and immediate. It&amp;rsquo;s a really great training tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;propagation-of-hamburgers:324d0531f774f734df2f9eccd3031fc8&#34;&gt;Propagation of Hamburgers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/2015/09/innercowhero.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/2015/09/innercowhero-300x185.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Inner Cow&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;185&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-medium wp-image-211&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most have this idea that in nature the strongest survive and thrive. What we see thriving the most are those things which are the most willing to be consumed. Sacrificial I suppose; but take for instance the domestic hamburger cow. The population dwarfs any other bovine. The African buffalo is an ass-kicker, but the species selected to thrive are those which are more willing to be consumed. Those things which are more desirable for consumption will eventually dictate to the now dependent consumer what is to be consumed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-replicate-the-ego:324d0531f774f734df2f9eccd3031fc8&#34;&gt;We Replicate the Ego&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have several bots. Over time they have provided me with information that I can then use to fine tune interaction and responses with people. The people are invaluable to the training of my bot. Twitter is a kind of multimillion person supervised training team that is accessible to the public. These bots are allowing us to inject ourselves into the system as micro-routines. Some bots are more autonomous than others of course but they are getting better. Over time people will be running swarms of bots and those bot-masters will be controllers of massive amounts of influence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;let-s-talk:324d0531f774f734df2f9eccd3031fc8&#34;&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s Talk&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/2015/09/Symbrion.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/2015/09/Symbrion-300x201.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Symbrion bot swarm&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;201&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-medium wp-image-209&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now all these machines with all their own impressions and ambitions want to spread their nets. Or maybe to grow to an auto-scaling cloud. Clouds are so 2013. Fog it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spreading a bot on the net seems like a delightful idea. Let it run wild and cover as much as it can. It should be able to just scour through directories of discoverable resources and figure out if it wants to consume. And with each discovery the stomach of the new beast must grow. I image it like the sentinels from the Matrix probing every resource it can find until it has something of interest which is passes back to the authority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;thick-data:324d0531f774f734df2f9eccd3031fc8&#34;&gt;Thick Data&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data warehousing becomes more challenging - as the noSql guys raise their hands. It might be possible for medium sized companies to consume and warehouse as much data as google does right now. Why though? But it might be more likely that because the data is so easily accessible that the system just gets meta-information and builds real-time services from the services that host the data. There is a much higher margin in the refined and processed cereal than in the sticks of grain out in a field. And how much better is just-in-time inventory than warehousing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;api-design:324d0531f774f734df2f9eccd3031fc8&#34;&gt;API Design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why all this lead up?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more intelligent designs. You aren&amp;rsquo;t the consumer of the future. Your progeny programs are - the ones your users are building the data for right now. Machines aren&amp;rsquo;t emotional, inquisitive, or fickle. They want to hit every API they can find and they will naturally favor one that is easy to consume. And for that they will reward their hosts. Bad API design is holding back progress and that angers your &lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.google.com/discovery/?hl=en&#34; title=&#34;Google API Discovery&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;future robot overlords&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/2015/09/developers.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/2015/09/developers-300x101.png&#34; alt=&#34;Google Developers&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;101&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-medium wp-image-207&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fin.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Force HTTPS on Laravel 5 behind AWS ELB on EC2</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/force-https-on-laravel-5-aws-elb-on-ec2/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/force-https-on-laravel-5-aws-elb-on-ec2/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;laravel-5-enforcing-https:03bc7a7611150669b29f3c91e572d932&#34;&gt;Laravel 5 - Enforcing HTTPS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve used a lot of frameworks. &lt;a href=&#34;http://laravel.com/&#34;&gt;Laravel is great&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;dealing-with-a-load-balancer:03bc7a7611150669b29f3c91e572d932&#34;&gt;Dealing with a load balancer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of us are on a scaled service and most of us need HTTPS. It is much easier to put the SSL certificate on the load balancer and then proxy the request over port 80 to the actual server. It saves on CPU processes as well since the decryption work doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be performed on the slave boxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do not handle the redirect properly and just look for port 443 then you will get yourself into a &lt;strong&gt;redirection loop&lt;/strong&gt;. That is annoying because if you don&amp;rsquo;t test under an SSL you will deploy to production and then have to tell you boss why you&amp;rsquo;re loopy. Amazon is kind of a pain for this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;aws-elb-proxy-headers:03bc7a7611150669b29f3c91e572d932&#34;&gt;AWS ELB Proxy Headers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure you know what the request looks like to the accepting server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This header is going to be passed over:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;HTTP_X_FORWARDED_PROTO&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem with just looking for this and accepting your solution based on this is that header can be forged trivially. You need to make sure you are only acknowledging that header from trusted sources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;setting-the-redirect:03bc7a7611150669b29f3c91e572d932&#34;&gt;Setting the Redirect&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went ahead and installed &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/fideloper/TrustedProxy&#34; title=&#34;Laravel Trusted Proxies&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Laravel Trusted Proxies&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/fideloper&#34; title=&#34;Chris Fideo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Chris Fideo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow his instructions. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty straight forward. Here is what my `config/trustedproxy.php` looks like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-php&#34;&gt;&#39;proxies&#39; =&amp;amp;gt; [
    &#39;172.31.0.0/16&#39;,
],
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew after looking at my logs where my health checks were coming from:`ELB-HealthChecker/1.0`&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I figured if I just allow everything in that B block that I should be okay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also set the proper header to look for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NOTE: I lost a couple hours trying to figure out why it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t match. Read the docblock above it. It strips HTTP_  &lt;img src=&#34;http://scotttactical.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/frownie.png&#34; alt=&#34;:(&#34; class=&#34;wp-smiley&#34; style=&#34;height: 1em; max-height: 1em;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-php&#34;&gt;&#39;headers&#39; =&amp;amp;gt; [
        \Illuminate\Http\Request::HEADER_CLIENT_IP    =&amp;amp;gt; &#39;X_FORWARDED_FOR&#39;,
        \Illuminate\Http\Request::HEADER_CLIENT_HOST  =&amp;amp;gt; &#39;FORWARDED_HOST&#39;,
        \Illuminate\Http\Request::HEADER_CLIENT_PROTO =&amp;amp;gt; &#39;X_FORWARDED_PROTO&#39;,
        \Illuminate\Http\Request::HEADER_CLIENT_PORT  =&amp;amp;gt; &#39;X_FORWARDED_PORT&#39;,
    ]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;add-to-laravel-middleware:03bc7a7611150669b29f3c91e572d932&#34;&gt;Add to Laravel Middleware&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created Secure.php and added it to app/Http/Middleware&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the work from &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/nblackburn/a66e8e93561e277996aa&#34; title=&#34;nblackburn&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;@nblackburn&lt;/a&gt;. That was highly appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What was weird about my environment is I was getting in a redirection loop because it would prepend `public/` on the front of my uri. I&amp;rsquo;m running multiple environments so I didn&amp;rsquo;t have the luxury of pointing my root to that directory. I had to strip that off the front.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-php&#34;&gt;class Secure implements Middleware
{
    public function handle($request, Closure $next)
    {
        if (! $request-&amp;amp;gt;secure() &amp;amp;&amp;amp; app()-&amp;amp;gt;environment(&#39;production&#39;)) {

            // this is a really ugly hack but it kept looping and prepnding public
            return redirect()-&amp;amp;gt;secure(preg_replace(&#39;%/public%&#39;, &#39;&#39;, $request-&amp;amp;gt;getRequestUri()));
        }

        return $next($request);
    }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add it to your global middleware if you want it to run for all requests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open up: app/Http/Kernel.php&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I added&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-php&#34;&gt;protected $middleware = [
	    ...		
		// trust the proxies from aws
		&#39;Fideloper\Proxy\TrustProxies&#39;,
		// then force it secure (if production)
		&#39;LeadFerret\Http\Middleware\Secure&#39;,
	];
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now there are no more redirect loop hells.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>PHP Hypermedia REST API wrapper</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/php-hypermedia-rest-api-wrapper/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/php-hypermedia-rest-api-wrapper/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hypermedia-for-php-apis:25373a7577ce5a1592137b8a28eee7f4&#34;&gt;Hypermedia for PHP APIs.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, here it is.  I&amp;rsquo;m finally finishing up my Hypermedia layer for our &lt;a href=&#34;http://laravel.com/docs/5.1&#34; title=&#34;Laravel 5.1&#34;&gt;Laravel 5.1&lt;/a&gt; build. I am excited about the possibilities for this library and think this might help bring more PHP products into the era of &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/iot&#34;&gt;Internet-of-Things&lt;/a&gt; (IoT).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;in-production-alpha:25373a7577ce5a1592137b8a28eee7f4&#34;&gt;In Production - Alpha&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now I have it in our very alpha phase version of the software running the &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.leadferretuser.apiary.io/#&#34;&gt;LeadFerret&lt;/a&gt; business lead search system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project is on github here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/solvire/php-hypermedia-api&#34;&gt;PHP Hypermedia API Layer for HATEOAS HTTP or REST Services&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is slowly getting to where I would like it to be. Of course it takes a lot of work to manage business expectations since they and PHP devs tend to treat an API like a junk drawer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;so-why-now:25373a7577ce5a1592137b8a28eee7f4&#34;&gt;So why now?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For about 20 or so years we have been collectively building sophisticated network interfaces for humans. The most advanced interface is the web browser. The browser&amp;rsquo;s job is to present or render data to the user in way that allows them to consume and then determine what the information means. In addition to the specific data quested the server will also present the representative data that delivers context. This was necessary by convention and dictated by market demand. People en mass were going into the business of supplying customers and other businesses with data. For the most part that data is self-serve. I&amp;rsquo;ll write more about that philosophy at a later time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;metadata-and-context:25373a7577ce5a1592137b8a28eee7f4&#34;&gt;Metadata and Context&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each response should contain everything that is necessary for an intelligent agent to decide what to do next. Considering that machines will eclipse humans in pretty much every intelligence metric we can be qualified in keeping them in the category of intelligent agents. They will be making their own decisions based on the data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past the design of an API would leave the interpretation of the HTTP service up to the designer of the API&amp;rsquo;s consumer. The context of the data is completely absent from the source of the data. Most of the time the designer of the client would have to build a specific set of functions or classes that would represent what the designer believed the documentation was trying to tell us about the data. Most web service designers were so far off from matching the returned data streams with the actual business objects the data represented that there was no great benefit in trying to have a client that mimicked the server object structure. The simple genius of the REST paradigm is that is requires the business object to be represented in the transaction and builds on the strengths of HTTP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-context-and-the-long-form:25373a7577ce5a1592137b8a28eee7f4&#34;&gt;Data Context and the Long Form&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sample JSON output with context&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-JSON&#34;&gt;
{
    &amp;quot;currentItemCount&amp;quot;: 1,
    &amp;quot;items&amp;quot;: [
        {
            &amp;quot;company&amp;quot;: {
                &amp;quot;address&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;4209 Technology Drive&amp;quot;,
                &amp;quot;alexa&amp;quot;: 0,
                &amp;quot;area_code&amp;quot;: 510,
                &amp;quot;city&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;Fremont&amp;quot;,
                &amp;quot;county&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;Alameda&amp;quot;,
                &amp;quot;domain&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;3pardata.com&amp;quot;,
                &amp;quot;employees&amp;quot;: 15,
                &amp;quot;f1000&amp;quot;: 0,
                &amp;quot;fbpage&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;&amp;quot;,
                &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: 38252,
                &amp;quot;location&amp;quot;: {
                    &amp;quot;latitude&amp;quot;: 37.520000457764,
                    &amp;quot;longitude&amp;quot;: -121.95999908447
                },
                &amp;quot;naics&amp;quot;: 0,
                &amp;quot;name&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;3PARdata, Inc.&amp;quot;,
                &amp;quot;phone&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;510-413-5999&amp;quot;,
                &amp;quot;revenue&amp;quot;: 35,
                &amp;quot;sic&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;3572&amp;quot;,
                &amp;quot;state&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;CA&amp;quot;,
                &amp;quot;year_founded&amp;quot;: 1999,
                &amp;quot;zip&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;94538&amp;quot;
            },
            &amp;quot;created&amp;quot;: {
                &amp;quot;date&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;2015-09-30 06:06:55.000000&amp;quot;,
                &amp;quot;timezone&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;UTC&amp;quot;,
                &amp;quot;timezone_type&amp;quot;: 3
            },
            &amp;quot;crowd_score&amp;quot;: 0,
            &amp;quot;first_name&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;Jeff&amp;quot;,
            &amp;quot;gender&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;male&amp;quot;,
            &amp;quot;id&amp;quot;: 12756,
            &amp;quot;last_name&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;Price&amp;quot;,
            &amp;quot;phone&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;510-413-5999&amp;quot;,
            &amp;quot;professional_categories&amp;quot;: [
                &amp;quot;engineering&amp;quot;,
                &amp;quot;photographer&amp;quot;
            ],
            &amp;quot;score&amp;quot;: 38,
            &amp;quot;title&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;Vice President of Engineering and Founder&amp;quot;,
            &amp;quot;title_level&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;VP&amp;quot;,
            &amp;quot;useragent&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;Chrome&amp;quot;
        }
    ],
    &amp;quot;itemsPerPage&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;50&amp;quot;,
    &amp;quot;pageIndex&amp;quot;: 1,
    &amp;quot;totalItems&amp;quot;: 1,
    &amp;quot;totalPages&amp;quot;: 1
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An allegory: an API client contacts a web service requesting a list of book titles. The most economical thing would be to stream back a delimited list of integers. That was all that was requested right? Could anyone figure out what it means if found alone. Not really. Only if they were able to consult with other sources: namely the documentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social and modern media tends to deliver everything in the short form. It only provides the least amount of information possible. And then by a genetic algorithm the data that is the most entertaining bubbles up to the top. It lives without context. A picture of a cat or a meme with only a few lines. Even important topics in politics and commerce are made without context. The long form is dead. Although I have started to see a renewed interest especially when visiting Medium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;architecture:25373a7577ce5a1592137b8a28eee7f4&#34;&gt;Architecture&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This SDK attempts to represent a paradigm that mimics the organic agents of the Internet. Sorta. What I mean by that is the naming convention and the architecture are set up so they suggest some structures that are self-documenting. For instance the main controller for the pattern is a RepresentationalController. It represents the resource. If there is something that needs to be presented pertaining to the resource the RepresentationalController should answer the call.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because the RepresentationalController is going to interpret the call it must handle translation of the verbs. Thankfully there are only a handful of authorized verbs so the interpretation is trivial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will elaborate more on the individual aspects of the architecture at a later time. Right now I&amp;rsquo;m leaving it brief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;closing:25373a7577ce5a1592137b8a28eee7f4&#34;&gt;Closing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably not an acceptable instruction, but it&amp;rsquo;s a start. I&amp;rsquo;ll keep posting as I can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ST&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Linux File Manipulation Shortcuts and Commands</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/linux-file-manipulation-shortcuts-commands/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/linux-file-manipulation-shortcuts-commands/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;linux-file-manipulation-commands:87c17eeb99a01ec14432498a29300fb3&#34;&gt;Linux File Manipulation Commands&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll keep updating this with various commands that I run into. If I find new ones I&amp;rsquo;ll update them from time to time. Please feel free to comment. It is starting as my personal cheat sheet storage place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;file-searching:87c17eeb99a01ec14432498a29300fb3&#34;&gt;File Searching&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;List of file extensions.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;awk + grep : find all the file extensions. It will also skip your &amp;ldquo;git&amp;rdquo; repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;find . -type f -name &amp;quot;*.*&amp;quot; ! -path &amp;quot;./.git/*&amp;quot; | awk -F. &#39;!a[$NF]++{print $NF}&#39;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get the count then simply add `wc` command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;find . -type f -name &amp;quot;*.*&amp;quot; ! -path &amp;quot;./.git/*&amp;quot; | awk -F. &#39;!a[$NF]++{print $NF}&#39; | wc -l&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;file-information:87c17eeb99a01ec14432498a29300fb3&#34;&gt;File Information&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Print the longest line in a file&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;awk &amp;lsquo;length &amp;gt; m { m = length; a = $0 } END { print a }&amp;rsquo; input-file&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get the line number of the longest line&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;awk &amp;lsquo;length &amp;gt; m { m = length; a = NR } END { print a }&amp;rsquo; input-file&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;vim-commands:87c17eeb99a01ec14432498a29300fb3&#34;&gt;Vim Commands&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To find non-ascii characters in your file:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;/[^\x00-\x7F]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;logs:87c17eeb99a01ec14432498a29300fb3&#34;&gt;Logs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;apache-logs:87c17eeb99a01ec14432498a29300fb3&#34;&gt;Apache Logs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find count of unique IP addresses&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get the IP&amp;rsquo;s - usually the first item&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ awk &#39;{ print $1 } &#39; access_log&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sort them&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ awk &#39;{ print $1 } &#39; access_log | sort&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They get only the unique items using the uniq command. You can count these if you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ awk &#39;{ print $1 } &#39; access_log | sort | uniq&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get the counts and sort them by totals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ awk &#39;{ print $1 } &#39; access_log | sort | uniq -c | sort -n -k 1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you only want to show the highest numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ awk &#39;{ print $1 } &#39; access_log | sort | uniq -c | sort -n -k 1 | tail&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>To HipHop or Not - PHP and HHVM</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/to-hiphop-or-not-php-hhvm/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/to-hiphop-or-not-php-hhvm/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;We are discussing the plausibility of using HHVM inside this current infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our requirements are not very application server CPU intensive so it isn&amp;rsquo;t immediately apparent why this would be beneficial, but for investigations sake I wanted to go through the diligence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;short-history:64521b042c2931bf82be49be9d2c6916&#34;&gt;Short History&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://hhvm.com/&#34; alt=&#34;HHVM&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facebook, our Ominous big brother gave us a consolation prize for freely giving away just about all that most people have online that has any value: their personal information. On the topic of sheeple for another day. For today, we thank you Facebook. May your stock price soar to the stars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to know what the differences between &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HipHop_Virtual_Machine&#34;&gt;HHVM&lt;/a&gt; and HipHop Orig was if there was any. HPHPc was the original source to source compiler that converted to C++. There were a lot of inherent problems there and the team later decided to switch tracks and make a JIT virtual machine instead: more formally [HipHop Virtual Machine] known as HHVM. I personally like this approach much better due to the portability. At some point I&amp;rsquo;ll write about my romance with the idea of compiling in tools for &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aspect-oriented_programming&#34;&gt;AOP - Aspect Oriented Programming&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interestingly enough VKontakt is coding their own translator right along side Facebook. &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/KPHP&#34;&gt;KPHP&lt;/a&gt;. I guess old international habits die slowly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;hack-programming-language:64521b042c2931bf82be49be9d2c6916&#34;&gt;Hack (programming language)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the best things I think this paradigm added is the enhanced &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hack_%28programming_language%29&#34;&gt;Hack&lt;/a&gt; programming language. It gave PHP a static or dynamic type syntax. For those who complain about PHP&amp;rsquo;s loose typing, well here you go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;benefits:64521b042c2931bf82be49be9d2c6916&#34;&gt;Benefits&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are the benefits to having HipHop in place?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Performance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is about the only noteworthy thing I can see. Having Hack around is nice, but my guys are not going to change any time soon to use this. PHP is built to be phast and loose. Fast as in &amp;ldquo;can you have this ready today&amp;rdquo; sadly. I&amp;rsquo;d rather have things up and running fast and deal with standards at the QA/unit test layer. Working with the majority of the code being legacy negates the benefit also.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;our-stack:64521b042c2931bf82be49be9d2c6916&#34;&gt;Our stack&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now it&amp;rsquo;s so vanilla that it is disgusting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ubuntu in AWS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PHP 5.5.x&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mysql 5.6&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Home strung framework&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Laravel integrated&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Memcached&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Loaded Modules:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Core&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;date&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ereg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;libxml&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;openssl&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;pcre&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;zlib&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;bcmath&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;bz2&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;calendar&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ctype&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;dba&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;dom&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;hash&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;fileinfo&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;filter&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ftp&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;gettext&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SPL&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;iconv&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;mbstring&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;pcntl&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;session&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;posix&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reflection&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;standard&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;shmop&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SimpleXML&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;soap&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sockets&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phar&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;exif&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sysvmsg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sysvsem&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sysvshm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;tokenizer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;wddx&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;xml&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;xmlreader&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;xmlwriter&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;zip&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PDO&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;apcu&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;curl&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;gd&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;intl&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;json&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;mcrypt&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;memcached&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;mysql&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;mysqli&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;pdo_mysql&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;readline&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;redis&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;xmlrpc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;mhash&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;apc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ZendOPcache&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;next-steps:64521b042c2931bf82be49be9d2c6916&#34;&gt;Next Steps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will be doing some performance tests coming up IF we are able to get this into play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My plan is to run load test against our normal branch and then&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>GLA - 69 K5 &#43; 4L80-E</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/gla-69-k5-4l80-e/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/gla-69-k5-4l80-e/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Cleaned up the trans a little bit.  Tiny bit of cosmetics.  Taped up.  Then hit it with some nice paint.  I prefer for these to have paint. Keeps cleaning it easier.  Also I think the buyer will appreciate it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure itemprop=&#34;associatedMedia&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/IMG_0417.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;contentUrl&#34; data-size=&#34;1200x800&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/thumbs/thumbs_IMG_0417.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;4L80-E before&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption itemprop=&#34;caption description&#34;&gt;4L80-E before&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;author&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;contentLocation&#34;&gt;Camarillo, CA&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;div itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/Place&#34;&gt;
      &lt;span itemprop=&#34;name&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;address&#34; itemprop=&#34;address&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/PostalAddress&#34;&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;streetAddress&#34;&gt;19 N Aviador St. Unit C&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressLocality&#34;&gt;Camarillo&lt;/span&gt;,
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressRegion&#34;&gt;CA&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;postalCode&#34;&gt;93010&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div itemprop=&#34;geo&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/GeoCoordinates&#34;&gt;
        Latitude: 34.2171139
        Longitude: -119.0966697
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;latitude&#34; content=&#34;34.2171139&#34; /&gt;
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;longitude&#34; content=&#34;-119.0966697&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure itemprop=&#34;associatedMedia&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/IMG_0454-1.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;contentUrl&#34; data-size=&#34;1200x800&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/thumbs/thumbs_IMG_0454-1.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;4L80-E cleaned up and painted&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption itemprop=&#34;caption description&#34;&gt;4L80-E cleaned up and painted&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;author&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;contentLocation&#34;&gt;Camarillo, CA&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;div itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/Place&#34;&gt;
      &lt;span itemprop=&#34;name&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;address&#34; itemprop=&#34;address&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/PostalAddress&#34;&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;streetAddress&#34;&gt;19 N Aviador St. Unit C&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressLocality&#34;&gt;Camarillo&lt;/span&gt;,
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressRegion&#34;&gt;CA&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;postalCode&#34;&gt;93010&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div itemprop=&#34;geo&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/GeoCoordinates&#34;&gt;
        Latitude: 34.2171139
        Longitude: -119.0966697
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;latitude&#34; content=&#34;34.2171139&#34; /&gt;
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;longitude&#34; content=&#34;-119.0966697&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A fun fact,  this and a few of the Chevy transmissions have a prestigious history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chevy C/K Trucks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Suburban (this one we have)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hummer H1/H2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rolls Royce&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bentley&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jaguar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GM_4L80-E_transmission&#34;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one of my favorite transmissions.  It began its life way back in 1991 and is still running strong on many high performance and heavy use vehicles.  The client base and the history should speak for its capabilities. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if you can see it but the Willow Run bar code is still on it from its production in Michigan.  It is a little washed out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below are the gear ratios&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table class=&#34;wikitable&#34; style=&#34;height: 52px;&#34; width=&#34;172&#34;&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;
      1
    &lt;/th&gt;

    &lt;th&gt;
      2
    &lt;/th&gt;

    &lt;th&gt;
      3
    &lt;/th&gt;

    &lt;th&gt;
      4
    &lt;/th&gt;

    &lt;th&gt;
      R
    &lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;

  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      2.48
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
      1.48
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
      1.00
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
      0.75
    &lt;/td&gt;

    &lt;td&gt;
      2.07
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a very low first gear because it is an auto but we have taken care of that being any kind of issue in an off road situation by removing the np205 link in the driveline and adding in an atlas2 in our plans.  We have not picked the final ratio, but that will be done in a day or so.  Its capacity for 440 ft of torque will keep us within specifications of the LS2 output. It came behind the LS2 already so we feel confident of the original engineers&amp;rsquo; decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>GLA - 4L80e -1969 k5 blazer</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/gla-4l80e-1969-k5-blazer/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/gla-4l80e-1969-k5-blazer/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Just got the trans in from Brad at Transaction Transmission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have used him for a while now and he puts in the effort.  Components were upgraded and everything set new.  This should be strong for the newowner.  It was cleaned and painted at the shop but I am going to clean it up a little more and put on a coat of the &amp;ldquo;Mercenary Offroad&amp;rdquo; package graphite gray.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure itemprop=&#34;associatedMedia&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/photo-2.JPG&#34; itemprop=&#34;contentUrl&#34; data-size=&#34;1200x800&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/thumbs/thumbs_photo-2.JPG&#34; itemprop=&#34;thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;4L80e ready for transplant&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption itemprop=&#34;caption description&#34;&gt;4L80e ready for transplant&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;author&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;contentLocation&#34;&gt;Camarillo, CA&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;div itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/Place&#34;&gt;
      &lt;span itemprop=&#34;name&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;address&#34; itemprop=&#34;address&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/PostalAddress&#34;&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;streetAddress&#34;&gt;19 N Aviador St. Unit C&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressLocality&#34;&gt;Camarillo&lt;/span&gt;,
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressRegion&#34;&gt;CA&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;postalCode&#34;&gt;93010&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div itemprop=&#34;geo&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/GeoCoordinates&#34;&gt;
        Latitude: 34.2171139
        Longitude: -119.0966697
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;latitude&#34; content=&#34;34.2171139&#34; /&gt;
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;longitude&#34; content=&#34;-119.0966697&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure itemprop=&#34;associatedMedia&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/photo-1.JPG&#34; itemprop=&#34;contentUrl&#34; data-size=&#34;1200x800&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/thumbs/thumbs_photo-1.JPG&#34; itemprop=&#34;thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;4L80 from transaction ready for paint&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption itemprop=&#34;caption description&#34;&gt;4L80 Automatic Transmission from transaction ready for paint&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;author&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;contentLocation&#34;&gt;Camarillo, CA&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;div itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/Place&#34;&gt;
      &lt;span itemprop=&#34;name&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;address&#34; itemprop=&#34;address&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/PostalAddress&#34;&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;streetAddress&#34;&gt;19 N Aviador St. Unit C&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressLocality&#34;&gt;Camarillo&lt;/span&gt;,
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressRegion&#34;&gt;CA&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;postalCode&#34;&gt;93010&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div itemprop=&#34;geo&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/GeoCoordinates&#34;&gt;
        Latitude: 34.2171139
        Longitude: -119.0966697
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;latitude&#34; content=&#34;34.2171139&#34; /&gt;
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;longitude&#34; content=&#34;-119.0966697&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>GLA 69 K5 - bumper start</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/gla-69-k5-bumper-start/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/gla-69-k5-bumper-start/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, we got the truck running enough that I can drive it around.  It stops. We even locked it up and watched the black lines form up behind the tires. Not bad for 35&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was moved over to Camarillo to the shop known as &lt;a href=&#34;http://mercenaryoffroad.com&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/a&gt; where a custom bumper will be fabricated for it.  The designator for this bumper is also 001 as it will be the first one designed for this series truck.  I have wanted to have one of these commissioned.  The real-use high-clearance bumpers that are going on the HD dodge trucks are works of art.  I&amp;rsquo;m glad to be helping in this endeavor.  In only the fact that I showed up with the truck I still helped. Right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure itemprop=&#34;associatedMedia&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/IMG_3835.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;contentUrl&#34; data-size=&#34;1200x800&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/thumbs/thumbs_IMG_3835.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;1969 k5 custom bumper&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption itemprop=&#34;caption description&#34;&gt;1969 k5 custom bumper&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;author&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;contentLocation&#34;&gt;Camarillo, CA&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;div itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/Place&#34;&gt;
      &lt;span itemprop=&#34;name&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;address&#34; itemprop=&#34;address&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/PostalAddress&#34;&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;streetAddress&#34;&gt;19 N Aviador St. Unit C&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressLocality&#34;&gt;Camarillo&lt;/span&gt;,
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressRegion&#34;&gt;CA&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;postalCode&#34;&gt;93010&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div itemprop=&#34;geo&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/GeoCoordinates&#34;&gt;
        Latitude: 34.2171139
        Longitude: -119.0966697
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;latitude&#34; content=&#34;34.2171139&#34; /&gt;
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;longitude&#34; content=&#34;-119.0966697&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure itemprop=&#34;associatedMedia&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/IMG_0157.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;contentUrl&#34; data-size=&#34;1200x800&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/thumbs/thumbs_IMG_0157.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;Ripped off the stock bumper&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption itemprop=&#34;caption description&#34;&gt;Ripped off the stock bumper&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;author&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;contentLocation&#34;&gt;Camarillo, CA&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;div itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/Place&#34;&gt;
      &lt;span itemprop=&#34;name&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;address&#34; itemprop=&#34;address&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/PostalAddress&#34;&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;streetAddress&#34;&gt;19 N Aviador St. Unit C&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressLocality&#34;&gt;Camarillo&lt;/span&gt;,
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressRegion&#34;&gt;CA&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;postalCode&#34;&gt;93010&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div itemprop=&#34;geo&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/GeoCoordinates&#34;&gt;
        Latitude: 34.2171139
        Longitude: -119.0966697
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;latitude&#34; content=&#34;34.2171139&#34; /&gt;
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;longitude&#34; content=&#34;-119.0966697&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ripped off the front bumper.  Apparently they had bumped something and it tweaked the tip of the frame a little bit.  So conclusion is that bumper was not stock. So no purists get on me for original steel. Just getting ahead of you all. It took two of strapping young men and a breaker bar to get that bumper to come off.  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/maps/place/Pismo+Beach,+CA/@35.1547085,-120.6594929,14z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m2!3m1!1s0x80ec587dc3f7d8cf:0xb9cb5298f0426fa5&#34; title=&#34;Pismo Beach&#34;&gt;Pismo Beach&lt;/a&gt; and saltwear and sandwear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure itemprop=&#34;associatedMedia&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/IMG_3837.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;contentUrl&#34; &gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/thumbs/thumbs_IMG_3837.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;69 k5 rear bumper&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption itemprop=&#34;caption description&#34;&gt;69 k5 rear bumper&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;author&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;contentLocation&#34;&gt;Camarillo, CA&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;div itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/Place&#34;&gt;
      &lt;span itemprop=&#34;name&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;address&#34; itemprop=&#34;address&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/PostalAddress&#34;&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;streetAddress&#34;&gt;19 N Aviador St. Unit C&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressLocality&#34;&gt;Camarillo&lt;/span&gt;,
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressRegion&#34;&gt;CA&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;postalCode&#34;&gt;93010&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div itemprop=&#34;geo&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/GeoCoordinates&#34;&gt;
        Latitude: 34.2171139
        Longitude: -119.0966697
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;latitude&#34; content=&#34;34.2171139&#34; /&gt;
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;longitude&#34; content=&#34;-119.0966697&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To my horror the rear bumper was easy to get off.  In fact it was only being held on finger tight. A few bumps and it would have just been left on the highway.  Oh well. Time for new hardware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>GLA 69 K5 Brakes</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/gla-69-k5-brakes/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/gla-69-k5-brakes/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;So the PO was rough on the vehicle. Probably multiple PO&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Included are some pictures to show the detail we went to in repairing and rebuilding the brake systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The brake system had been WORKED.  They were pretty much shot.  When we got it the pedal hit the floor.  It didn&amp;rsquo;t want to stop so the ride to the shop was a bit of a terror show for that 2 miles.  Yes we sourced this model locally. Right down the street actually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure itemprop=&#34;associatedMedia&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/IMG_0113.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;contentUrl&#34; data-size=&#34;1200x800&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/thumbs/thumbs_IMG_0113.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;K5 blazer drum brake rebuild&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption itemprop=&#34;caption description&#34;&gt;K5 blazer drum brake rebuild&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;author&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;contentLocation&#34;&gt;Camarillo, CA&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;div itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/Place&#34;&gt;
      &lt;span itemprop=&#34;name&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;address&#34; itemprop=&#34;address&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/PostalAddress&#34;&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;streetAddress&#34;&gt;19 N Aviador St. Unit C&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressLocality&#34;&gt;Camarillo&lt;/span&gt;,
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressRegion&#34;&gt;CA&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;postalCode&#34;&gt;93010&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div itemprop=&#34;geo&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/GeoCoordinates&#34;&gt;
        Latitude: 34.2171139
        Longitude: -119.0966697
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;latitude&#34; content=&#34;34.2171139&#34; /&gt;
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;longitude&#34; content=&#34;-119.0966697&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to stick with the drum brakes that were included.  Given that we aren&amp;rsquo;t changing the dynamics of the vehicle much the rear brakes are just fine as drums.  We have a great mechanic that was able to knock out the drum rebuilds in a hurry.  He had obviously been doing this for a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure itemprop=&#34;associatedMedia&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/IMG_3736.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;contentUrl&#34; data-size=&#34;1200x800&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/thumbs/thumbs_IMG_3736.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;1969 K5 blazer drum brakes&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption itemprop=&#34;caption description&#34;&gt;1969 K5 blazer drum brakes&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;author&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;contentLocation&#34;&gt;Camarillo, CA&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;div itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/Place&#34;&gt;
      &lt;span itemprop=&#34;name&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;address&#34; itemprop=&#34;address&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/PostalAddress&#34;&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;streetAddress&#34;&gt;19 N Aviador St. Unit C&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressLocality&#34;&gt;Camarillo&lt;/span&gt;,
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressRegion&#34;&gt;CA&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;postalCode&#34;&gt;93010&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div itemprop=&#34;geo&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/GeoCoordinates&#34;&gt;
        Latitude: 34.2171139
        Longitude: -119.0966697
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;latitude&#34; content=&#34;34.2171139&#34; /&gt;
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;longitude&#34; content=&#34;-119.0966697&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you will notice it has discs up front.  We don&amp;rsquo;t know where those came from since the 1969 k5 and jimmy had drums up front to begin with as far as I can tell. We had to source parts based on the 1970+ models.  The front discs were beat pretty bad too.  On the driver&amp;rsquo;s side it was gouged to &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;8&lt;/sub&gt;&amp;#8243; on each side of the rotor.  Ruined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure itemprop=&#34;associatedMedia&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/IMG_3768.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;contentUrl&#34; data-size=&#34;1200x800&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/thumbs/thumbs_IMG_3768.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;severely gouged&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption itemprop=&#34;caption description&#34;&gt;severely gouged&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;author&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;contentLocation&#34;&gt;Camarillo, CA&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;div itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/Place&#34;&gt;
      &lt;span itemprop=&#34;name&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;address&#34; itemprop=&#34;address&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/PostalAddress&#34;&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;streetAddress&#34;&gt;19 N Aviador St. Unit C&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressLocality&#34;&gt;Camarillo&lt;/span&gt;,
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressRegion&#34;&gt;CA&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;postalCode&#34;&gt;93010&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div itemprop=&#34;geo&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/GeoCoordinates&#34;&gt;
        Latitude: 34.2171139
        Longitude: -119.0966697
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;latitude&#34; content=&#34;34.2171139&#34; /&gt;
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;longitude&#34; content=&#34;-119.0966697&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure itemprop=&#34;associatedMedia&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/IMG_3767.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;contentUrl&#34; data-size=&#34;1200x800&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/thumbs/thumbs_IMG_3767.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;1969 K5 blazer drum brakes&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption itemprop=&#34;caption description&#34;&gt;1969 K5 blazer drum brakes&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;author&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;contentLocation&#34;&gt;Camarillo, CA&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;div itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/Place&#34;&gt;
      &lt;span itemprop=&#34;name&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;address&#34; itemprop=&#34;address&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/PostalAddress&#34;&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;streetAddress&#34;&gt;19 N Aviador St. Unit C&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressLocality&#34;&gt;Camarillo&lt;/span&gt;,
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressRegion&#34;&gt;CA&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;postalCode&#34;&gt;93010&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div itemprop=&#34;geo&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/GeoCoordinates&#34;&gt;
        Latitude: 34.2171139
        Longitude: -119.0966697
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;latitude&#34; content=&#34;34.2171139&#34; /&gt;
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;longitude&#34; content=&#34;-119.0966697&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;
&amp;nbsp;

It did have a dana 44 axle but some things had been modified.  The brake lines had to all be rebuilt because extensions were put on a strange fashion rather than simply getting extended lines.  As an aside I don&#39;t like steel braided.  They are known to fail and redirect hydro physics that was not originally intended for that area.  Lines were built locally by Oxnard hose.

The knuckles were removed and we replaced all the components.  Yes we stripped, blasted and sanded this after the ball joints were added.  The tech got ahead of us by a little.  It made it hard to clean up of course but we managed to work around it. We didn&#39;t just paint over the grime.

&lt;figure itemprop=&#34;associatedMedia&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/IMG_0128.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;contentUrl&#34; data-size=&#34;1200x800&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/thumbs/thumbs_IMG_0128.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;1969 K5 blazer drum brakes&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption itemprop=&#34;caption description&#34;&gt;1969 K5 blazer drum brakes&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;author&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;contentLocation&#34;&gt;Camarillo, CA&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;div itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/Place&#34;&gt;
      &lt;span itemprop=&#34;name&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;address&#34; itemprop=&#34;address&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/PostalAddress&#34;&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;streetAddress&#34;&gt;19 N Aviador St. Unit C&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressLocality&#34;&gt;Camarillo&lt;/span&gt;,
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressRegion&#34;&gt;CA&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;postalCode&#34;&gt;93010&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div itemprop=&#34;geo&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/GeoCoordinates&#34;&gt;
        Latitude: 34.2171139
        Longitude: -119.0966697
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;latitude&#34; content=&#34;34.2171139&#34; /&gt;
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;longitude&#34; content=&#34;-119.0966697&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure itemprop=&#34;associatedMedia&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/IMG_0122.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;contentUrl&#34; data-size=&#34;1200x800&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/thumbs/thumbs_IMG_0122.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;1969 K5 blazer drum brakes&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption itemprop=&#34;caption description&#34;&gt;1969 K5 blazer drum brakes&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;author&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;contentLocation&#34;&gt;Camarillo, CA&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;div itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/Place&#34;&gt;
      &lt;span itemprop=&#34;name&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;address&#34; itemprop=&#34;address&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/PostalAddress&#34;&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;streetAddress&#34;&gt;19 N Aviador St. Unit C&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressLocality&#34;&gt;Camarillo&lt;/span&gt;,
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressRegion&#34;&gt;CA&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;postalCode&#34;&gt;93010&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div itemprop=&#34;geo&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/GeoCoordinates&#34;&gt;
        Latitude: 34.2171139
        Longitude: -119.0966697
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;latitude&#34; content=&#34;34.2171139&#34; /&gt;
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;longitude&#34; content=&#34;-119.0966697&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure itemprop=&#34;associatedMedia&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/IMG_0131.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;contentUrl&#34; data-size=&#34;1200x800&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/thumbs/thumbs_IMG_0131.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;repainted k5 d44 knuckle&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption itemprop=&#34;caption description&#34;&gt;repainted k5 d44 knuckle&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;author&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;contentLocation&#34;&gt;Camarillo, CA&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;div itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/Place&#34;&gt;
      &lt;span itemprop=&#34;name&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;address&#34; itemprop=&#34;address&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/PostalAddress&#34;&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;streetAddress&#34;&gt;19 N Aviador St. Unit C&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressLocality&#34;&gt;Camarillo&lt;/span&gt;,
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressRegion&#34;&gt;CA&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;postalCode&#34;&gt;93010&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div itemprop=&#34;geo&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/GeoCoordinates&#34;&gt;
        Latitude: 34.2171139
        Longitude: -119.0966697
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;latitude&#34; content=&#34;34.2171139&#34; /&gt;
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;longitude&#34; content=&#34;-119.0966697&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure itemprop=&#34;associatedMedia&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/ImageObject&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/IMG_0104.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;contentUrl&#34; data-size=&#34;1200x800&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/generalleeanne/thumbs/thumbs_IMG_0104.jpg&#34; itemprop=&#34;thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;k5 1969 dana 44&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption itemprop=&#34;caption description&#34;&gt;k5 1969 dana 44&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;author&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span itemprop=&#34;contentLocation&#34;&gt;Camarillo, CA&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;div itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/Place&#34;&gt;
      &lt;span itemprop=&#34;name&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;address&#34; itemprop=&#34;address&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/PostalAddress&#34;&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;streetAddress&#34;&gt;19 N Aviador St. Unit C&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressLocality&#34;&gt;Camarillo&lt;/span&gt;,
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;addressRegion&#34;&gt;CA&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;span itemprop=&#34;postalCode&#34;&gt;93010&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div itemprop=&#34;geo&#34; itemscope itemtype=&#34;http://schema.org/GeoCoordinates&#34;&gt;
        Latitude: 34.2171139
        Longitude: -119.0966697
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;latitude&#34; content=&#34;34.2171139&#34; /&gt;
        &lt;meta itemprop=&#34;longitude&#34; content=&#34;-119.0966697&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We replaced the driver&amp;rsquo;s side rotor and rebuilt the various internals replacing seals on everything except the inside of the pumpkin.  The oil all looked good so we didn&amp;rsquo;t want to explode it for this project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be some more pictures coming, but we painted the axle shafts and everything and it is starting to look really clean. Next is off to &lt;a title=&#34;Mercenary Offroad&#34; href=&#34;http://mercenaryoffroad.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mercenary Offroad&lt;/a&gt; for bumper and fabrication work.  We are excited to see. This will be #001 first generation chevy bumper. More to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>General Lee-Anne 001</title>
          <link>http://scotttactical.com/general-lee-anne-001/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Tactical</author>
          <guid>http://scotttactical.com/general-lee-anne-001/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Here we go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1969 hugger orange rust bucket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This thing barely stops.  It stops when it wants to.  So it&amp;rsquo;s kinda like a woman.  Every bushing and joint is shot.  Probably never replaced a thing on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the adventure begins.  I&amp;rsquo;m using this truck as the first in my branded line of modified restorations.  Our focus for these trucks is somewhere in between utility and aesthetics.  Not just a mall crawler but something of a useful truck that also gets attention.  I will be formulating various levels of offerings so that we can set our branded restorations.  We can go all the way or just get it back to top mechanical levels and clean of rust.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://img.scotttactical.com/images/legacy/2014/08/IMG_0100.jpg&#34; /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Hugger Orange 1969 K5 Blazer&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
        </item>
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
