<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Politics on Scott Tactical</title>
    <link>https://scotttactical.com/tags/politics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Politics on Scott Tactical</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2014–2019, Scott Tactical; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 18:51:01 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://scotttactical.com/tags/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Vehemenism</title>
      <link>https://scotttactical.com/post/vehemenism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 18:51:01 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scotttactical.com/post/vehemenism/</guid>
      <description>Preface to Vehemenism Opening letter to future ultra-violent men.
We stand at a transition. Either at the bottom of a cliff we may ascend, or at the precipice of one we will be pushed from. This &amp;ldquo;we&amp;rdquo; is addressed to men alone. Only we are the ones presented with this unique problem. It is a problem of perspective and one that contains many recursive questions. The answer to these questions will ultimately decide whether or not the observer was indeed a man.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why The Covered California Website Sucks</title>
      <link>https://scotttactical.com/post/why-the-covered-california-website-sucks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 08:52:58 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scotttactical.com/post/why-the-covered-california-website-sucks/</guid>
      <description>Why It Needs Help - My Letter This is an open letter to the Covered California website designer, administrators, bureaucrats and contractors.
Website Design and Usability I have several things listed below. Things I find to be of poor design or just plain broken.
You Don&amp;rsquo;t Got Mail!  &amp;ldquo;Secure Mailbox (2)&amp;rdquo; even though nothing was in my mail box.
 It randomly logged me out.
  GO&amp;rsquo;ON CLICK ME IF YA CAN  I am low on time for open enrollment and it gave me a &amp;ldquo;Pay Now&amp;rdquo; button in order to do it faster, but the button was broken.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internet 3rd Wave and Rise of the Technology Fascist</title>
      <link>https://scotttactical.com/post/internet-3rd-wave-and-rise-of-the-technology-fascist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2016 13:13:26 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scotttactical.com/post/internet-3rd-wave-and-rise-of-the-technology-fascist/</guid>
      <description>The Waves of Technology Professional I like to consider 2001 the tail edge of the Internet bubble. It was a brutal time to be in a computer science field. There weren&amp;rsquo;t many jobs. The jobs that were being squatted on were jealously guarded. I needed the one thing that nobody would provide. Experience. So instead I grinded projects and studied unceasingly.
In 2001 I had to take a job as an &amp;ldquo;integration specialist&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Conservatism Fails</title>
      <link>https://scotttactical.com/why-conservatism-fails/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2015 17:18:43 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scotttactical.com/why-conservatism-fails/</guid>
      <description>This essay is not an attack on the people who claim membership to a philosophical outlook, but an exposition on the inherent difficulties which exist in maintaining traditional systems.
Let us begin with the needful: term definition.
Term Definition  Conservatism as a political and social philosophy promotes retaining traditional social institutions in the context of the culture and civilization.
 This is the definition found at Wikipedia and I find it to be a pretty good summation of the idea.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>