<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Django on Scott Tactical</title>
    <link>https://scotttactical.com/tags/django/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Django on Scott Tactical</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2014–2019, Scott Tactical; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2017 16:00:07 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://scotttactical.com/tags/django/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Django Saleor eCommerce Review</title>
      <link>https://scotttactical.com/post/django-saleor-ecommerce-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2017 16:00:07 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scotttactical.com/post/django-saleor-ecommerce-review/</guid>
      <description>Django And eCommerce TL;DR I setup Oscar as a demo ecommerce project in the previous post.
Preface Backstory I just finished a post about setting up eCommerce with Python Django and wasn&amp;rsquo;t totally pleased with the process. Also I don&amp;rsquo;t think it is fair to only demo a single application. I decided to give Saleor my second slot after talking with several people online and looking through its source. The parent company has a number of nice products which was confidence building.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Django eCommerce in 30&#43; Minutes</title>
      <link>https://scotttactical.com/post/django-ecommerce-in-30-minutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2017 16:00:07 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scotttactical.com/post/django-ecommerce-in-30-minutes/</guid>
      <description>Django And eCommerce TL;DR I like Python and want to use it for eCommerce, so I went through the well known products and settled on Oscar as my demo. It took a while to set up, but was pretty full featured. Python and Django still have to compete with short busses like wordpress and dump trucks like Magento, but I think these tools are ready for me to start pushing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Django Search: Multiple Fields and Full Text</title>
      <link>https://scotttactical.com/django-search-multiple-fields/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2016 22:34:50 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scotttactical.com/django-search-multiple-fields/</guid>
      <description>Text Search - Django Model Fields Django has a pretty flexible ORM, but sometimes clients need a free-form text search to get down to the content that you are looking for. It is beyond the capability of most engineers to build a comprehensive search tool and shoehorn it into an existing application. There are people working on these problems for years.
This does remind me of a senior boss that asked me to add a fuzzy search field to an application and that it was &amp;ldquo;super simple&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dump Django Databases and Create Fixtures for Testing</title>
      <link>https://scotttactical.com/post/dump-django-databases-and-create-fixtures-for-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 23:20:36 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scotttactical.com/post/dump-django-databases-and-create-fixtures-for-testing/</guid>
      <description>Fixtures are a Messy Mess It is quite a pain to maintain fixtures it seems. I am not sure why yet. Maybe there hasn&amp;rsquo;t been quite enough time on this piece of the product for it to mature.
Django dumpdata I tried several different variations to dump the data. I&amp;rsquo;ll include a few of them here since they might actually work for someone else.
python manage.py dumpdata &amp;gt; fixture.json</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>