<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>restoration on Scott Tactical</title>
    <link>https://scotttactical.com/tags/restoration/</link>
    <description>Recent content in restoration on Scott Tactical</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2014–2019, Scott Tactical; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://scotttactical.com/tags/restoration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>General Lee-Anne 001</title>
      <link>https://scotttactical.com/dana-60-front-axle-build/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scotttactical.com/dana-60-front-axle-build/</guid>
      <description>Building a Dana Sixty Part of this process was setting up the new axles. I wanted to go 1-ton all the way around. I think everyone knows that finding a good condition d60 for a reasonable price is not possible.
So I bought one from a local guy that had been sitting on a truck in a paintball field. It looked like it was pulled from Davey Jones Locker Room.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GLA - 69 K5 &#43; 4L80-E</title>
      <link>https://scotttactical.com/gla-69-k5-4l80-e/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scotttactical.com/gla-69-k5-4l80-e/</guid>
      <description>Cleaned up the trans a little bit. Tiny bit of cosmetics. Taped up. Then hit it with some nice paint. I prefer for these to have paint. Keeps cleaning it easier. Also I think the buyer will appreciate it.
Before:
After:
 A fun fact, this and a few of the Chevy transmissions have a prestigious history.
 Chevy C/K Trucks Suburban (this one we have) Hummer H1/H2 Rolls Royce Bentley Jaguar  Source</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GLA - 4L80e -1969 k5 blazer</title>
      <link>https://scotttactical.com/gla-4l80e-1969-k5-blazer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scotttactical.com/gla-4l80e-1969-k5-blazer/</guid>
      <description>Just got the trans in from Brad at Transaction Transmission.
I have used him for a while now and he puts in the effort. Components were upgraded and everything set new. This should be strong for the newowner. It was cleaned and painted at the shop but I am going to clean it up a little more and put on a coat of the &amp;ldquo;Mercenary Offroad&amp;rdquo; package graphite gray.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GLA 69 K5 - bumper start</title>
      <link>https://scotttactical.com/gla-69-k5-bumper-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scotttactical.com/gla-69-k5-bumper-start/</guid>
      <description>Well, we got the truck running enough that I can drive it around. It stops. We even locked it up and watched the black lines form up behind the tires. Not bad for 35&amp;rsquo;s.
It was moved over to Camarillo to the shop known as Mercenary Offroad where a custom bumper will be fabricated for it. The designator for this bumper is also 001 as it will be the first one designed for this series truck.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GLA 69 K5 Brakes</title>
      <link>https://scotttactical.com/gla-69-k5-brakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scotttactical.com/gla-69-k5-brakes/</guid>
      <description>So the PO was rough on the vehicle. Probably multiple PO&amp;rsquo;s.
Included are some pictures to show the detail we went to in repairing and rebuilding the brake systems.
The brake system had been WORKED. They were pretty much shot. When we got it the pedal hit the floor. It didn&amp;rsquo;t want to stop so the ride to the shop was a bit of a terror show for that 2 miles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>General Lee-Anne 001</title>
      <link>https://scotttactical.com/general-lee-anne-001/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scotttactical.com/general-lee-anne-001/</guid>
      <description>Here we go.
1969 hugger orange rust bucket.
This thing barely stops. It stops when it wants to. So it&amp;rsquo;s kinda like a woman. Every bushing and joint is shot. Probably never replaced a thing on it.
And the adventure begins. I&amp;rsquo;m using this truck as the first in my branded line of modified restorations. Our focus for these trucks is somewhere in between utility and aesthetics. Not just a mall crawler but something of a useful truck that also gets attention.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
